<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tyler Kinley on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/tyler-kinley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tyler Kinley on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/tyler-kinley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Spirit Animal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</guid>
      <description>I like to imagine a team&amp;rsquo;s culture as its spirit animal.
Furious would be a rabid dog: Fierce, foaming at the mouth, and angry.
Revolver would be a cobra: Patient, calculating, and deadly.
Chain is like a big gorilla: Powerful, intimidating, and brutish.
Sockeye is like a monkey: Playful, goofy, throwing its own feces, yet strong.
Okay, Tyler. What in the hell are you talking about.
Well, think about it this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Planning Musts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</guid>
      <description>1. Write it down.
This helps you remember your plan, creates a document that you can return to, and can be emailed to the team beforehand if you feel it would help.
2. Specify time allotments for each segment of practice.
This creates a schedule, and is easier on you (you know when to start/stop a drill) and your team (they know there&amp;rsquo;s a plan to stick to).
3. Don&amp;rsquo;t perform a drill for more than 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Strong Sideline Voice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</guid>
      <description>Most offenders will tell you that yelling instructions to them on the sideline when they&amp;rsquo;re on offense is annoying, if not worse. When you&amp;rsquo;re on offense, sideline chatter is best saved for positive encouragement and celebrating a goal scored.
However, on D, the sideline is an incredibly powerful tool, able to create momentum on your side, stop momentum for the other team, and create blocks that otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Now, a good sideline voice has a few characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
