<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chain: Building A Core</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</guid>
      <description>Good club teams often have a core of stars who have played with each other for a while. Looking at Chain Lightning&amp;rsquo;s roster last year, I was struck by how little turnover the team experienced. With a few notable exceptions, last year&amp;rsquo;s Chain team was the same team that lost in the semifinals in 2008, bolstered by the addition of five rookies, all of whom Chain used in key defensive roles (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain: The New DoG</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</guid>
      <description>During DoG&amp;rsquo;s heyday 15 years ago, our main offensive strength was that we would take what they&amp;rsquo;d give us. Our offense was efficient, not just in terms of scoring percentage, but in using energy wisely. Players created space by knowing when to get out of the way or to simply stay put and remain out of the way. We liked the long game, but were equally comfortable in taking a series of passes up the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain&#39;s Big Assist From The Weather</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</guid>
      <description>After twelve straight years as a nationals participant in the Open division (1997-2008), in 2009 as a masters player was a different experience. First, few people, and really nobody outside the division itself, care much about the Masters division. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say it isn&amp;rsquo;t competitive, or even that there isn&amp;rsquo;t good Ultimate being played there, it&amp;rsquo;s just that when you have the Open nationals to watch, why would you watch Masters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury By The Numbers: Conversion &amp; Psyche</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</guid>
      <description>Despite Backhoe outscoring Brute Squad 9-7 in the second half after starting out the game 0-6, 2-8 at half, Brute never allowed the game to get ugly [ugly meaning a turnover-fest]. Of the 16 goals (37 possessions) scored between the teams in the second half, 12 were scored on one possession: Backhoe was 8 for 9, Brute was 4 for 7; two of the remaining four were 2nd possession goals. Regardless of our unusual second half efficiency (statistically we were strong on O2D and had a high percentage of Offense 2nd possession [O2] goals), we still walked into our match-up with Fury like a wounded animal looking to make too many corrections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury Knows How To Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</guid>
      <description>Fury, more than any other Women&amp;rsquo;s team in the nation (perhaps ever, though there will be those who argue for Godiva or Maineiacs), knows what to do in Sarasota.
Each player seems to have a very good grasp of her specific role from the top of the roster to the bottom. Everyone plays that role perfectly when push comes to shove. They don&amp;rsquo;t mess around against teams they know they will beat, and they bring it hard to teams that might have entertained thoughts of having a chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Chain Won 2009 Nationals - Offensively</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/how-chain-won-2009-nationals-offensively/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/how-chain-won-2009-nationals-offensively/</guid>
      <description>I was in a unique position at the championships last season: being employed by the UPA to follow the action and write daily recaps on the website&amp;rsquo;s results page for the Open Division. In this capacity I witnessed part of each game Chain was involved in, and as they progressed through the tournament I got to watch how they were able to attack so effectively against the other top teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Teens Again</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</guid>
      <description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t there, but as I was watching the live feed of Fury dismantling Brute Squad I was struck by a sense of déjà vu; I felt like I was watching Godiva. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about Fury and Godiva&amp;rsquo;s dominance, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about a single little cut that is the backbone of both team&amp;rsquo;s offenses. It&amp;rsquo;s a cut I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen other teams (men&amp;rsquo;s or women&amp;rsquo;s) use. I remember watching Teens (Christine Dunlap) wreck people with this cut, getting wide open again and again and again, so it was a little weird to watch Fury doing the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
