<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Thoughts &amp; Techniques</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/cutting-thoughts-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/cutting-thoughts-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Becoming a great cutter, like any ultimate skill, requires more than simply athleticism (though work at the track won&amp;rsquo;t hurt). It requires plenty of skill, thought, and practice. I think about cutting broken down into two components: the technique of the cut itself and cutting within an offensive system.
Cutting technique: As you start to work on your cutting technique, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to think about your strengths and role as a cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D-Line Handlers</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/d-line-handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/d-line-handlers/</guid>
      <description>I should start by saying that I am an incredibly blessed ultimate player. For the past few years, I have had the coolest job in ultimate. &amp;ldquo;Go cover whoever you want, and when we get the disc, get it moving, then put it up. Your receivers will be Beau, Jolian, Mangan and Martin.&amp;rdquo; Uhhh, yes please? (I imagine Jeremy Cram felt the same way when he was choosing between Nord, Chase, Andrew Fleming and Mark Stone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Cutting</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/deep-cutting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/deep-cutting/</guid>
      <description>Three of the handiest attributes a deep receiver can have are speed, jumping ability, and height. Sadly, even by lifting, doing plyometrics, and running sprints, an athlete and only increase her or his speed and explosiveness to a certain extent. As far as I have seen, height cannot be taught or learned. Fortunately, there are several other factors that go into being an effective deep threat, all of which are much more learnable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defense From The Handler Spot</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</guid>
      <description>A great defensive handler first and foremost plays defense. The defensive unit will only get a handful of opportunities to try to score; most of their time spent on the field will be defending. To be valuable to their team, a defensive handler will need to produce more than they give up, and the offense has a big advantage to start with. Effective defending from a variety of positions is well covered in other issues of The Huddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Handlers I Admire</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defensive-handlers-i-admire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defensive-handlers-i-admire/</guid>
      <description>Every team has its own style of play and I think it is hard to pick out characteristics that make a great defensive handler—or any other position—without considering it in the context of a specific team. That said, I have noticed that good defensive lines are able to use the chaos of a turn to their advantage. Some teams try to pick up the disc right away and move it quickly to make it difficult for the other team to set up a defense while others take their time to set up an organized offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling: Doing The Little Things</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-doing-the-little-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-doing-the-little-things/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to being a great handler than meets the eye. Being one of the better throwers on your team is important. But there have been plenty of teams on which the best thrower is not a handler, especially when it comes to hucking. This isn&amp;rsquo;t say that being a great thrower doesn&amp;rsquo;t help a handler be great. Rather, there are a lot of factors and skills that make some handlers particularly effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling: Vision</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-vision/</guid>
      <description>Having great throws is one thing, but what makes a great handler is how those throws are used. A lot of characteristics that apply can be said about any great player, like the ability to consistently get open, especially late in the stall, and in a dangerous place to make the next throw. The great ones blend taking opportunities and making opportunities. With handlers, I think what separates the great ones, beyond just having great throws, is vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schwa&#39;s D-Handler</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</guid>
      <description>Great defensive handlers are typically people who are aggressive, able to see the field really well, and have a solid understanding of when it is appropriate to play transition offense. In my opinion, one of the most important parts of being a defensive handler is leading your team when you guys do get the D. This may be calling a play, running to the disc to transition, creating space for a teammate, or cutting to get the disc off the transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well-Rounded Deep Threats</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</guid>
      <description>In my experience, the toughest match-ups on receivers are against those players that are as big a threat going deep as they are coming under. Playing defense against a player like this, it is not obvious how you should play them. If you force them away, they&amp;rsquo;ll burn you deep and/or sky you for the score, but if you force them in, they&amp;rsquo;ll have a chance to use their throws to put the disc into the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Else Makes A Good Handler?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/what-else-makes-a-good-handler-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/what-else-makes-a-good-handler-/</guid>
      <description>Many players in Ultimate have good throws, but that does not necessarily mean that they are great handlers. The key to becoming a great handler is combining the mechanics of good throws and a versatile throwing repertoire with three big picture attributes: awareness, communication, and mind set/attitude.
The first characteristic of a great handler is awareness, or vision. The ability to evaluate the field at a moment&amp;rsquo;s notice is crucial for calling plays, or dictating what you want as a thrower.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
