<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[kuhl-cher]</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/-kuhl-cher-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/-kuhl-cher-/</guid>
      <description>Culture [kuhl-cher] -noun: the attitudes and behavior that are characteristic of a particular social group or organization.
Successful teams, sometimes by accident, but more often by design, share amongst their members a common set of values, attitudes and goals. These characteristics define the identity of a given team, and ultimately create the culture of that team.
Everything about the actions of the team is a function of these characteristics, right down to the definition of success itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Spirit Animal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</guid>
      <description>I like to imagine a team&amp;rsquo;s culture as its spirit animal.
Furious would be a rabid dog: Fierce, foaming at the mouth, and angry.
Revolver would be a cobra: Patient, calculating, and deadly.
Chain is like a big gorilla: Powerful, intimidating, and brutish.
Sockeye is like a monkey: Playful, goofy, throwing its own feces, yet strong.
Okay, Tyler. What in the hell are you talking about.
Well, think about it this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Will Change Every Season</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to realize about your team’s culture is that it will change every season.
Yes, I was concerned when I first joined Riot that I might never fit into the intense, upfront grind of the kickass East Coast transplant women, but the team has changed a great deal in the past 7 years. Riot has become a weird, unique, open-nearly-to-a-fault bunch of weenies (young and old) who’d rather drink Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Team Culture Moments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/key-team-culture-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/key-team-culture-moments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The very essence of leadership is that you have to have vision. It’s got to be a vision you articulate clearly and forcefully on every occasion. You can’t blow an uncertain trumpet.&amp;rdquo; — Father Theodore Hesburgh
If team culture is simply a set commonly held attitudes and beliefs about a team, then the reason for wanting to encourage helpful culture is straightforward: it helps performance.
As evidence, here’s an example of a &amp;ldquo;team culture&amp;rdquo; situation that you may have seen or been a party to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuture What You Like, Overcome What You Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</guid>
      <description>Team culture can often be overlooked as an important contributor to your team’s success, both in the short and long term. The culture of your team determines what types of players will be attracted to the team, will enjoy playing on your team, and will stick around season after season. There is no one &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; team culture, and it can be defined as much from the actions of a single individual (founder, strong personality, etc) as shaped over time by the collective actions and personalities of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustaining Team Culture</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</guid>
      <description>A former captain and then-coach of mine offered only this advice when I described to him the multitude of ideas and plans we rising seniors at Dartmouth had for team leadership and culture in the coming season: It’s always harder than you think.
This message is worth keeping in mind for anyone seeking to engineer or change something as amorphous yet integral as one’s team culture - it’s all too easy to get caught up in the energy and excitement of the season and neglect the grand ideas and notions you have for making this season the season for you and your teammates, to say nothing of the difficulty of managing people in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Identity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/team-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/team-identity/</guid>
      <description>Why have some teams (in both college and club) been around for years while others fade in and out of existence, emerging with new names and members every year? What seems to be true is that teams with strong identities have more fun, are more dedicated, stick around longer and play better. The teams that don’t will fight, argue and fade away. What do you think about as a leader and team member of a team struggling to exist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Them</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the WUFF Warriors defeated FBI from Portland, Oregon 11-6 at Chicago Tune Up. That win was probably the biggest win for a Wilmington club team since the Slickers defeated NY Graffiti at Worlds in 1993 [one could argue that the victory over Philly in the regional final in ’95 was larger, but I’ll take ‘93]. Later that weekend the Warriors defeated Ring of Fire 11-10; the first win over Ring for a Wilmington team since 1996 [though in ’96 they called themselves En Fuego I believe].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Together</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/work-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/work-together/</guid>
      <description>Ultimate is a sport of independent minded players—players who like to self- govern—and in ultimate a wide range of personal investment and work ethic on a given team is common. This creates a difficult situation: the headstrong leader yelling about commitment as the fun loving party-captain rolls his eyes. Forming a single team identity can be daunting. The most important step is to get everyone together doing something other than playing ultimate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
