<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Little Perspective</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/a-little-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/a-little-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Field vision is the ability to understand the dynamics of the opposition&amp;rsquo;s offense or defense despite being embroiled in a battle against it. Every team has players who see plays happen/develop (be it from on the pitch or the sideline), and compile the information to start the next point with the knowledge they just took on board (and, importantly, can dispense it to their teammates). It is these adaptive players that win tight matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Your Eyes To Open Them</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/closing-your-eyes-to-open-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/closing-your-eyes-to-open-them/</guid>
      <description>Good field vision can be described as a contrast between being somebody with good field sense and somebody who has &amp;ldquo;visionary throws.&amp;rdquo; If you have ever been called &amp;ldquo;visionary&amp;rdquo; I bet that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a compliment.
Most of the time people who are described as having good field vision are players who have a general sense of what is going on with all 14 players on the field. This is broken down into four things: a good understanding of passing lanes, a strong mastery of various throwing skills, a knowledge of what the offensive system is trying to attack and what the defense is currently doing to stop that attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn To Think So You Don&#39;t Have To Think</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</guid>
      <description>How do we make decisions? In many real-life examples we create a list of choices and features, maybe take some data, rate how each option stacks up in each feature, and coolly select the optimum choice. In ultimate you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to go through this whole process. You have to rely on your trained inner self to figure out what to do based on internalized guidelines.
Since I like lists of rules here are some for making sense of what is happening on the field and figuring out what to do about it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Recognition</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Psychologist John Dewey debunked a commonly held belief called the stimulus- response reflex arc: you see something, you decide what to do, you respond. Instead, Dewey proposed, you only see what you have a mental framework for; this framework contains your response within it. In other words, your response exists before you see the stimulus. Many players have the experience of knowing they&amp;rsquo;ve thrown the goal before the disc leaves their hands, or &amp;ldquo;seeing&amp;rdquo; the lay out D before it happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play A Different Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</guid>
      <description>I would argue that field vision, like speed or height, is pretty hard to teach and learn. The best athletes don&amp;rsquo;t see what&amp;rsquo;s happening so much as take a picture of the field and respond. A few brains can do that kind of thing, but most can&amp;rsquo;t. Bill Rodriguez would counsel deeps in a zone to move up if they saw seven opposing players in front of them. Super, if, like Bill, you can see them all at once and count them at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding The Information</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</guid>
      <description>Understanding positioning and distribution of players on the field is an important skill, but also somewhat of an innate ability. How this skill manifests itself is sometimes subtle and other times overt. It can show up in the guy who always seems to be making the good cut to keep the offensive flow going or in the physically ungifted player who consistently finds themselves alone in the endzone. It can be the thrower who is able to find targets on the goal line or the defender who gets a lot of poach blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yeah Iverson, We&#39;ve Talkin&#39; About Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have a rather painful childhood memory from back in middle school. I was playing basketball and went to set a low screen for another player. In a moment of miscommunication both my defender and the player who I set a pick on rushed to guard my teammate. I was left open for just a few seconds, but before I realized it, the basketball hit me in the face. The point guard recognized that I was about to be open and passed the ball early.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
