<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Tennis Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</guid>
      <description>I usually try to write on the presented topic from a objective and scientific viewpoint, however, due to the nature of this topic, this will be rather subjective and opinionated. Also, much of this is a comparison to tennis since that is where I have participated in the highest levels of competition prior to frisbee.
Growing up learning the sport of Ultimate in Australia, my viewpoint of SOTG comes from a more global perspective of competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character When It Matters Most</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</guid>
      <description>Spirit of the Game is easy when the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;hellip;but that is certainly not the case with Northwest Regionals. Every game is a battle and every game is intense. In my opinion, it is when the UPA Series starts that Spirit matters most.
The best players in the game can play at an incredibly high level without compromising their personal integrity or the reputation of their team. I think that sometimes Spirit of the Game is mistaken for not contesting calls or not being willing to make a call, but really it is honoring your opponents and yourself by playing 100% and making calls if true violations or fouls occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codifying Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</guid>
      <description>This topic is not useless, but I find that my thoughts on it are fairly disconnected.
A phrase that reminds us to respect each other and the game makes sense even if it is not as effective as some would like preventing players from cheating or acting like jerks. We are really just codifying the idea that Ultimate players should practice good sportsmanship, That has value, I hope.
A lot of people discover Ultimate after some bad experience with another sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even If No One Is Watching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</guid>
      <description>Really, honestly, how can anyone possibly not believe that this is a worthy philosophy to embrace? The only thing that kills me is the the name: &amp;ldquo;Spirit of the Game.&amp;rdquo; The word spirit is not synomynous with common words and expressions I associate with sports: Grit - Battle - Fair - Integrity - Determination - Motivation - Guts - Glory - Respect. &amp;ldquo;Spirit&amp;rdquo; is a word that I would associate with yoga class, folklore, or a Bible Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Turn As That Guy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/my-turn-as-that-guy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/my-turn-as-that-guy/</guid>
      <description>I know a lot of your other articles are going to be from people that always do the right thing, but not everyone is them. I thank you for letting me write from my perspective without, I think, giving people the wrong impression about my team. But I think it is important that you get all sides here.
I cheated in a game-to-go. When I made the call I thought it was correct but I knew right then about ten seconds later that it was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Rules</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</guid>
      <description>No one gets four strikes in baseball simply because they think its wrong that the rules allow only three. You don&amp;rsquo;t pick and choose which rules to follow. You play by the rules of the game. Whether or not you agree with it, the Spirit of the Game concept is a fixture in the official rules of Ultimate so we, as players, have an obligation to adhere to it. But in the middle of a game, especially one with much at stake, what does it mean to adhere to a concept that is so vaguely defined?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platoon</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</guid>
      <description>ECC and Chesapeake are behind us, as is Sectionals. We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past 8 weeks running 120s. We started Cones after Sectionals. In what will have been a mere stepping stone of a game for us, the trust building and empathy through conditioning mentioned above will raise its beautiful head at Regionals, as will the burden of self-officiating.
2nd round and it&amp;rsquo;s 5 all and on serve. hile there are no certainties, except that one that says we&amp;rsquo;ll receive for the 2nd half, they will only score 3 more points to our 10; but at 5 all, nobody but nobody knows this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirit Of The Games</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/spirit-of-the-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/spirit-of-the-games/</guid>
      <description>I am not going to write about history. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write of how &amp;ldquo;zealots&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;RSDers&amp;rdquo; alike bake their theory cake and top it with a little Spirit icing so everybody thinks it will taste sweet. If I am going to talk about it, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be about me and what I think, so here goes:
Spirit is respect. Respect for your opponent, respect for the situation, and respect for right to play this game at any level you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blender</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</guid>
      <description>What if the Minnesota Timerwolves had to play Macalaster College and a YWCA pick-up team on their road to an NBA Championship? What if the Commissioner of MLB also governed little league and summer softball league? Those levels of play differ so much they are hardly the same sport. Yet in the Club Series of Ultimate, players from all levels comingle on the same field. The best players in the world compete against absolute novices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Issues With Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</guid>
      <description>I love the Huddle. I think the work they do is a great contribution to Ultimate, I love reading the other contributors&amp;rsquo; work and I am honored that they would include me as an author. That said, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe they are making such a colossal mistake in having ONE Spirit of the Game issue.
Spirit of the Game is essential to Ultimate. Every time we step on the field to play, we are participating in what makes Ultimate unique and special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Principal Components</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</guid>
      <description>To me, Spirit of the Game has two principal components: respect (don&amp;rsquo;t be an ass) and integrity (don&amp;rsquo;t be a cheater). I think you could go through reams of paper defining how those two principles should and do play out, which is not my intent here.
My point is that playing with Spirit is much harder than I think we give it credit for. What we are asking of people is to fight against their ego, their desire for appreciation and status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Goes Through Your Head</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</guid>
      <description>Last year at Northeast Regionals my team (PoNY) was playing Bodhi to go to Nationals. Game tied at 12s, time cap approaching, PoNY is on defense. Bodhi goes on a fast break with a quick succession of give-go throws—&amp;ldquo;Pick!&amp;rdquo; someone yells—and the last throw, a huck, falls incomplete. The two teams start to argue. Was the pick two throws ago, or one? Does the disc go back to Bodhi, or is it a turnover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Do</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll let better writers and players describe why Spirit is, or is not, worth your time. I know my answer, and you have to find your own.
If you come away having decided that it is worth your your effort, here are a couple of things that your team can do to improve your own Spirit on the field in meaningful games. At the very least, they are things that my teams have done in the past that have helped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
