<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Couple Of Thoughts On Zone D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</guid>
      <description>A couple of quick thoughts.
Sidelines are great for communication, but the people that need to be able to talk to each other are all on the field already. In a standard three-person cup, the communication streams are simple:
Deep talks to wings and short-deep Short-deep talks to points and middle Middle talks to points Wings talk to their side&amp;rsquo;s point With these streams, each player can adjust the positioning of the players they are covering for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tweak To The 1-3-3</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</guid>
      <description>With zone defenses, I tend to lean away from the old standards, reasoning that if most defenders know them, most offenses know how to play against them. Almost everyone has run a standard three-person cup, and every offense has seen one. In order to get a good offense out of its rhythm enough to generate turnovers, you need to either run a well-known zone better than other teams do, or you need to do something different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Zone Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</guid>
      <description>From your experience, what zone configuration do you feel most confident in?
In general I prefer a three man cup mainly because it can be used to disguise other types of defensive schemes teams may use, such as a zone to man. The specific setup I prefer for the three man cup is with the short deep playing very close to the cup, if not actually part of the cup, working as a unit to trap the disc on the sideline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments To The 2-3-2</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a favorite zone depends on a few factors, including the personnel on my team, the personnel on the other team, the direction and strength of the wind, and the things the other team are doing that are working. Every team should have two different zone looks in their arsenal, ideally with a well practiced ability to transition out of the zone into a person defense. Choosing a zone is another question though, so I&amp;rsquo;ll go with the classic—the 2-3-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redistribute Their Resources</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</guid>
      <description>I believe that it is impossible to design a zone (or any defense for that matter) that takes away everything. If I knew that zone I would never lose a game. I think the important thing about a zone is to make sure that everyone is clear of what the zone&amp;rsquo;s objectives are, and when they are forced to make a decision on the field, they do it within the context of that zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>For most of my teams (coaching and playing) we have been most comfortable in a 4-person cup recently. The goal with this zone is to prevent throws through the cup or around it with yardage gainers—we want to force the throws backward and we want to force a lot of them. I was taught to see this as a math problem—even the simplest throw will only be completed 99% of the time (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wham!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</guid>
      <description>2001 in Sarasota was crazy. Hurricane Michelle was causing major havoc for most of the Mixed division&amp;rsquo;s offenses. The wind started mild on Thursday and picked up through the week. One of my teammates on Trigger Hippy, Scott &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; Runkel (who played for Boston back when they were Big Brother, and, as far as I know, was the original &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; of the three that I know), along with Mike &amp;ldquo;the Wizard&amp;rdquo; Faris, came up with a zone to man to zone to man, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trap Hard &amp; Smart</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</guid>
      <description>A trap cup zone is a common and effective configuration in Mixed Ultimate. It looks to create pressure and mismatches at the disc. The handlers, who touch the disc most in zone offense, are depended upon by the rest of the team to be consistent and unflappable when working a zone D. An aggressive trap cup can serve to fluster and frustrate the handlers, whether it&amp;rsquo;s because they themselves are having trouble moving the disc or because others are having trouble getting them the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should We Contain?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</guid>
      <description>Zone Basics
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of a good trapping zone, but in unpredictable winds even a very conservative and basic zone would produce turns. There are way too many specifics and permutations to cover in this forum, but below are three principles of a trapping zone.
Basically, a trapping zone consists of three things. First, how are you going to allow the disc to move to a sideline. This is a combination of making it hard to move the disc in the middle, and making a lateral throw an easy pass without giving up too many yards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone Observations From The NYNY Days</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</guid>
      <description>Pike ran an imposing 1-3-3 for a number of years, a set that may or may not have morphed into a 4-man cup at times. Mike Jaeger (formerly of Michigan, currently of Sockeye) was great at the one spot.
The Warrior squad I played for in 2001 ran a 1-3-3 as well and that look got us to Nationals. Rhett Russ also the right man for the one spot. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the 1-3-3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
