<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Dufort on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/matt-dufort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matt Dufort on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/matt-dufort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</guid>
      <description>Marking consists of two simple steps: knowing the threats, and denying the threats. While the specifics will depend on how your team decides to play defense, the ideas below will apply in nearly all situations.
Step 1: Know the threats.
The best way to adjust your mark is to anticipate what the offense wants to do. If you can read the offense, you can take away the throws that would help them the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</guid>
      <description>First things first—calling subs for a competitive team is a big job. It will take a lot away from anyone&amp;rsquo;s playing ability. There may be someone out there who can play at their best and call subs at the same time, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t met them. Because of this, I think it&amp;rsquo;s better to split sub-calling duties between two or three players, or expect that the person calling subs is not going to play very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>Catching the disc is all about practice. If a situation comes up in a game, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much easier if you&amp;rsquo;ve done it a hundred times in practice than if it&amp;rsquo;s totally foreign to you. What that means is that you need to practice catching in game situations, not just easy, uncovered, and standing still. Practice catching the disc out in front of you, practice catching with a defender on your back, off-hand catches, in the wind, hammers, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tweak To The 1-3-3</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</guid>
      <description>With zone defenses, I tend to lean away from the old standards, reasoning that if most defenders know them, most offenses know how to play against them. Almost everyone has run a standard three-person cup, and every offense has seen one. In order to get a good offense out of its rhythm enough to generate turnovers, you need to either run a well-known zone better than other teams do, or you need to do something different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box-And-One</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</guid>
      <description>A player like this, who clearly has multiple offensive weapons, presents a serious match up challenge. Individual defensive match ups are an odd thing, and it can be difficult to predict which defender would be most effective. Given the past experience of this player being most effective as a deep thrower, I would continue to push them away from the disc. I would try different defenders on them until finding a player who could be successful in keeping the player away from the disc, and in containing their deep game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
