<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kirk Savage on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/kirk-savage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kirk Savage on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/kirk-savage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Defending The Area Around The Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy marking—particularly in the zone of a 1-3-3. Marking is a very important part of the game that often goes unnoticed or is an afterthought in defensive play. Teams usually pay some lip service to marking strategy (forcing flick or middle or straight-up), but that tends to be about it. Unfortunately, common practice is that the marker will rest on the mark. They use the mark as a chance to get their breath and prepare for another defensive run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Spacing &amp; Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/field-spacing-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/field-spacing-offense/</guid>
      <description>Field spacing depends on the offense your team is running. This is dictated in part by the defensive strengths of the team you are playing and in part by your own team&amp;rsquo;s strengths.
In the mid-to-late 1990&amp;rsquo;s, the offense of choice for us (Furious) was the vertical stack. In the vertical O, the idea is to move the disc to one sideline or the other and flood the stack to the other side of the field, thus isolating a cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles From Necessity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting topic as the need for specialized roles has been born more out of necessity than out of desire in Vancouver.
Historically, the top players on Furious have been the players who excel at multiple aspects of the game. These players have been able to fulfill multiple roles, and truly have a very strong all-around game. Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s fast pace of play combined with multiple turnovers and unforeseen situations, calls for players on the field to be able to adapt and excel regardless of the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice For Improvement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I am writing in about this topic not because I am a great distance thrower. In fact I am quite the opposite. Throwing the disc was something that I did with much trepidation for many years. In fact I was ridiculed constantly by my teammates for not being able to throw a simple backhand (which is why my scoober is a decent throw for me now).
However, over the years I have improved in this area and I do have some advice to pass along to others who struggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get In Front</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</guid>
      <description>Even though the answer to this question is pretty straightforward—a surprising number of club players make errors on this play.
First of all, if I am only a stride or two behind my check when a huck goes up then I am feeling pretty good about my positioning. Only a perfectly thrown disc will not allow me to have a play on it. Secondly—and this is where many players make an error—I always make the inside play on the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cue The Comeback!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</guid>
      <description>Well&amp;hellip;the answer to a situation like this (defending a handler in the lanes) is going to be dependant on a number of factors and variables that are unknown in this scenario (athletic ability, height, speed, etc.). However, in a general sense, if you have one of the main players on the opposing team drastically altering their game due to your defensive strategy then your defensive strategy is effective. Forcing a &amp;ldquo;main handler&amp;rdquo; to strike and cut downfield is a great situation for the defensive team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
