<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Slow-Developing Chess Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</guid>
      <description>Zone O is like a game of chess- you spend a while moving your pieces around the board, not making much apparent headway, trying to find the weakness in the other team&amp;rsquo;s defense, and then suddenly you see your opportunity to capture their queen and it&amp;rsquo;s off to the races! Zone O also often showcases the triumph of craftiness over athleticism. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be faster or taller or quicker than the other team- you just need to be skilled with the disc, disciplined, and know how to take advantage of the opportunities that present themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments &amp; Positioning</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</guid>
      <description>The easiest way to simulate bad-weather conditions in a drill or a game is to simply tell your players to not throw the throws you can&amp;rsquo;t realistically complete in those conditions. The idea is to gain confidence in beating a zone with flat, crisp, high percentage throws. And if for some reason they decide to throw a cross-field hammer, or 10 yard push pass, stop the drill and reset, or just call it a turnover and continue playing from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Practice For Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</guid>
      <description>Zone offense is very difficult to simulate in practice. The skills necessary for zone are often quite different than for man (offense and defense). For zone O, you need to practice vision, patience and confidence which are quite difficult to simulate. For the most part, we usually teach zone O by drawing it up on a white board, going over it on the field and then doing LOTS of 5/10-pulls sometimes stopping the point to reposition people, especially in the early parts of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Fundamentals Of Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll write here about the fundamentals of good zone O. These will, I hope, reveal some underlying principles that any team can apply to its specific strategy/terminology, and to specific situations (e.g., how to deal with a sideline trip). I&amp;rsquo;ll rely on my co-contributors to address those specifics in detail, and read with interest!
So, getting down to basics&amp;hellip;
To figure out how our zone offense should work, we should think about what makes good zone defense successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepping For A 4-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>A zone defense is usually designed to only give the offense options that do not play to their strengths (i.e. working it laterally, taking away speed, or breaking the mark into the wind). I have been on women&amp;rsquo;s teams before that have had a very difficult time with the four person cup in a moderately windy (cross wind) situation. Typically, the defense would trap the downwind sideline making it difficult for the thrower to break the cup not only because there are four big defensive players near them, but also because there is a wind in their face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions About Your Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of ways to try to approximate the weather approximations that a zone offense will face. Some of these strengthen the defense such as adding an 8th player to the d or shortening the stall count while others might hamper the offense no overheads or huck limits.
There is really no good way to approximate inclement weather for the offense, but at some point you can handcuff the offense enough that when they face a weather situation with standard playing conditions they will feel that things are easy, and really that is the goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Condor Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>Up through the 90s, teams played a mix of two- and three-handler sets, but all zone offenses emphasized swinging the disc and attacking the far side of the field against a zone on the run. Then, the Condors, led by handlers James Studarus, Steve Dugan and Taro Ramberg began to run something fundamentally different. This was a two-handler set that didn&amp;rsquo;t swing and attacked a stagnant zone. Their philosophy was that no matter how many defenders you pulled in, you weren&amp;rsquo;t going to be able to stop two of them from throwing it back and forth to each other on little two to five yard passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</guid>
      <description>For most zones, the vulnerable spot is ten yards behind the cup (or front wall). To get there you can go through the cup, over the cup, or around the cup. Through and over involve risk. Around requires patience and planned cuts. Ideally after the swing, before the cup is reset, the handler has two cutters available for the next throw, one a continuation to the line and the other a throw to the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Points</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</guid>
      <description>Three points about zone offense that are usually true:
Your poppers have to identify the zone they are playing against and adjust their positioning/movement accordingly. Handlers must do the same and adjust their throws.
Keep moving. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for deeps and wings to start standing and watching. Even if your zone offense calls for you as the deep O threat to go to the back of the endzone, move around there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wings &amp; Poppers</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</guid>
      <description>My college team always seemed to be able to only field 5 good zone offense players. The last two players on the line were usually assigned to play the wing position—that is, the popper responsible for making cuts to the sideline when the handlers swung the disc around. As a result, I never really appreciated how important the wing position is to an effective zone offense until I started playing club.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
