<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/about/</guid>
      <description>The Huddle, created by Ben Wiggins and Andy Lovseth, was an incredible resource while it existed, presenting a wealth of high-level information that is still extremely useful and relevant.
This web-site is an archive of The Huddle that intends to make the contents easier to search and prettier to read. This archive has been generated from another archive available at the USA Ultimate website, which is a little hard to read and navigate, especially on mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find What Works For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>We all know how exciting it is to play Ultimate, and we all know what it feels like to have those butterflies before game time. Having a well executed pre- game warm-up can literally mean the difference, in my opinion, between winning or losing the game. Setting the appropriate tone for game time is essential because this game we play is at least 80% mental. Here are a few things to keep in mind when you are creating a warm-up:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Team On One Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</guid>
      <description>The pre-game warmup can take on any number of forms, and I have seen successful routines span a huge range, from individual to team wide and from fully choreographed to ad hoc. In all cases, the general goal of the warmup should be to get the body ready to perform at a peak performance. This will require people to exert some energy, get a light sweat on and get the muscles firing, and should also include a few throws to help players calibrate to the conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing For The Game At Hand</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/preparing-for-the-game-at-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/preparing-for-the-game-at-hand/</guid>
      <description>There are many strategies for trying to prepare your team to get properly warmed up. I will hit on the main scenario for pre-game warm-up- preparing for the first game of the day.
Most teams have their own set warm-up that they perform; however, in my opinion the overall goal for warming up before the first game of day should be to get everyone’s body and mind ready to compete at its peak level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routine Need Not Mean Redundant</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</guid>
      <description>You show up early.
Your team has a routine: a slow jog to get the blood flowing, the usual dynamic warm-up routine. From there, you move into the handful of drills you always do, working out the kinks, getting ready for prime time. Sound like the warm-up you know and love?
While this is the current paradigm, I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room for continued innovation. Dynamic (active) warm-ups have become the norm over the past decade, but the next step is to make your dynamic warm-up more&amp;hellip;dynamic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift Your Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</guid>
      <description>The number one mistake teams make in their pregame warmup is too much focus on the muscles and cardiovascular system and too little focus on the nervous system. There is too much focus on volume and too little focus on intensity of movement.
Last year when I was coming out of retirement I enlisted the help of some speed and agility training professionals. These guys specialize in training football players for the combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Pregame Warm-Up Routines</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/team-pregame-warm-up-routines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/team-pregame-warm-up-routines/</guid>
      <description>Team Warm ups should accomplish two goals:
Prepare a team 1) mentally and 2) physically for the game ahead. Most teams perform at their peak if they can use their warm up to feel like they comfortable with their system and their bodies. Any team warm up should include enough things to get the team focused and ready for the task at hand without becoming drudgery.
The &amp;ldquo;warm up&amp;rdquo; should generally start an hour before the first pull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New School Warm-up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/the-new-school-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/the-new-school-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>A quality warm up should simply prepare the body for the work to follow. What is to follow? A match of our beautiful, dynamic sport that involves sprinting, jumping, throwing, marking and changing direction&amp;hellip;
Ok, so how do we prepare for all that?
The New School Warm Up: Pros: The most effective way to prepare the body to work out
Cons: Takes a relatively long time, requires tools, is not flashy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Warm-Up Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>While others may be more concerned with adjustments for each game, specific plyometrics, or the most useful drills, I have 3 solid beliefs on fundamentals of warm-ups:
Try to do the same thing for each game. No matter what you may include in your warm-ups, teams and individuals respond well to a routine. This way players don’t have to focus too much on the timing or progression of warm-ups and can instead focus on their skills, body and/or uncontrollables around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Will Laugh</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</guid>
      <description>Within 5 years, I firmly believe that we will look back on the warm-ups we use now and laugh. This isn&amp;rsquo;t true for every team, but I think that most high- level teams are warming up in ways that are more similar than they are different. Team huddle, jogging, stretching, plyos, throwing, catching drills, personal time, huck drills, 7v7, pre-game huddle, cheer, etc, etc. And those combined similarities are holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[kuhl-cher]</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/-kuhl-cher-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/-kuhl-cher-/</guid>
      <description>Culture [kuhl-cher] -noun: the attitudes and behavior that are characteristic of a particular social group or organization.
Successful teams, sometimes by accident, but more often by design, share amongst their members a common set of values, attitudes and goals. These characteristics define the identity of a given team, and ultimately create the culture of that team.
Everything about the actions of the team is a function of these characteristics, right down to the definition of success itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Spirit Animal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/find-your-spirit-animal/</guid>
      <description>I like to imagine a team&amp;rsquo;s culture as its spirit animal.
Furious would be a rabid dog: Fierce, foaming at the mouth, and angry.
Revolver would be a cobra: Patient, calculating, and deadly.
Chain is like a big gorilla: Powerful, intimidating, and brutish.
Sockeye is like a monkey: Playful, goofy, throwing its own feces, yet strong.
Okay, Tyler. What in the hell are you talking about.
Well, think about it this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Will Change Every Season</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to realize about your team’s culture is that it will change every season.
Yes, I was concerned when I first joined Riot that I might never fit into the intense, upfront grind of the kickass East Coast transplant women, but the team has changed a great deal in the past 7 years. Riot has become a weird, unique, open-nearly-to-a-fault bunch of weenies (young and old) who’d rather drink Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Team Culture Moments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/key-team-culture-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/key-team-culture-moments/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The very essence of leadership is that you have to have vision. It’s got to be a vision you articulate clearly and forcefully on every occasion. You can’t blow an uncertain trumpet.&amp;rdquo; — Father Theodore Hesburgh
If team culture is simply a set commonly held attitudes and beliefs about a team, then the reason for wanting to encourage helpful culture is straightforward: it helps performance.
As evidence, here’s an example of a &amp;ldquo;team culture&amp;rdquo; situation that you may have seen or been a party to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuture What You Like, Overcome What You Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</guid>
      <description>Team culture can often be overlooked as an important contributor to your team’s success, both in the short and long term. The culture of your team determines what types of players will be attracted to the team, will enjoy playing on your team, and will stick around season after season. There is no one &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; team culture, and it can be defined as much from the actions of a single individual (founder, strong personality, etc) as shaped over time by the collective actions and personalities of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustaining Team Culture</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</guid>
      <description>A former captain and then-coach of mine offered only this advice when I described to him the multitude of ideas and plans we rising seniors at Dartmouth had for team leadership and culture in the coming season: It’s always harder than you think.
This message is worth keeping in mind for anyone seeking to engineer or change something as amorphous yet integral as one’s team culture - it’s all too easy to get caught up in the energy and excitement of the season and neglect the grand ideas and notions you have for making this season the season for you and your teammates, to say nothing of the difficulty of managing people in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Identity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/team-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/team-identity/</guid>
      <description>Why have some teams (in both college and club) been around for years while others fade in and out of existence, emerging with new names and members every year? What seems to be true is that teams with strong identities have more fun, are more dedicated, stick around longer and play better. The teams that don’t will fight, argue and fade away. What do you think about as a leader and team member of a team struggling to exist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Them</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the WUFF Warriors defeated FBI from Portland, Oregon 11-6 at Chicago Tune Up. That win was probably the biggest win for a Wilmington club team since the Slickers defeated NY Graffiti at Worlds in 1993 [one could argue that the victory over Philly in the regional final in ’95 was larger, but I’ll take ‘93]. Later that weekend the Warriors defeated Ring of Fire 11-10; the first win over Ring for a Wilmington team since 1996 [though in ’96 they called themselves En Fuego I believe].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Together</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/work-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/work-together/</guid>
      <description>Ultimate is a sport of independent minded players—players who like to self- govern—and in ultimate a wide range of personal investment and work ethic on a given team is common. This creates a difficult situation: the headstrong leader yelling about commitment as the fun loving party-captain rolls his eyes. Forming a single team identity can be daunting. The most important step is to get everyone together doing something other than playing ultimate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Focus, Full Effort</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</guid>
      <description>When planning a practice, it is important to think about the personnel and goals of a practice. For instance, a fall practice for a college team is going to have very different objectives than a fall practice for an elite open team. The college team might be trying to have a lot of fun to &amp;ldquo;set the hook&amp;rdquo; with new players and give a lot of reps to players still learning the game, while an elite team is tuning up for the peak of their season and should be focusing on consistent execution of skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting More Out of the Practice Warm-Up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/getting-more-out-of-the-practice-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/getting-more-out-of-the-practice-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>Nearly every team I&amp;rsquo;ve played on had what I would call the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; ultimate warm up. You jog/plyo/stretch in some combination, and then you do some set of drills which can be roughly summarized as: the down field under &amp;ldquo;cutting&amp;rdquo; drill (Go To, etc), the dump/swing/continue &amp;ldquo;handler&amp;rdquo; drill and the huck drill. There are lots of different flavors of them, with or without marks, where you start, etc, but at their core, these drills focus on 2 or 3 players while everyone else is watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Intensity, Concepts, and Fun</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning can be daunting and it’s often hard to know where to start. It can be difficult to strike the right balance between fun and intense, learning and playing, covering everything and getting enough reps on any individual thing, etc. In my experience, it helps to have a broad, season-long outline from which to flesh out individual practices. This means having a rough idea of all the different strategies you want to cover in a season (specific offenses, specific defenses, fundamentals, etc), and making sure there are enough practices to cover everything (and if there aren’t, then to scale back your expectations of how much to cover in the season!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes Are Precious</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</guid>
      <description>Minutes at practice are precious. Here are my 5 relatively simple ways to maximize the amount of growth you can foster from each of your practices. At the end, I&amp;rsquo;ve included an example set of 3 practices to try and illustrate these points.
1) Use your warm-up time effectively
Warm-ups take a large percentage of total practice time. To focus that effort, I like to include warm-up drills or games that give a good mental introduction to the purpose of later practice drills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parts of a Whole</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</guid>
      <description>Everything that happens at practice should be a building block and not an isolated event. You need to design practices behind a theme that&amp;rsquo;s overtly stated to the whole team and repeated often throughout the day. Never let the participants lose track of the day&amp;rsquo;s goal or remain unclear about the lesson at hand. Emphasizing concrete points of focus over the course of practice as well as the course of the season gives your players a measure of their progress, in addition to game-time tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Ahead</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Great practices don&amp;rsquo;t just happen. A lot of work goes on behind the scenes to plan practices that run smoothly and effortlessly, as well as accomplishing the main goal of making the team better.
Plan your practices in advance - not just the drills for one practice, but figure out what concepts you want and need to cover over the course of the season. Then break down the concepts and spread them over the available practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Youth Practices</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-youth-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-youth-practices/</guid>
      <description>Elementary Ultimate (Ages 8-11) Beginners
Fun, fun fun.
When it comes down to it, these guys just aren’t quite developed enough to hold attention on one thing for anything longer than 15 minutes. So first things first, you really have to chunk your practice out. Secondly, these kids are just learning how to use their bodies in an athletic way and ultimately a lot of what you do will be teaching them overall coordination and control of their bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Planning Musts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</guid>
      <description>1. Write it down.
This helps you remember your plan, creates a document that you can return to, and can be emailed to the team beforehand if you feel it would help.
2. Specify time allotments for each segment of practice.
This creates a schedule, and is easier on you (you know when to start/stop a drill) and your team (they know there&amp;rsquo;s a plan to stick to).
3. Don&amp;rsquo;t perform a drill for more than 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice? We Talkin&#39; About Practice?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</guid>
      <description>Epic rants by NBA legends belittling the importance of practice aside, there is a wealth of evidence that points to the importance of practice, both quantity and quality, when it comes to improving athletic performance. Many people have noted that athletes seem to require at least 10 years from the time they begin a sport until they are able to reach the top of their game. Others have taken this analysis further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Habits of Highly Effective Throwers: How to Plan a Throwing Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning isn&amp;rsquo;t just for the team captain. Every player should take it upon themselves to have throwing practice in addition to team practice. Make the most of your practice hours by incorporating these habits into your throwing regimen.
1. Choose the right throwing partner(s)
Before you can even practice, you need a throwing partner!
Find a good throwing partner or several partners. If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about becoming an all-star handler, you will probably need more than one partner to get in the amount of hours required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Control of Your Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/take-control-of-your-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/take-control-of-your-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice is a vital part of mastering any skill, and team sports are no exception. A quality practice structure can transform a meaningless few hours running around into a valuable and productive growth opportunity for your team. While the content covered in a given practice clearly varies heavily with the level, division, weather, time of year, etc, some of the basics of running a quality practice are nearly always applicable. Here are a few of my favorites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Easy Targets</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/three-easy-targets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/three-easy-targets/</guid>
      <description>It’s the end of the day, and it feels like nothing has been accomplished. Teammates barely listened to instruction, drills were sloppy and unfocused, everything took twice as long as it should have, and you walk away with a sick taste in your mouth, directing your anger and frustration towards the most vocal trouble-makers. That’s right, you’ve just experienced another bad practice.
We’ve all had this feeling before, and while you’ll probably have it again, there are ways we can reduce the severity of the bad practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Constant Stream Of Specific Information</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-constant-stream-of-specific-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-constant-stream-of-specific-information/</guid>
      <description>When I played in college especially, my team made a concerted effort to maintain an active sideline and to communicate efficiently from the sideline rather than simply being loud. That carried over in Club, where I played with many of those same players.
When I am on the sideline helping teammates on the field, I like to select one player to communicate with and focus on two things: 1) conveying information and 2) being specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Strong Sideline Voice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</guid>
      <description>Most offenders will tell you that yelling instructions to them on the sideline when they&amp;rsquo;re on offense is annoying, if not worse. When you&amp;rsquo;re on offense, sideline chatter is best saved for positive encouragement and celebrating a goal scored.
However, on D, the sideline is an incredibly powerful tool, able to create momentum on your side, stop momentum for the other team, and create blocks that otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Now, a good sideline voice has a few characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assisting The Visually Impaired</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/assisting-the-visually-impaired/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/assisting-the-visually-impaired/</guid>
      <description>The impact of the sideline is most important when the team is on defense. In ultimate, as in most possession style games, the offense has a distinct advantage. The offense is in control of where the future will take place on the field and therefore offensive players are ABLE to be a step ahead of the defense at all times. It is the job of the defenders to constantly anticipate where the thrower would like to throw and when those spaces will be available, while at the same time making decisions to force blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Takes Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/it-takes-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/it-takes-practice/</guid>
      <description>Like any team, Death or Glory had its own mythology. As a green twenty-year old, very few tales of the past loomed as large for me as Paul Greff’s block against the Condors in 1998. It seemed told and told again: as the deep in the zone at a critical point, Paul hears someone on the sideline telling him to drop and he does, without looking, just in time to get a game saving block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep It Calm</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/keep-it-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/keep-it-calm/</guid>
      <description>Assuming there are other essays that discuss the importance of having one sideline voice using simple language, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a slightly contrarian approach to the topic: there&amp;rsquo;s not much you can really accomplish from the sideline during a game. Put more accurately, the best you can hope for from your sideline is to help remind the players on the field of what they already know. Defensive blocks are created by players executing the strategy they decided on before the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loud &#43; Positive = Good</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</guid>
      <description>I think that sideline contributions are underrated in their worth by most teams and particularly by most great players. People who are great at team sports are not necessarily motivated to play well for themselves – especially in our sport, they are motivated to play well by their love of team, teammates and something bigger than themselves.
In this way, I will stand by something I accidentally said in a huddle last year: &amp;ldquo;Loud information is good information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Useful</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</guid>
      <description>Basic principles of sideline talk are fairly simple: make it targeted (say the player’s name first), make it specific (not just &amp;ldquo;c’mon, go, go&amp;rdquo;), and give information (not instruction). You may not know what the player already knows and is planning, so this lets him decide what to do and how to handle the info. (Sometimes, if the level of trust is high, off-field players can give instructions rather than information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide New Information and Reinforcement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>Sideline talk should make the players on the field more effective in two ways: it should help them make different decisions than they might make otherwise, and it should help them (re)act more quickly to game situations. In other words, the primary functions of sideline talk are to provide new information, and to provide reinforcement that cuts down processing time.
&amp;lsquo;Provide new information&amp;rsquo;: tell the player on the field anything they can&amp;rsquo;t see that might- or should- change the way they play for the next few seconds or passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing The Work</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/sharing-the-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/sharing-the-work/</guid>
      <description>Standing on the sidelines is, for many players, the hardest or most frustrating part of being on a team. Ultimate is special in the larger world of sports in that the sideline is a great place to help your team out. Where in other sports the sideline is not allowed to actively participate by communicating with their fellow players on the field, in Ultimate the sideline can work as an eighth player, one with position and focus dedicated to improving the outcome of strategies and plays being made my fielded players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing A Team Way Of Communicating</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</guid>
      <description>Different teams have a very different approach to the role of individuals when they’re on the sideline. Some teams like to give the players on the sideline a chance to rest and have them sit in the shade to recover for their next time in the game. Others, especially in the college ranks, can have countless players making tons of useless noise from the sidelines. I think the best teams find a way to keep players involved in the success of the team when they are not one of the seven guys on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangible vs. Intangible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</guid>
      <description>As cliché as it may be, it is true that the sideline can equate to the eighth man (woman) for a team. However, I would say the sideline can mean much more than just an eighth man. The sideline can be a symbolic representation of the morale and demeanor of the game.
Most speak of the sideline and the tangible benefits of using your voices to motivate and push your teammates in the heat of battle on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</guid>
      <description>In the moment of competition, I like my brain to be functioning on approximately the level of a caveman chasing a woolly mammoth. The biggest motivation to help from the sideline is that the louder I yell, the more primordial I feel, and the better I play. It’s the best way for me to get in and stay in &amp;ldquo;the zone.&amp;rdquo;
Here is a great description of the zone, which I recently read in a novel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Things Durings A Point</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</guid>
      <description>When you find yourself on the sideline, there are two obvious things to do during a point. You should serve as an extra brain and pair of eyes to help them execute the team’s strategy, and you need to encourage them to keep putting in effort. I’ll skip over these two aspects of sideline help (which I hope others will cover in more detail), and focus on one aspect which takes place after a point is over, and one aspect which is believed to be helpful, but is frequently not, and should be discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Perspective</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/a-little-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/a-little-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Field vision is the ability to understand the dynamics of the opposition&amp;rsquo;s offense or defense despite being embroiled in a battle against it. Every team has players who see plays happen/develop (be it from on the pitch or the sideline), and compile the information to start the next point with the knowledge they just took on board (and, importantly, can dispense it to their teammates). It is these adaptive players that win tight matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Your Eyes To Open Them</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/closing-your-eyes-to-open-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/closing-your-eyes-to-open-them/</guid>
      <description>Good field vision can be described as a contrast between being somebody with good field sense and somebody who has &amp;ldquo;visionary throws.&amp;rdquo; If you have ever been called &amp;ldquo;visionary&amp;rdquo; I bet that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a compliment.
Most of the time people who are described as having good field vision are players who have a general sense of what is going on with all 14 players on the field. This is broken down into four things: a good understanding of passing lanes, a strong mastery of various throwing skills, a knowledge of what the offensive system is trying to attack and what the defense is currently doing to stop that attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn To Think So You Don&#39;t Have To Think</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</guid>
      <description>How do we make decisions? In many real-life examples we create a list of choices and features, maybe take some data, rate how each option stacks up in each feature, and coolly select the optimum choice. In ultimate you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to go through this whole process. You have to rely on your trained inner self to figure out what to do based on internalized guidelines.
Since I like lists of rules here are some for making sense of what is happening on the field and figuring out what to do about it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Recognition</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Psychologist John Dewey debunked a commonly held belief called the stimulus- response reflex arc: you see something, you decide what to do, you respond. Instead, Dewey proposed, you only see what you have a mental framework for; this framework contains your response within it. In other words, your response exists before you see the stimulus. Many players have the experience of knowing they&amp;rsquo;ve thrown the goal before the disc leaves their hands, or &amp;ldquo;seeing&amp;rdquo; the lay out D before it happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play A Different Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</guid>
      <description>I would argue that field vision, like speed or height, is pretty hard to teach and learn. The best athletes don&amp;rsquo;t see what&amp;rsquo;s happening so much as take a picture of the field and respond. A few brains can do that kind of thing, but most can&amp;rsquo;t. Bill Rodriguez would counsel deeps in a zone to move up if they saw seven opposing players in front of them. Super, if, like Bill, you can see them all at once and count them at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding The Information</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</guid>
      <description>Understanding positioning and distribution of players on the field is an important skill, but also somewhat of an innate ability. How this skill manifests itself is sometimes subtle and other times overt. It can show up in the guy who always seems to be making the good cut to keep the offensive flow going or in the physically ungifted player who consistently finds themselves alone in the endzone. It can be the thrower who is able to find targets on the goal line or the defender who gets a lot of poach blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yeah Iverson, We&#39;ve Talkin&#39; About Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have a rather painful childhood memory from back in middle school. I was playing basketball and went to set a low screen for another player. In a moment of miscommunication both my defender and the player who I set a pick on rushed to guard my teammate. I was left open for just a few seconds, but before I realized it, the basketball hit me in the face. The point guard recognized that I was about to be open and passed the ball early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain: Building A Core</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</guid>
      <description>Good club teams often have a core of stars who have played with each other for a while. Looking at Chain Lightning&amp;rsquo;s roster last year, I was struck by how little turnover the team experienced. With a few notable exceptions, last year&amp;rsquo;s Chain team was the same team that lost in the semifinals in 2008, bolstered by the addition of five rookies, all of whom Chain used in key defensive roles (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain: The New DoG</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</guid>
      <description>During DoG&amp;rsquo;s heyday 15 years ago, our main offensive strength was that we would take what they&amp;rsquo;d give us. Our offense was efficient, not just in terms of scoring percentage, but in using energy wisely. Players created space by knowing when to get out of the way or to simply stay put and remain out of the way. We liked the long game, but were equally comfortable in taking a series of passes up the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain&#39;s Big Assist From The Weather</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</guid>
      <description>After twelve straight years as a nationals participant in the Open division (1997-2008), in 2009 as a masters player was a different experience. First, few people, and really nobody outside the division itself, care much about the Masters division. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say it isn&amp;rsquo;t competitive, or even that there isn&amp;rsquo;t good Ultimate being played there, it&amp;rsquo;s just that when you have the Open nationals to watch, why would you watch Masters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury By The Numbers: Conversion &amp; Psyche</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</guid>
      <description>Despite Backhoe outscoring Brute Squad 9-7 in the second half after starting out the game 0-6, 2-8 at half, Brute never allowed the game to get ugly [ugly meaning a turnover-fest]. Of the 16 goals (37 possessions) scored between the teams in the second half, 12 were scored on one possession: Backhoe was 8 for 9, Brute was 4 for 7; two of the remaining four were 2nd possession goals. Regardless of our unusual second half efficiency (statistically we were strong on O2D and had a high percentage of Offense 2nd possession [O2] goals), we still walked into our match-up with Fury like a wounded animal looking to make too many corrections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury Knows How To Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</guid>
      <description>Fury, more than any other Women&amp;rsquo;s team in the nation (perhaps ever, though there will be those who argue for Godiva or Maineiacs), knows what to do in Sarasota.
Each player seems to have a very good grasp of her specific role from the top of the roster to the bottom. Everyone plays that role perfectly when push comes to shove. They don&amp;rsquo;t mess around against teams they know they will beat, and they bring it hard to teams that might have entertained thoughts of having a chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Chain Won 2009 Nationals - Offensively</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/how-chain-won-2009-nationals-offensively/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/how-chain-won-2009-nationals-offensively/</guid>
      <description>I was in a unique position at the championships last season: being employed by the UPA to follow the action and write daily recaps on the website&amp;rsquo;s results page for the Open Division. In this capacity I witnessed part of each game Chain was involved in, and as they progressed through the tournament I got to watch how they were able to attack so effectively against the other top teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Teens Again</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</guid>
      <description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t there, but as I was watching the live feed of Fury dismantling Brute Squad I was struck by a sense of déjà vu; I felt like I was watching Godiva. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about Fury and Godiva&amp;rsquo;s dominance, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about a single little cut that is the backbone of both team&amp;rsquo;s offenses. It&amp;rsquo;s a cut I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen other teams (men&amp;rsquo;s or women&amp;rsquo;s) use. I remember watching Teens (Christine Dunlap) wreck people with this cut, getting wide open again and again and again, so it was a little weird to watch Fury doing the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</guid>
      <description>As others have mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s highly important to catch the pull whenever possible. In the Women&amp;rsquo;s game, far too many players let the pull hit the ground if it comes in at a hard angle. As a puller, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to take advantage of this by working on big outside-in pulls to gain an extra second or two while the player stops a roll and picks up the disc, possibly gain field position if the player misreads how the disc will roll, and give the offense a wet disc to work with if there&amp;rsquo;s dew on the grass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate 2-3 Breaks A Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</guid>
      <description>Preface: Ever since I started playing competitive Ultimate, I have been on the D team. So, receiving the pull isn&amp;rsquo;t something that I have partaken in very often. That being said, I have done it and can give a viewpoint from a defensive standpoint.
Most important and crucial part of receiving the pull is the reception. I mean pure and simple, having someone there to initially catch the disc. From an offensive standpoint, catching the pull is where the offense begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left &amp; Right Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I would be very intrigued to hear the Open authors&amp;rsquo; answers on this question because, for the most part, Women&amp;rsquo;s pulls do not involve a ridiculous amount of rocket science to field (or maybe I have been missing out on something for years).
Typically, we will call a pull play where one person on the left side of the field fields the pull if it goes left and one person on the right side of the field fields the pull if it goes right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respond As It Comes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</guid>
      <description>The best offensive teams can get big yards from the first few passes off a pull, and immediately knock the defense on its heels. There are no shortage of ways to do this, and the best offenses I have been a part of have always had a few options for taking this advantage.
In all cases the critical first component is having a player who feels comfortable catching the pull and throwing the first pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</guid>
      <description>The key goal when receiving the pull is to get into your play/offense as quickly and safely as possible. A few thoughts on how to do this:
Unless the pull is going out of bounds or a big blade in a nice wind, catch it and get it moving. If it&amp;rsquo;s a big blade, stop it as soon as it hits and do the same thing. The only situation which I can think of in which you would not want to do this is if the pull is going to hit and slide out of bounds AND the defense is already set up on all the people you might throw to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Catch To The Hitch</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</guid>
      <description>I have traditionally posted to this website with answers that questioned the question instead of answered it. I feel that I owe Ben and Andy a single straightforward response.
My teams have traditionally fielded the pull with the three handlers. The &amp;ldquo;Catch,&amp;rdquo; not surprisingly, catches the pull. I am surprised how often capable players choose to let pulls hit the ground instead of catching them on the fly. I encourage attempting to catch all but the most vertical of pulls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfailing Terminology</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</guid>
      <description>Catching the pull requires four players: a 1, a 2, a Short Fill, and a Deep Fill. Everyone else can have their heads up their asses and it&amp;rsquo;ll be okay.
The 1&amp;rsquo;s job is to catch the pull and make the first pass.
The 2&amp;rsquo;s job is to set themselves up to catch the first pass, catch the first pass and then deliver the big throw to the 3.
The Short Fill&amp;rsquo;s job is to read the pull and the defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Unpredictable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</guid>
      <description>1. Face the mark. This classic piece of throwing technology dates back to the dawn of modern Ultimate when Windy City and NYNY ruled. The uneducated thrower looks upfield at the stack and they position their body to reflect this. When they want to throw a dump they have to turn 270 degrees, which is incredibly slow. (Or turn their back to the field, which is incredibly dumb.) By facing the mark, you shorten the turn to 180 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut &amp; Clear</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</guid>
      <description>When we&amp;rsquo;re facing a &amp;ldquo;rotated&amp;rdquo; mark paired with good up-line dump defense, we have to do a few things to win.
First, we have to cut and clear decisively. The defensive tactic succeeds if it forces the handlers to &amp;ldquo;dance,&amp;rdquo; clogging the reset lane and creating uncertainty for the thrower. Even if the handlers have nowhere to run but towards the defense, they must run. Often times, the defense isn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as it looks and the handler can swim past the up-line defender, or the thrower can shimmy to open up the around-break throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move As Early As Possible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</guid>
      <description>In framing this discussion, I think it is important to note that some teams have a static approach to shifting the mark, while others are more dynamic. In the static case, the mark starts off taking away more of the reset look only on the sideline, while giving up more of an angle downfield. In the dynamic case, the marker starts off with a conventional angle, but rotates with the marker when they turn to hit the dump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Without The Frisbee</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/moving-without-the-frisbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/moving-without-the-frisbee/</guid>
      <description>Rotating the mark is a very effective strategy in forcing teams into difficult situations. This strategy works especially well in windy conditions or against teams that primarily run a vertical stack. I am sure that other authors will talk about the mechanics of the thrower in this situation but the one thing that I want to emphasize in this situation is the role of the cutter (normally a handler) who is in the dump position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotate 90°</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark can effectively make the backfield dump a very difficult throw. Here are a few ways to prevent this defense from making your life as a thrower difficult.
First of all, the D is most effective on a high stall count when you are running out of time and options (and many teams will only shift their marks to take away the dump once the stall count gets high).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Advantage Of The Given Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</guid>
      <description>Rotating the mark can be a very effective strategy against teams that effectively use the reset to work the disc upfield when the initial cut isn&amp;rsquo;t open. This defense works best when it has the element of surprise behind it. However, like many defenses, if offenses recognize that this strategy is being used they can develop a plan to counter it.
The easiest thing to think about is what the defense gives up when they implement this strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Looks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</guid>
      <description>Nothing earth-shattering here, but first and most important: the easiest way to get out of this situation is to avoid it. A good offense recognizes what the D is playing early (see the zone, see the clam, see everything). An anti- reset mark can be set up by the defense several throws ahead. A person sits in the lane, leaving the handler on the sideline open. It&amp;rsquo;s an obvious throw. The first way to avoid this is to have that receiver (the person who would be trapped) move towards the thrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition From The Grabled Mess</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark is very effective at putting throwers in an uncomfortable position. You&amp;rsquo;ve been working it up the line effectively, dumping when needed, but generally marching up the field. Now, the defense has shifted, and you either have to make a tough break backwards or hope that your resets can break free up the line. The sideline, as the 8th defender, limits your options. Typically in these situations there is a flood of players close to you, as cutters come in for the bail or defenders sag a bit into the lane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</guid>
      <description>There are a few key tricks that I have found make an effective mark. Some are commonly talked about and pretty well agreed. I do think that not all of these are universally agreed. This is mostly a list of key points, rather than in depth on each one.
The first is mental. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to relax when you get to a mark. It&amp;rsquo;s important to remind yourself that you are responsible for more of the field than any other single defender on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond The Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the fundamentals of marking—getting low with the hips, staying balanced, keeping arms wide—here are a few &amp;ldquo;advanced fundamental&amp;rdquo; techniques.
1. Chin up, eyes on the chest. My hand is much more likely to find its way in front of the disc when I&amp;rsquo;m only &amp;ldquo;looking&amp;rdquo; with my peripheral vision. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this works so well. In part, I think it&amp;rsquo;s because good throwers use disc fakes to get you out of position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending The Area Around The Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy marking—particularly in the zone of a 1-3-3. Marking is a very important part of the game that often goes unnoticed or is an afterthought in defensive play. Teams usually pay some lip service to marking strategy (forcing flick or middle or straight-up), but that tends to be about it. Unfortunately, common practice is that the marker will rest on the mark. They use the mark as a chance to get their breath and prepare for another defensive run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventative vs. Deceptive</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</guid>
      <description>The most common mark you see on the frisbee field is what I would define as a preventative mark. The mark has each arm extended out fully, explicitly placed to take away a specific throw. This is a useful mark as it does prevent the intended throws and it is seen at every level of frisbee (see photo 1). However, though it is useful, it has certain disadvantages. It allows the thrower to know which throws you are trying to take away before they even attempt to throw or fake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Marking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</guid>
      <description>When marking, face to face, one-on-one with your opponent, you are more closed off from the game around you than at any other moment in Ultimate. This leads some markers to try for too much, going for every block. Others miss opportunities to help their teammates by adhering too closely to the force. Effective marking requires a balance between these extremes. One trick to achieving this balance (and knowing when to take a risk on the mark) is glancing over your shoulder at the oncoming cuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidbits</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of marking tidbits I&amp;rsquo;ve heard and dispensed over the years. I find myself repeatedly coming back to four in particular. Two of these pieces of wisdom have come from amazing coaches, one is from a legendary point-block machine, and one is from observations of what makes the biggest difference in my own marking.
From Jennifer &amp;ldquo;JD&amp;rdquo; Donnelly (while coaching Stanford Superfly): Your mark should take into account body mechanics and reaction time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips &amp; Insights</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</guid>
      <description>When the disc is dead, always check behind your back to see where the first threats are and position yourself to take those away most effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s the one chance you have to see what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen behind you before you set up your mark—use it!
I try to think of my arms and legs separately as a &amp;rsquo;two-pronged&amp;rsquo; defense. Think of your arms as being on a separate vertical plane from your legs, so that the thrower has to get through 2 vertical planes of extremities rather than just one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks Of The Trade</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tricks-of-the-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tricks-of-the-trade/</guid>
      <description>As a player who is in all honesty not the most gifted and speedy athlete in the game, getting defensive turnovers with monster layouts and big skies is not always the best strategy for me. I learned early on however that I can still have a huge effect on the defensive side of the game by simply focusing on putting on a solid mark on the player I&amp;rsquo;m covering (or trying to cover) once they have the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice, No More</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve mastered the basics (like the two-spot mark) and the not-so-basic- but-standard (like denying the dump on stalling 8), it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to learning individual players.
Of course you know all the moves of your nemesis; you play him five times a season and cover him every point you&amp;rsquo;re in. Of course you adjust your game to meet the challenge. Your match-ups become games within games within games where the slightest mistake yields victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</guid>
      <description>Marking consists of two simple steps: knowing the threats, and denying the threats. While the specifics will depend on how your team decides to play defense, the ideas below will apply in nearly all situations.
Step 1: Know the threats.
The best way to adjust your mark is to anticipate what the offense wants to do. If you can read the offense, you can take away the throws that would help them the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tennis Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</guid>
      <description>I usually try to write on the presented topic from a objective and scientific viewpoint, however, due to the nature of this topic, this will be rather subjective and opinionated. Also, much of this is a comparison to tennis since that is where I have participated in the highest levels of competition prior to frisbee.
Growing up learning the sport of Ultimate in Australia, my viewpoint of SOTG comes from a more global perspective of competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character When It Matters Most</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</guid>
      <description>Spirit of the Game is easy when the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;hellip;but that is certainly not the case with Northwest Regionals. Every game is a battle and every game is intense. In my opinion, it is when the UPA Series starts that Spirit matters most.
The best players in the game can play at an incredibly high level without compromising their personal integrity or the reputation of their team. I think that sometimes Spirit of the Game is mistaken for not contesting calls or not being willing to make a call, but really it is honoring your opponents and yourself by playing 100% and making calls if true violations or fouls occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codifying Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</guid>
      <description>This topic is not useless, but I find that my thoughts on it are fairly disconnected.
A phrase that reminds us to respect each other and the game makes sense even if it is not as effective as some would like preventing players from cheating or acting like jerks. We are really just codifying the idea that Ultimate players should practice good sportsmanship, That has value, I hope.
A lot of people discover Ultimate after some bad experience with another sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even If No One Is Watching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</guid>
      <description>Really, honestly, how can anyone possibly not believe that this is a worthy philosophy to embrace? The only thing that kills me is the the name: &amp;ldquo;Spirit of the Game.&amp;rdquo; The word spirit is not synomynous with common words and expressions I associate with sports: Grit - Battle - Fair - Integrity - Determination - Motivation - Guts - Glory - Respect. &amp;ldquo;Spirit&amp;rdquo; is a word that I would associate with yoga class, folklore, or a Bible Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Turn As That Guy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/my-turn-as-that-guy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/my-turn-as-that-guy/</guid>
      <description>I know a lot of your other articles are going to be from people that always do the right thing, but not everyone is them. I thank you for letting me write from my perspective without, I think, giving people the wrong impression about my team. But I think it is important that you get all sides here.
I cheated in a game-to-go. When I made the call I thought it was correct but I knew right then about ten seconds later that it was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Rules</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</guid>
      <description>No one gets four strikes in baseball simply because they think its wrong that the rules allow only three. You don&amp;rsquo;t pick and choose which rules to follow. You play by the rules of the game. Whether or not you agree with it, the Spirit of the Game concept is a fixture in the official rules of Ultimate so we, as players, have an obligation to adhere to it. But in the middle of a game, especially one with much at stake, what does it mean to adhere to a concept that is so vaguely defined?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platoon</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</guid>
      <description>ECC and Chesapeake are behind us, as is Sectionals. We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past 8 weeks running 120s. We started Cones after Sectionals. In what will have been a mere stepping stone of a game for us, the trust building and empathy through conditioning mentioned above will raise its beautiful head at Regionals, as will the burden of self-officiating.
2nd round and it&amp;rsquo;s 5 all and on serve. hile there are no certainties, except that one that says we&amp;rsquo;ll receive for the 2nd half, they will only score 3 more points to our 10; but at 5 all, nobody but nobody knows this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirit Of The Games</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/spirit-of-the-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/spirit-of-the-games/</guid>
      <description>I am not going to write about history. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write of how &amp;ldquo;zealots&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;RSDers&amp;rdquo; alike bake their theory cake and top it with a little Spirit icing so everybody thinks it will taste sweet. If I am going to talk about it, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be about me and what I think, so here goes:
Spirit is respect. Respect for your opponent, respect for the situation, and respect for right to play this game at any level you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blender</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</guid>
      <description>What if the Minnesota Timerwolves had to play Macalaster College and a YWCA pick-up team on their road to an NBA Championship? What if the Commissioner of MLB also governed little league and summer softball league? Those levels of play differ so much they are hardly the same sport. Yet in the Club Series of Ultimate, players from all levels comingle on the same field. The best players in the world compete against absolute novices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Issues With Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</guid>
      <description>I love the Huddle. I think the work they do is a great contribution to Ultimate, I love reading the other contributors&amp;rsquo; work and I am honored that they would include me as an author. That said, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe they are making such a colossal mistake in having ONE Spirit of the Game issue.
Spirit of the Game is essential to Ultimate. Every time we step on the field to play, we are participating in what makes Ultimate unique and special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Principal Components</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</guid>
      <description>To me, Spirit of the Game has two principal components: respect (don&amp;rsquo;t be an ass) and integrity (don&amp;rsquo;t be a cheater). I think you could go through reams of paper defining how those two principles should and do play out, which is not my intent here.
My point is that playing with Spirit is much harder than I think we give it credit for. What we are asking of people is to fight against their ego, their desire for appreciation and status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Goes Through Your Head</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</guid>
      <description>Last year at Northeast Regionals my team (PoNY) was playing Bodhi to go to Nationals. Game tied at 12s, time cap approaching, PoNY is on defense. Bodhi goes on a fast break with a quick succession of give-go throws—&amp;ldquo;Pick!&amp;rdquo; someone yells—and the last throw, a huck, falls incomplete. The two teams start to argue. Was the pick two throws ago, or one? Does the disc go back to Bodhi, or is it a turnover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Do</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll let better writers and players describe why Spirit is, or is not, worth your time. I know my answer, and you have to find your own.
If you come away having decided that it is worth your your effort, here are a couple of things that your team can do to improve your own Spirit on the field in meaningful games. At the very least, they are things that my teams have done in the past that have helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid The Pile-Up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/avoid-the-pile-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/avoid-the-pile-up/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there before. The throw goes up, the disc catches some wind, and just hangs. As the intended offensive receiver, you are forced to slow down and track the path of the disc. It soon becomes quite crowded around you as multiple players converge on what seems like the optimal position to vie for the disc. Soon it&amp;rsquo;s time to jump for the disc and hope everything works out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beating The Pack From Below The Canopy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</guid>
      <description>Usually being the shortest guy on the teams I play on, catching 50/50 (jump ball) discs from my perspective is a different game altogether. There are two situations you can encounter with a 50/50 disc. Either you are in the eye of the storm, in which case you were the initial receiver or your the first defender to get into the play, and a multitude of others are collapsing down upon you from all places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</guid>
      <description>In order to catch a 50/50 disc a player needs to be able to do a number of things correctly to win the battle.
1. Reading
The player must be able to read the disc and understand how the wind and the way the disc was thrown is going to affect its flight path.
2. Positioning
Once that player has a good grasp of where that disc is going to float down to earth, that player must establish that position firmly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting The Advantage</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/getting-the-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/getting-the-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Catching a 50/50 disc is not an exact science just like every other aspect of Ultimate and unfortunately there aren&amp;rsquo;t a lot of aspects you can practice if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to sky the best receivers in the game. Superior athleticism and your ability to read the disc almost always win. However, there are a few things (besides improving vertical leap, experience, etc.) that can set you apart from the rest of the pack if you want to have an advantage at catching a disc over someone of similar or greater ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Into The Sky Club</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/how-to-get-into-the-sky-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/how-to-get-into-the-sky-club/</guid>
      <description>My first action, after recognizing that I am about to engage in a 50/50 disc tango, is to take the appropriate angle of attack based on where I think the disc is going to go. This is obviously stale information for veterans. But for the beginners out there, you&amp;rsquo;ll always be considered a member of the grounds crew if you keep running directly underneath the disc expecting that it will drop down to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Them Make A Play</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/make-them-make-a-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/make-them-make-a-play/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to catching a floating 50/50 disc, one of the most important things to think about is that if the other person is going to get the disc then at least make them make a play. Force them to make a great play to catch it, don&amp;rsquo;t let it be easy. This philosophy most directly applies to playing defence, but still applies to offensive situations.
Too often I see players setting up position behind their opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning &amp; Approach</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</guid>
      <description>While we call these hangers &amp;ldquo;50/50 discs,&amp;rdquo; I would bet that at the moment the disc is coming down an observer would have a better than coin-flip chance of guessing who will touch the disc first. Keying in on the information informing that decision will help guide a player in giving themselves a better than coin-flip chance of getting to it first.
I think that beyond obvious physical differences (&amp;ldquo;I like the guy who is 6&#39;8&amp;rdquo; over the short guy&amp;quot;) the two main components are positioning and approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retain That!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</guid>
      <description>To catch a 50/50 disc, you need to somehow make the chances better than 50/50 for yourself. The first thing you can do is be tall—and yes, I know you can&amp;rsquo;t teach height, but this also includes putting your hand up outstretched and trying to catch the disc at your &amp;ldquo;tallest point&amp;rdquo; including your jump. This is related to the second thing which is timing your jump. I know lots of players (particularly new women) who think just putting their hand up will work—well, it won&amp;rsquo;t work against good competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning On Both Sides Of The Disc</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/winning-on-both-sides-of-the-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/winning-on-both-sides-of-the-disc/</guid>
      <description>On Offense
You ought to have done much of the work up front. You were out in the lane first, making an open cut to the end zone, you were looking over your shoulder and saw the release point of the throw. You made your read early, calculated the trajectory of the disc, and picked your line before your defender even heard an up call.
Realizing that your thrower has laid you out to dry with a floaty throw (at least they didn&amp;rsquo;t pump fake and make you come under), you pick a spot four to five yards from where the disc will come down between the disc and the defender to hold your ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Point Guard&#34; Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</guid>
      <description>When I play, I often pick up the disc after a turnover. When I coach, my teams are in this situation often (as Lou noted, college teams have dead-disc situations much more frequently than in club Ultimate). Given the inherent confusion of the moment, I value a simple communication system in order to create positive and coordinated disc movement in a chaotic environment.
I really don&amp;rsquo;t care if everyone on the team can call plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Play(er)s</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play is if it works on the field with the players you have. No matter the nomenclature, strategic genius, or underlying theory: what happens on paper matters little.
In general, I would say most team&amp;rsquo;s playbooks (and plays) are too complicated. Go simple. And a few simple rules are:
1. Does the play work? (Not, &amp;ldquo;it would have worked if&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;)
2. What is option B if the first pass doesn&amp;rsquo;t go as designed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</guid>
      <description>In game two of this year&amp;rsquo;s Eastern Conference Finals against the Orlando Magic, LeBron and the Cavs had a set play. They were down by 2 with seconds left and needed a quick bucket. LeBron was to cut hard to the hoop for an alley-oop. Magic forward Hedo Turkoglu had an idea what would happen and positioned himself between LeBron and the basket. As the play unfolded, LeBron took a few steps towards the rim, and Turkoglu sags off him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secrecy &amp; Spying In Ultimate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2006 Sub Zero cut a player then accidentally left him on our email list. This guy later played for our competition. He forwarded to them our &amp;ldquo;playbook.&amp;rdquo; But before we uncovered the leak, Zero and this team played in finals of Sectionals. Early in the game we got our first defensive possession, near our opponent&amp;rsquo;s endzone. Mark &amp;ldquo;Paco&amp;rdquo; Enright picked up the disc and called the audible for me to cut for an immediate swing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Plays For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The trick to a good set play package is selecting the right plays for your team. Here are some basic guidelines:
1. Make it worth your time. There is only so much your team can learn, so you want to make sure you are getting the most out of what you are practicing. If you are playing elite club ultimate, over half of your possessions are going to be off of the pull, so learn more pull plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity, Creatvity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play great is simplicity and creativity. It should be designed to have a main cut, but also a bail out. It should be taught on paper, on a whiteboard, with walk-throughs and at full speed. In the past, we have relied more on designing our own plays. My women&amp;rsquo;s club team has minimal to no plays, but the college team I coach has a playbook that they rely on probably 20% of the time off a dead disc situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits Of Theft</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</guid>
      <description>Steal, steal, steal. If you are the smartest play to have ever played the game, you may have reason to rely on your own originality. If not, find out who is—be it player, team, or just a better division—and how they position themselves to be successful. Any stoppage of play, between points, after timeouts, after violations, will allow you to see what they want to do, given the context on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Double Flat Stack</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-double-flat-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-double-flat-stack/</guid>
      <description>It was late 2007, and Western Washington University was fielding an alumni team at the Sundodger Invitational. It was early on Saturday—round one or two, and I believe we were playing Simon Fraser University. A nice group of lads if ever I&amp;rsquo;d seen. They had just put a goal in, and I was trotting back to line with Dave Bestock, Ben Wiggins, and Aly Lenon, among others.
When we arrived to the line, Aly tells me to call a line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Thoughts &amp; Techniques</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/cutting-thoughts-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/cutting-thoughts-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Becoming a great cutter, like any ultimate skill, requires more than simply athleticism (though work at the track won&amp;rsquo;t hurt). It requires plenty of skill, thought, and practice. I think about cutting broken down into two components: the technique of the cut itself and cutting within an offensive system.
Cutting technique: As you start to work on your cutting technique, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to think about your strengths and role as a cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D-Line Handlers</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/d-line-handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/d-line-handlers/</guid>
      <description>I should start by saying that I am an incredibly blessed ultimate player. For the past few years, I have had the coolest job in ultimate. &amp;ldquo;Go cover whoever you want, and when we get the disc, get it moving, then put it up. Your receivers will be Beau, Jolian, Mangan and Martin.&amp;rdquo; Uhhh, yes please? (I imagine Jeremy Cram felt the same way when he was choosing between Nord, Chase, Andrew Fleming and Mark Stone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Cutting</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/deep-cutting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/deep-cutting/</guid>
      <description>Three of the handiest attributes a deep receiver can have are speed, jumping ability, and height. Sadly, even by lifting, doing plyometrics, and running sprints, an athlete and only increase her or his speed and explosiveness to a certain extent. As far as I have seen, height cannot be taught or learned. Fortunately, there are several other factors that go into being an effective deep threat, all of which are much more learnable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defense From The Handler Spot</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</guid>
      <description>A great defensive handler first and foremost plays defense. The defensive unit will only get a handful of opportunities to try to score; most of their time spent on the field will be defending. To be valuable to their team, a defensive handler will need to produce more than they give up, and the offense has a big advantage to start with. Effective defending from a variety of positions is well covered in other issues of The Huddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Handlers I Admire</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defensive-handlers-i-admire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defensive-handlers-i-admire/</guid>
      <description>Every team has its own style of play and I think it is hard to pick out characteristics that make a great defensive handler—or any other position—without considering it in the context of a specific team. That said, I have noticed that good defensive lines are able to use the chaos of a turn to their advantage. Some teams try to pick up the disc right away and move it quickly to make it difficult for the other team to set up a defense while others take their time to set up an organized offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling: Doing The Little Things</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-doing-the-little-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-doing-the-little-things/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to being a great handler than meets the eye. Being one of the better throwers on your team is important. But there have been plenty of teams on which the best thrower is not a handler, especially when it comes to hucking. This isn&amp;rsquo;t say that being a great thrower doesn&amp;rsquo;t help a handler be great. Rather, there are a lot of factors and skills that make some handlers particularly effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling: Vision</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/handling-vision/</guid>
      <description>Having great throws is one thing, but what makes a great handler is how those throws are used. A lot of characteristics that apply can be said about any great player, like the ability to consistently get open, especially late in the stall, and in a dangerous place to make the next throw. The great ones blend taking opportunities and making opportunities. With handlers, I think what separates the great ones, beyond just having great throws, is vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schwa&#39;s D-Handler</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</guid>
      <description>Great defensive handlers are typically people who are aggressive, able to see the field really well, and have a solid understanding of when it is appropriate to play transition offense. In my opinion, one of the most important parts of being a defensive handler is leading your team when you guys do get the D. This may be calling a play, running to the disc to transition, creating space for a teammate, or cutting to get the disc off the transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well-Rounded Deep Threats</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</guid>
      <description>In my experience, the toughest match-ups on receivers are against those players that are as big a threat going deep as they are coming under. Playing defense against a player like this, it is not obvious how you should play them. If you force them away, they&amp;rsquo;ll burn you deep and/or sky you for the score, but if you force them in, they&amp;rsquo;ll have a chance to use their throws to put the disc into the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Else Makes A Good Handler?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/what-else-makes-a-good-handler-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/what-else-makes-a-good-handler-/</guid>
      <description>Many players in Ultimate have good throws, but that does not necessarily mean that they are great handlers. The key to becoming a great handler is combining the mechanics of good throws and a versatile throwing repertoire with three big picture attributes: awareness, communication, and mind set/attitude.
The first characteristic of a great handler is awareness, or vision. The ability to evaluate the field at a moment&amp;rsquo;s notice is crucial for calling plays, or dictating what you want as a thrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change A Losing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</guid>
      <description>First and farmost, attitude is everything. If you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have 7 players who believe you can actually win, then this isnt worth reading and the rest of your game isn&amp;rsquo;t worth playing.
Most teams I have played on, in this situation, would try and load the Defensive line with the top defenders. However, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t just to stop the offense and gain possession, but to actually catch the disc in the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countering &amp; Changing Defenses</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</guid>
      <description>While I have not been personally very successful in this situation, other teams have been successful at times against my teams so I can tell you what it seems like they did. You must call tight lines—having players in the games that can create Ds and capitalize on them is imperative. Now is not the time to give players a chance to show their stuff for the first time—use people that are tried and true on D and O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute Your Changes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</guid>
      <description>If you are behind because the team has something you can&amp;rsquo;t handle (a few players or a defense) you are not behind, you are getting beaten. Change it up. Play a different D, run the counter play, even if you have to invent it. Maybe the risk means you go down 13-7 and later people whisper about how you got blown out. But if you can&amp;rsquo;t get the score to 11-9 or 12-10 so what?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One At A Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>One thing I remember an old teammate saying was that &amp;ldquo;there are no four- pointers in Ultimate.&amp;rdquo; What he meant was that you&amp;rsquo;re not going to bridge the gap in one play, so you have to stay with the gameplan and keep doing the things that your team needs to do to play their best.
The first key is to make sure that your offense is going to score every time they receive, because the worst thing for the team would be to add another break, which only lengthens the odds of a comeback while also being demoralizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short, Aggresive Risks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</guid>
      <description>As a coach, I feel it is necessary to take some risks defensively and call a few different defensive looks that may create enough confusion and lead to a quick turnover by the offense. If you have been playing man the entire game, try a little zone. If you have been forcing one way the entire time, try some middle or straight up. At that point, you must try something different to get the other team out of their comfort zone because clearly, they are comfortable right now in the driver&amp;rsquo;s seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful Attitudes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/successful-attitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/successful-attitudes/</guid>
      <description>The opportunity to be successful in the face of difficult odds is created long before you&amp;rsquo;ve been put in to that situation. It is an attitude that is built in practices, team meetings, and work-outs from the beginning of the season. The focus needs to be on what you and your team have control over in any given moment. Things that you do not have control over include the score of the game—those scores are now part of the past and we are unable to have any affect on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Scenarios For A 2nd Half Comeback</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</guid>
      <description>Scenario #1. Your opponent has a short roster. In the first half they got breaks early. But they are starting to look tired and predictable in their offense. You have identified their play-makers. Your D line has already generated some grueling points for their O line. Meanwhile your team has legs, intensity, they just can&amp;rsquo;t cash in with breaks. In this scenario I&amp;rsquo;d turn up the defensive intensity with a straight up mark, specific match ups, and hard physical D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An In-Cut Adjustment Illustrated</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember ever thinking &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a layout block&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I need to be in a position to get a layout block on this throw.&amp;rdquo; My goal was simply to be in the best position I could be in to cover the person who was my responsibility at the time. I believe that layout blocks are simply &amp;lsquo;opportunities taken&amp;rsquo;—being in the right place at the right time, and the offense made just enough of a mistake for you to go get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baiting</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</guid>
      <description>This is a skill that many of the top defenders possess which generates lots of lay out blocks. There are 3 key components to a successful baited block.
1. Knowing the offense (thrower/cutter)
To many, this is just knowing how far away you can let your player get before you can&amp;rsquo;t make up the ground in time to get a bid on the pass. Knowing how much ground you can make up on your player when the disc goes up is the most important part to knowing the offense; if you can&amp;rsquo;t regain the ground when the disc is thrown, you surely won&amp;rsquo;t get the block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bide Your Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</guid>
      <description>D, they say, is for dummies. But no D player worth their salt should have the ability to do anything more than stare at their big toe Saturday night at the hotel. Why? Because they should be too mentally taxed from keeping the stall count each time they step on the field for D. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about counting the stall when marking your assignment; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about keeping the stall when playing D in the stack or spread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</guid>
      <description>The skill I&amp;rsquo;ve used most and tried to teach my players more than any other part of getting a layout block (aside from the obvious WANTING IT BAD part) is the footwork required to get a layout block. The obvious problem about getting a layout D is that you are trying to get to something that is being blocked by your offense&amp;rsquo;s body. I think getting a layout D without getting called for a foul/hurting anyone is huge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get A Layout Block</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/how-to-get-a-layout-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/how-to-get-a-layout-block/</guid>
      <description>In the perfect defensive scenario, no one ever has to get a layout block. The marker does a great job of taking away part of the field and preventing hucks. Lane cutter defenders deny any open space to downfield receivers and when the count is getting higher, the dump defender stuffs the reset option. The thrower is left with nothing and quietly puts down the disc after hearing the word ten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition &amp; Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</guid>
      <description>Two key factors of getting a block are:
Being able to recognize mistakes by the offense Being in a good position to capitalize upon them Being faster than the person you&amp;rsquo;re guarding helps, but paying attention to these two aspects will help your team defensively.
When it comes to positioning, as a defender I rarely bait throws in anticipation of a layout block, especially when it comes to cuts that are close to the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Glory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</guid>
      <description>Ah the layout block, the play that got you started, the one you still dream about, the slam dunk of our game. Or maybe the three-pointer.
On a bad throw everyone can get what looks like a good block. That&amp;rsquo;s why you play summer league. But when teams are executing well, coming up with a piece is tough. Don&amp;rsquo;t over-commit to laying out or you will end up getting burned on jukes and lying on the ground as the person you are supposed to cover has a free throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Grail Of This Sport</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</guid>
      <description>Like all things holy, the more you try to explain it with words, the farther you get from its essence&amp;hellip;
Look: If you are on the field and thinking about getting a layout block, you&amp;rsquo;re likely not playing good defense. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is a recipe for getting a layout block . I suppose you could practice, and I have seen people working on their diving and landing techniques. But it also requires a tremendous amount of luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value Of A Layout Block?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m frequently torn between the value of a layout block versus just shutting your guy down to the point that he&amp;rsquo;s not thrown to. Layout blocks, at least at the elite level, are typically the result of a bad decision or throw by the thrower, because it is very tough to get around elite receivers, and you&amp;rsquo;re generally just not going to make up enough ground to go from a guy being open to you blocking him unless the throw is in a bad spot or the receiver does a terrible job of sealing you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Slow-Developing Chess Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</guid>
      <description>Zone O is like a game of chess- you spend a while moving your pieces around the board, not making much apparent headway, trying to find the weakness in the other team&amp;rsquo;s defense, and then suddenly you see your opportunity to capture their queen and it&amp;rsquo;s off to the races! Zone O also often showcases the triumph of craftiness over athleticism. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be faster or taller or quicker than the other team- you just need to be skilled with the disc, disciplined, and know how to take advantage of the opportunities that present themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments &amp; Positioning</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</guid>
      <description>The easiest way to simulate bad-weather conditions in a drill or a game is to simply tell your players to not throw the throws you can&amp;rsquo;t realistically complete in those conditions. The idea is to gain confidence in beating a zone with flat, crisp, high percentage throws. And if for some reason they decide to throw a cross-field hammer, or 10 yard push pass, stop the drill and reset, or just call it a turnover and continue playing from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Practice For Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</guid>
      <description>Zone offense is very difficult to simulate in practice. The skills necessary for zone are often quite different than for man (offense and defense). For zone O, you need to practice vision, patience and confidence which are quite difficult to simulate. For the most part, we usually teach zone O by drawing it up on a white board, going over it on the field and then doing LOTS of 5/10-pulls sometimes stopping the point to reposition people, especially in the early parts of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Fundamentals Of Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll write here about the fundamentals of good zone O. These will, I hope, reveal some underlying principles that any team can apply to its specific strategy/terminology, and to specific situations (e.g., how to deal with a sideline trip). I&amp;rsquo;ll rely on my co-contributors to address those specifics in detail, and read with interest!
So, getting down to basics&amp;hellip;
To figure out how our zone offense should work, we should think about what makes good zone defense successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepping For A 4-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>A zone defense is usually designed to only give the offense options that do not play to their strengths (i.e. working it laterally, taking away speed, or breaking the mark into the wind). I have been on women&amp;rsquo;s teams before that have had a very difficult time with the four person cup in a moderately windy (cross wind) situation. Typically, the defense would trap the downwind sideline making it difficult for the thrower to break the cup not only because there are four big defensive players near them, but also because there is a wind in their face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions About Your Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of ways to try to approximate the weather approximations that a zone offense will face. Some of these strengthen the defense such as adding an 8th player to the d or shortening the stall count while others might hamper the offense no overheads or huck limits.
There is really no good way to approximate inclement weather for the offense, but at some point you can handcuff the offense enough that when they face a weather situation with standard playing conditions they will feel that things are easy, and really that is the goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Condor Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>Up through the 90s, teams played a mix of two- and three-handler sets, but all zone offenses emphasized swinging the disc and attacking the far side of the field against a zone on the run. Then, the Condors, led by handlers James Studarus, Steve Dugan and Taro Ramberg began to run something fundamentally different. This was a two-handler set that didn&amp;rsquo;t swing and attacked a stagnant zone. Their philosophy was that no matter how many defenders you pulled in, you weren&amp;rsquo;t going to be able to stop two of them from throwing it back and forth to each other on little two to five yard passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</guid>
      <description>For most zones, the vulnerable spot is ten yards behind the cup (or front wall). To get there you can go through the cup, over the cup, or around the cup. Through and over involve risk. Around requires patience and planned cuts. Ideally after the swing, before the cup is reset, the handler has two cutters available for the next throw, one a continuation to the line and the other a throw to the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Points</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</guid>
      <description>Three points about zone offense that are usually true:
Your poppers have to identify the zone they are playing against and adjust their positioning/movement accordingly. Handlers must do the same and adjust their throws.
Keep moving. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for deeps and wings to start standing and watching. Even if your zone offense calls for you as the deep O threat to go to the back of the endzone, move around there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wings &amp; Poppers</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</guid>
      <description>My college team always seemed to be able to only field 5 good zone offense players. The last two players on the line were usually assigned to play the wing position—that is, the popper responsible for making cuts to the sideline when the handlers swung the disc around. As a result, I never really appreciated how important the wing position is to an effective zone offense until I started playing club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretically Helpful Exercise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t really answer these questions. The right answers depend on too many factors, many of which can only be judged during your game. Variables such as individual&amp;rsquo;s athleticism, defensive abilities, your opponent&amp;rsquo;s strengths, current conditions, number of defenders available, ect, are all part of the equation.
Having an answer to these questions is hard, but judging the quality of your answer is even harder. At best it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly difficult to evaluate results based on your coaching input alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Your Defenders A Chance</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/give-your-defenders-a-chance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/give-your-defenders-a-chance/</guid>
      <description>Just as with an offensive squad, each player on the defensive line has a few areas that he or she excels at. Some may be good at running down the long, streaking cuts, while other will be good at then tight, close-to-the-disc cuts. There may be another who has a very active mark that comes up with more point blocks than anyone else. And just as the offense trains players to fill certain roles, so should the defense train players to stop certain roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations To Matchup Theory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</guid>
      <description>Defensive matchups can be a positive aspect of successfully implementing a defensive strategy, but they can also serve to be a limitation. There are certain instances where a defender just has another players number and as a team you would be foolish to not consider that, but if you let certain matchups become the focus of the defensive strategy it may prevent you from running the defenses that are most successful for the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matching Up With Defensive Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/matching-up-with-defensive-characteristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/matching-up-with-defensive-characteristics/</guid>
      <description>I have a fairly low tolerance for good defenders getting beat. On the other hand, I&amp;rsquo;m always telling my girls (until I&amp;rsquo;m blue in the face) that the offensive player always has an advantage because she always know where she&amp;rsquo;s going to cut, and the defensive player is always a step behind. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m always going to put my best defender on the other team&amp;rsquo;s best offensive threat, unless there&amp;rsquo;s a reason that I don&amp;rsquo;t want that matchup—be it height, or speed, or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Defensive Assets</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</guid>
      <description>Know your foe.
There are lots of ways you can get the most out of your defensive matchups and it starts with not only knowing your own players but also knowing your opponents. The more familiar you are with the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offensive weapons ahead of time, the better you can prepare to counter them quickly and effectively. Furthermore, as important as it is to recognize primary play makers, it&amp;rsquo;s just as important to know how the rest of your roster compares overall to the other team&amp;rsquo;s personnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Impact</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</guid>
      <description>Lets step away from Ultimate, and assume you are playing a card game in which there are five random cards face up on the table and you will get dealt five cards randomly; your job is to pair each one of your cards up with one on the table. There are many ways of doing this (five to be exact!).
Example
Presented on the table: 7 J 3 9 K</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May The Best Man Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</guid>
      <description>I have an image, indelible perhaps, of UCSC&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Hagar and ECU&amp;rsquo;s Nat Taylor standing before each other after their battle at College Nationals in 1993 [not sure but this game may have decided semis]. Each was covered in grass stains, dirt, sweat, and knowing Hager probably some blood and a new scar. Standing their considering the other, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell who won, except the Slugs had more points.
For the many of us who have played at the top level, and for the many that will one day get there, we know that playing through a Section and a Region and later a National is not unlike getting through each round of a fortnight of tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>In a person defense, getting the right matchups can be critically important. It can also require some trial and error. Teams which face each other all the time get to try out a number of different approaches until they get most comfortable. Teams that don&amp;rsquo;t see each other often have a challenge at the start—but fortunately both teams have that challenge. The team that figures out how to neutralize (or at least slow down) the key threat from the other team the fastest can get an advantage early in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-Legged Stool</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</guid>
      <description>Think of the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offense as a three-legged stool. You want to knock it over. Do you kick the sturdiest leg? No, that&amp;rsquo;d be silly. Kick the weak leg.
Look, marquee players are going to get theirs. You can put your best defender on them, rotate defenders, do what you want; they are still going to get open, still get the disc and still make throws. But we all know Ultimate isn&amp;rsquo;t a one person game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Rotate Or Not To Rotate?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</guid>
      <description>To rotate or not to rotate? That is the question. Well, that depends on what type of game we are talking about. If we are talking about semis at Nationals, and I have a great downfield defender and the other team has a great downfield offensive player, then my defender is going to be on that offensive player for as long as they are effective. If this is pool play at Nationals, than I feel like it is somewhat necessary to share the load for fear that you may wear out your best defensive player during Day One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Should Guard Their Best Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</guid>
      <description>Let me answer this question with a question. When was the last time your best cutter defender spent a scrimmage covering your best handler? How about the other way around? Sure, your best on the ball defender talks all the time about hounding the region&amp;rsquo;s best handler, and your best athlete wants to stop the receiver all others fear, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a game hoping (or just hoping) your top players match up well against their top players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack Both Sidelines</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/attack-both-sidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/attack-both-sidelines/</guid>
      <description>Offenses used to look to get the disc near the sideline and then attack from there. Teams didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be right on the sideline—with a foot on the edge hoping to attack from there, but a vertical stack offense looks to move the disc to ~5-10 yards from one sideline, take a good long look up field and then swing it around and try the other sideline. This offense can still be effective and all teams should have the ability to use this, even as simply a change of pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depends On The Offensive System</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/depends-on-the-offensive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/depends-on-the-offensive-system/</guid>
      <description>The value of the sideline space depends on the offense. In a horizontal offense, the sideline limits your options. In a vertical offense, it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to be—until it isn&amp;rsquo;t.
Horizontal
From a downfield cutter&amp;rsquo;s perspective, one unique benefit of the horizontal offense is that it lets you make cuts across the mark. With so much uncrowded horizontal space between the cutters and the thrower, you can threaten an open-side cut, then change direction to receive a breakmark pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drilling For The Sideline Trap</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/drilling-for-the-sideline-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/drilling-for-the-sideline-trap/</guid>
      <description>An organized approach to sideline situations gives the offense a great advantage. For example: a well-isolated huck down the line or a series of swings to the breakside. Unprepared and against a good defense, a team facing a sideline trap will likely turn the disc over. I would challenge any team to spend more time practicing from the sideline. Most teams have only one play for the sideline, and many for a centered disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Spacing &amp; Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/field-spacing-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/field-spacing-offense/</guid>
      <description>Field spacing depends on the offense your team is running. This is dictated in part by the defensive strengths of the team you are playing and in part by your own team&amp;rsquo;s strengths.
In the mid-to-late 1990&amp;rsquo;s, the offense of choice for us (Furious) was the vertical stack. In the vertical O, the idea is to move the disc to one sideline or the other and flood the stack to the other side of the field, thus isolating a cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Room For Error</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/no-room-for-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/no-room-for-error/</guid>
      <description>Typically, our offense thinks of the sideline as a trap if we are being forced to that sideline. Given the right thrower, it could be a land of opportunity as it is much easier to destroy a defense with one break throw from the trap sideline. But, given that there are few throwers that skilled on a team, as a whole, the sideline is viewed as a trap.
The sideline is a trap because it gives throwers who do not consistently break the mark a very small window to work with when throwing to an in-cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraphrasing Parinella &amp; Zaslow</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/paraphrasing-parinella-zaslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/paraphrasing-parinella-zaslow/</guid>
      <description>Moving the disc does one of three things:
Gains ground (i.e. attacks) Moves you to a better place from which to attack Maintains possession Because there is less room, the sideline can often be a harder place from which to do 2 and 3. But if you can make space for your teammates, it can also be an ideal place from which to attack.
As always, personnel and approach determines much of what you do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extra Defender</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/the-extra-defender/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/the-extra-defender/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always viewed the sideline as an extra defender that can be utilized by the defense to gain an advantage, especially in a vertical stack offense. As the disc moves to the sideline, the thrower and cutters have less viable space to work with, which restricts them to two kinds of viable cuts; a deep cut and an under cut. For a defender, shutting down these two sideline options simplifies the task that is presented when the disc is in the middle; a deep cut, an under cut, and a break mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Lane Theory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/three-lane-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/three-lane-theory/</guid>
      <description>I tend to think of the Ultimate field in three lanes running down the field. When the disc is in one of the side lanes, you really only have that lane and the middle lane available, as throws to the far lane are quite risky. Sometimes focusing on just two lanes can mean that you reduce the complexity for the thrower and the offense, and it limits the angles that poachers can come from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yardage Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/yardage-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/yardage-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>The sideline is a great space to look to gain yardage. If your dump can beat his defender up the line, it should be a relatively easy pass to space in front of him, and he can then potentially hit a deep throw. This is probably the best way to get off a high percentage huck (and doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to happen on the sideline). It&amp;rsquo;s easy for the downfield cutters to time a deep cut when they see this up-line cut developing, and the thrower can use his momentum to get off a big throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build From Versatile, Athletic Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</guid>
      <description>Not everyone can be great at everything and some become very good at a few things. There are times where we have a few players who are very, very good at a particular position - whether defensive or offensive. For example, I have been on teams where we have a few players who sole purpose in life is to give the handlers on the other team h***. That is their job, and is why they are on the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Hope For The Specialist?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</guid>
      <description>I started playing for Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Sockeye in the Spring of 2007. Among the great athletes and throwers and minds one thing stood out the most—an almost singular obsession on beating their main rival, Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s Furious George. Throwers needed to have five options because at nationals, against Furious, you could be sure four would not be open. Three-step separations were not enough, because Oscar and Alex could make it one. Running trap zone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needs Of The Team And The Individual</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</guid>
      <description>Role players are valuable to any successful team. More than valuable, they may be essential. This is typically because they have the ability to throw their whole effort into a part of the game that the stars don&amp;rsquo;t have the effort for. An obvious example of this is a marker in the zone. Marking takes a lot of effort, and is very tiring both because of chasing the disc around, but also because working hard on the mark takes a lot of energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles Can Be Difficult To Observe</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</guid>
      <description>Apart from specific match-ups on defense that require certain roles (being tall and fast, or short and quick), there are lots of roles in zone defenses and in some offensive sets. The best example I can think of is the marker on a trap-side zone defense. This is the position that anchors the zone when it is within 5 yards of the sideline, and can make or break the scheme. This person has the opportunity to take away more options that any other defensive player on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles From Necessity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting topic as the need for specialized roles has been born more out of necessity than out of desire in Vancouver.
Historically, the top players on Furious have been the players who excel at multiple aspects of the game. These players have been able to fulfill multiple roles, and truly have a very strong all-around game. Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s fast pace of play combined with multiple turnovers and unforeseen situations, calls for players on the field to be able to adapt and excel regardless of the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use All Of Your Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</guid>
      <description>I believe that what makes a team successful is its ability to use all of its players. Most good teams have a few superstars- those players that are game- changers and whose absence can really hurt the team&amp;rsquo;s chances. However, the difference between good teams and great teams, I believe, lies in how the team utilizes its role players. Ultimate is truly a team sport, and if the top players on a team aren&amp;rsquo;t supported by a solid and confident group of role players, the team will have many exploitable weaknesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Best Part Of Each Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</guid>
      <description>The best example of a role player on Riot is Michelle Bowlen. Michelle is very tall (5&#39;11&amp;quot;), well-trained in fundamentals and particularly smart (Fulbright Scholar!). She doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best break-mark throws in the game and can&amp;rsquo;t guard every quick little handler. However, she is the scariest mark I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in a 1-3-3. Luckily, we play in bad weather conditions at Sectionals, Regionals and Nationals (usually) so we can run a lot of zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is A Role Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen certain players take over games, throwing hucks, getting lay out Ds, or getting open against good defenders. These players are revered. What is a role player? Everyone else.
I avoid using the term &amp;ldquo;role player&amp;rdquo; because it implies a value judgment on those players who don&amp;rsquo;t get the glory. The player who throws hucks isn&amp;rsquo;t a role player. The player who uses his mark to stop the hucks is a role player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Beating&#34; The Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</guid>
      <description>When most players think about breaking the mark, they envision a thrower throwing around or over a stationary mark. However, I&amp;rsquo;d argue that the majority of break throws in high level ultimate don&amp;rsquo;t happen this way. Most breaks I see are simple forehands and backhands thrown in motion with the mark trailing behind the thrower.
You can be a great at switching fields with the Frisbee and have terrible &amp;ldquo;break throws&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allowing Mistakes, Deceiving Marks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</guid>
      <description>What is your favorite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; for breaking the mark? How do you do it, and in what situations do you find it most useful?
To break the mark, I typically like to convince, or deceive, the mark that I am going to throw a different throw than what I want.
For example, if I am being forced flick and I want to throw the around backhand break, I will get into a very threatening inside out forehand flick position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Easier Way</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the easiest way to break the mark is just to let someone else do it. I mean, break throws are hard. Do I really want to go to the trouble of pivoting all over the place, faking out the mark, getting off a potentially risky throw&amp;hellip; and then perhaps get hacked by the mark for my efforts? Forget it. I just don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of hassle.
Not everyone can break the mark at will, and even for those who have great break throws, it can still be a somewhat risky pass at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Fake Make Be A Viable Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</guid>
      <description>The best piece of advice I ever received about breaking the mark is that every fake must be a viable throw. You need to create space in order to break the mark; strong fakes are going to make that happen. Many defenders choose to watch only the disc when they are marking (don&amp;rsquo;t do that, defenders!) and therefore they are reacting to your fakes. By making realistic fakes, with the disc and your upper body movement, you will get your defender to shift their weight and be off-balance for a moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From The 2000 UPA Finals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</guid>
      <description>2000 Open Finals: Condors vs Furious George. It&amp;rsquo;s four even. Mike Grant [of FG] is defended by Corey Sanford. Mike runs a sort of S-cut in the end zone. Jeff Cruicshank with the disc. He seems to look break mark for a righty backhand, then he pivots big for his lefty inside out backhand, throws a quick, strong fake, and then he throws the inside out backhand to Grant. The throw is right in the sweet spot, safely away from Corey&amp;rsquo;s extended hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Breaking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite fakes is really quite quick (maybe a quarter of a second of motion), and from the waist up looks exactly like I am going to move my pivot foot for an around break, but I immediately step out for an inside break. My head and torso kind of lunge to one side, and I move the disc quite quickly in the same direction, but my lower body remains stationary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan Ahead</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/plan-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/plan-ahead/</guid>
      <description>By far the most effective &amp;ldquo;move&amp;rdquo; for breaking the mark that I&amp;rsquo;ve found is one that is rarely (but with increasing frequency) used in the women&amp;rsquo;s game. The general idea is that you throw a backhand over the mark&amp;rsquo;s shoulder (while being forced backhand) to the I/O lane, while using the step forward to throw as your first step running for the give-go.
Specifically, I try to throw in the space above the mark&amp;rsquo;s shoulder (not too near their face), and I throw down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Consistently</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</guid>
      <description>What I like to do is to not let the mark dictate the throw, but for the thrower to dictate the markers positioning and movements. In doing so, I find teaching young players to break the mark that you must first teach them to make themselves a threat while holding the disc. I consider the way I hold the disc similar to what is called a triple threat in basketball. To me, this means holding the disc in a throwing position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal Is To Make It Easy To Score</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</guid>
      <description>Every time a team moves the disc, this changes the defense. It puts the defensive players out of position, if even for a short period of time. The greater change is better for the offense, and this means putting the disc as far from where the defense wants it to be as possible. If a team is forcing you to throw forehand, and you get a chance to complete a pass straight up field, you just made a good move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shimmy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</guid>
      <description>My favorite move, that is very popular and can be used by any player, is the shimmy flick. This is a move that I was taught at Carleton but is based on principles that I learned in my first sport, basketball. In basketball as a defender, you are always taught to look at the offense&amp;rsquo;s belly-button because that is the hardest part of the body to fake with. You can get faked out if you look at the ball, the player&amp;rsquo;s head, feet or hands, but the belly button&amp;rsquo;s not going anywhere unless the whole player is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Your Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</guid>
      <description>Breaking the mark is key to scoring against solid defense and an important factor to any offense. Here are 5 ways to dictate play and gain an advantage over your mark:
1. Expanding your options early (become more threatening)
Since at the beginning of the game the defense is trying to figure out your strengths and weaknesses to properly apply pressure, this is your opportunity to take advantage and become more threatening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Never Have To Break The Mark If...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</guid>
      <description>There are some basic concepts that everyone talks about to effectively break the mark:
use your core to stay balanced while you fake and pivot to get your marker off balance; learn to fake and throw/release at different heights; engage your marker by drawing them closer or moving them side-to-side with your pivots. However, my favourite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; to teach, regardless of playing level, is how to redefine your throwing lanes when you have the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Theory &amp; A Lot Of Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</guid>
      <description>It can be easy to make excuses for not playing team defense in Mixed Ultimate, especially in man-to-man set-ups. About half the people on the field you would never choose to mark up on/cover prior to the pull, the people you want to set up switches with may not be the closest people to you, and the person in the best position to help you might not be the obvious choice given the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Example: Defending The Dump</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had some success teaching team D in the past, and I like to think that young players, especially bright ones, will often surprise you with their ability to learn complex concepts and make them work against very good offensive players and teams.
One example of our team-D philosophy is in how we taught dump D at U of Oregon. This would usually happen at some point during February or March, after the basics of defense and offense but before the real tournament schedule got up to speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication &amp; Vision</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</guid>
      <description>I think there are two skills that can take a player from a good defender to a great defender and they both have to do with the transition from an individually good defender to a good team defender.
1. Communication. Silent defenders will never be great defenders. This includes &amp;ldquo;up,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;switch&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;last back&amp;rdquo; calls. This is particularly important in zone defense for wings and deeps. To practice this, I sometimes require players to be saying something continuously during a defensive drill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Screw The Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</guid>
      <description>Team defense begins with an understanding and analysis of the strengths and weaknesses of your team&amp;rsquo;s defensive talents, followed by the development of defensive philosophies that are executed by specific team-oriented strategy. Too often, &amp;ldquo;team defense&amp;rdquo; is taught in terms of situational defensive sets such as zone, clam, poaching, and whatnot with an over-reliance on individual athleticism to play man-D. While high-flying layout blocks are at times warranted and necessary, it appears the spectacular has come to define a team&amp;rsquo;s defensive prowess along with foot-races and gravity-defying leaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Specific Calls To Your D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</guid>
      <description>Rich &amp;ldquo;Farmer&amp;rdquo; Hollingsworth once said that when a team is on offense, seven people is too many (a crowd), but when a team is on defense, seven isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Communication is the extra player, and it&amp;rsquo;s the key to successful team defense. For team defense, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there is a more important skill or a more simple one. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to develop and I have always found it to be really difficult to teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limit Handler Play, &amp; The Caterpillar Drill</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/limit-handler-play-the-caterpillar-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/limit-handler-play-the-caterpillar-drill/</guid>
      <description>Team defense starts when you can make solid assumptions about what your teammates will and will not allow. A good team defense limits the offense&amp;rsquo;s options to looks that the D is prepared for, and then pounces when the O predictably does what you set them up for. Basically, you can&amp;rsquo;t play team defense if you are purely reactive to the offense—you have to have a general goal for how you are going to manufacture turnovers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Space For Real Time Results</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</guid>
      <description>At the college level, the dividing line between teams that can generate a break or two, and the teams that consistently go on a run of breaks can be attributed to the concept of team defense.
My experience in trying to introduce this concept to new, or inexperienced, players is to break things down to the absolute basics. Initially, during our first chalktalk regarding the defense I like to introduce the name of the D (something catchy, without lending too much information to opponents who might hear it on the sideline), and the main objectives of the defense (forcing lots of short passes, forcing inside out strikes, forcing long, low percentage throws).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-By-Step Approach At Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</guid>
      <description>Understanding that each player is an integral part in the defensive machine precludes all other aspects of defense. Getting everyone on the same page is of utmost importance as 6 players playing together and fulfilling their responsibilities does not equate to a block. So, this is the initial step in teaching team defense.
From here, it is a matter of understanding the defense we are running (zone, man, clam, junk, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisiveness Leads To Glory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/decisiveness-leads-to-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/decisiveness-leads-to-glory/</guid>
      <description>Goal line cutting starts with decisiveness and ends in glory—either for your or your teammates.
When your team moves into its red zone offense, begin by moving quickly into position. Your speed getting into position will determine whether they are going to stay with you or leave you and poach the lane. When you sprint to your attack point, your defender will instinctively feel like you are a threat and attempt to stay with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Defensive Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/exploiting-defensive-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/exploiting-defensive-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>When you transition from open field cutting to goal-line cutting, two major things change: (1) you are no longer a deep threat, and (2) a throw that gains only a few yards can be very advantageous. Both of these factors change how the defense will play you. For instance, many defenders will get closer to you, get physical, and perhaps force you away from the thrower with their body position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Quadrants</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/field-quadrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/field-quadrants/</guid>
      <description>Really, long points are earned at practice and at the track, well before the specific moment arrives on a Sunday afternoon.
It&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to think about being a successful endzone cutter as a personal achievement. More than any other position on the field, having the disc near the goal line requires a full team effort to create a good scoring chance. Stack discipline and spacing are crucial to avoiding clogged lanes and disruptive picks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Thrower, Make It Easy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about cutting in the endzone, the first thing to consider is if you even should cut. You have to assess where the space is and the convenience of your angle to that space. You need to know who your thrower is and what they are comfortable with (if you cut to where you intend to cut, will the thrower have the throw to hit you accurately enough for it to be a score?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Move</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m usually thinking, &amp;ldquo;Get open on the open side.&amp;rdquo;
When fatigue sets in, throws and finesse are the first thing to go and open side throws are generally easier. Cutters can push through fatigue with desire and brute strength. So, to get open on the open side, I usually start facing the thrower, juke hard toward the defender (they are on their heels), take a few steps really hard to the break side (this usually lures the off-balance defender to commit to the break side), then explode past them to the open side (this may require some stepping past/running through limbs of your defender).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Versus Efficient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</guid>
      <description>From an elementary basketball analogy (sorry readership to those that know a lot about basketball), if everyone is doing their job, the point guard is keeping the ball alive and getting it into the post when available for the forwards and center to finish off. Much like this, in open field, the handlers are keeping the disc alive and looking to get it to the cutters whenever available. To this end, the cutters are the primary workhorses during this phase of the offense by getting the big gains and opening up the downfield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Without Breaking A Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</guid>
      <description>The following is a couple of thoughts from a handler/team perspective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly what we asked our authors to write about (but we thought it appropriate to add in here). I first wrote this article in 2004, in response to this comment on rec.sport.disc:
&amp;gt; &amp;gt;scoring in the endzone is easy. just break the mark.
Yes, this will probably work most of the time. I think that the intrinsic difficulty in End Zone O is the pressure on the offense to score; the idea that &amp;ldquo;most of the time&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing Is Everything</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/timing-is-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/timing-is-everything/</guid>
      <description>Goal line cutting (especially in the elite division) is a difficult technique to master. The fact is, the closer you get to the endzone, the more effective a defensive player can be because you are shortening the field and removing the threat of a deep cut. In general, the offense always has the advantage, but close to the endzone, your advantage as a cutter is lessened.
All organized teams usually have a specific endzone offense that they default to when they get within ten yards or less of the goal line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Do When The Field Shrinks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</guid>
      <description>The field shrinks when you reach the endzone.
Your defender no longer has to worry about your deep cuts, and so can front you by a larger margin. The pressure builds- a turnover here in the &amp;ldquo;red zone&amp;rdquo; seems particularly disheartening. All of a sudden, everyone is cutting at once, forgetting about rules and technique, just anxious to get the disc and finish the point.
However, it is precisely here in the red zone that it becomes all the more important to remember your team&amp;rsquo;s strategies and offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downfield 1-On-1 Defense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re downfield, the disc has stopped, and you&amp;rsquo;re defending a cutter in the middle of a flat stack. You&amp;rsquo;ll need all the speed, agility, and strength you have—long before the point begins you can better your odds by improving your physical ability. Chances are if you are reading this you know how.
Although Ultimate is a team game, the flat stack does a good job at isolating one-on-one matchups. While switching and poaching can work against weaker offensive teams, intelligent ones will be able to change the position of both the disc and their cutters quicker than you can react, and will beat your defense without much effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Should Be Intentional</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/everything-should-be-intentional/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/everything-should-be-intentional/</guid>
      <description>If I was teaching a young player to learn to cut from the &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or iso&amp;rsquo;ed positions in the middle of a horizontal stack, I would emphasize a few keys points, which are generally applicable to getting open on a stopped disc within any offensive structure, but are particularly important for a horizontal offense. The points I make are assuming that the defense is not poaching, as cutting against a poaching defense would require a more in-depth discussion of how to run a horizontal offense in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Easy Steps</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/five-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/five-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>1st: Narrow the gap between you and your defender and engage him. If you get him on his heels then you can cut where ever you please.
2nd: Clear Out! It is much easier to cut from the side positions in the horizontal, as long as the middle is vacated. Make room for your teammates to get open.
3rd: Become a side cutter. Observe the field see who is going to get the disc, get your self out of the way and be aware of where your defender is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It All Comes Back To Throwing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</guid>
      <description>The most important piece to an effective initiation cut is the thrower. To get open, you need to be able to challenge the defender into at least two different places. In the typical flat-stack set, there are three spaces open to the interior cutters: open-side, break-side, and deep. If the thrower can hit all of those spots, getting open is no problem. Fake to one of them, cut to another. Throw, catch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sockeye&#39;s Wheelhouse</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/sockeye-s-wheelhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/sockeye-s-wheelhouse/</guid>
      <description>Cutting from the middle in a horizontal stack is a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, you have the freedom to cut in any direction, your defender is on an island with no deep help, and the offense is looking to you to make a play. Awesome.
On the other hand, the flat stack presents some unique challenges for cutters. I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on the unpredictability of the flat stack as a cutting problem, and explain a couple simple adjustments that address this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Keys To Being A Good Middle</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</guid>
      <description>I can think of three main points that will help you when you are trying to get open in the middle of a horizontal stack. The first is that your team needs to put the right type of player in that position. In my opinion, this is a player who is confident with the disc, is a threat as a deep thrower, and understands how to get open both going deep and coming under.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Offensive Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</guid>
      <description>As a defender this is one of the most uncomfortable positions to defend if the stack is well-spaced and with just the right depth to make both the deep cut and the underneath cut a viable option. If the disc is in the middle of the field (say at the brickmark), and your cutter is on the open side of the horizontal stack, there is a lot of space to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use On-Field Cues</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</guid>
      <description>Cutting from the middle of the flat stack requires good field sense. In my mind, good field sense involves the ability to accurately read three things simultaneously: reading the defense, reading the thrower, and reading the spaces on the field.
I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone has heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;take what the defense gives you.&amp;rdquo; This important concept necessitates knowing what your defender is trying to take away at any given moment. At its most basic level, you have to recognize the force and figure out which direction your D is trying to push your cut (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice For Improvement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I am writing in about this topic not because I am a great distance thrower. In fact I am quite the opposite. Throwing the disc was something that I did with much trepidation for many years. In fact I was ridiculed constantly by my teammates for not being able to throw a simple backhand (which is why my scoober is a decent throw for me now).
However, over the years I have improved in this area and I do have some advice to pass along to others who struggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Every Huck</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</guid>
      <description>I think a lot of people focus too much on how to throw the disc far rather than on how to complete their hucks. A lot of time, players will spend hours practicing throwing the disc really far, but then they don&amp;rsquo;t make disciplined decisions during a game about when to use those hucks. There are three questions to ask yourself before unleashing any bomb if you want to increase the chances of completing that huck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face A Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/face-a-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/face-a-mark/</guid>
      <description>The most important part of throwing for distance is learning to do so while facing a mark. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for many players to throw 40+ yards unmarked, but when someone&amp;rsquo;s standing in front of you, it becomes much more difficult.
Begin your backhand motion with your hips and follow through with your shoulder and arm. I&amp;rsquo;m a proponent of bringing the disc straight from the wind- up point to the release point, as opposed to a more arced path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Chris Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</guid>
      <description>You need Chris Page. Chris who? Remember back when Sockeye was good the first time? Back in the 90s and you watched those epic battles on NBC? Dreaming of how it was gonna be you? Sockeye-Double Happiness? Sockeye-Rhino? All those heart-breakers against DoG? Remember that shaggy headed blonde kid ripping it forehand, backhand, marked, didn&amp;rsquo;t matter? That was Chris Page.
When I hit the big time in 96, I had some power, but no control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Backhands</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</guid>
      <description>I am going to focus on a long backhand because that is my best long throw, but I think that a lot of the principles hold for long forehands and pulls as well.
I&amp;rsquo;m all about maximizing torque when throwing—using rotation to generate power flowing into your throw. On a long backhand the first point is to step out so that when you twist your body you&amp;rsquo;re not killing your defender with a giant elbow to the face (this is easier for tall players—shorter players should focus on a quick stepout).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2¢ On Hucking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</guid>
      <description>When I think about throwing long, it helps me to visualize a spring in action. I try to activate four parts of my body that act as springs: legs, hips, shoulders, elbow, and wrist. As I wind up for the throw, I think about compressing these springs in turn and as I throw, I think about releasing each of the springs. The legs are an important part of the step; I step out as far as I can to still feel completely balanced throughout the throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secrets For Throwing Farther</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-secrets-for-throwing-farther/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-secrets-for-throwing-farther/</guid>
      <description>How to throw farther.
A good question. To start I will say this. Some people do not have the physical ability to throw as far as others. Strength, body type, and other factors are the reason behind this. However, there are ways to throw further no matter how far you can throw it now.
TECHNIQUES
The best throwers in the game and their ability to throw the disc further than others is based on a few techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Body Mechanics Early</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/strong-body-mechanics-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/strong-body-mechanics-early/</guid>
      <description>Hailing from Paideia I probably started throwing a frisbee earlier than most. In 4th grade I was learning push passes, thumbers, and scoobers from Coach Baccarini in addition to the more conventional flicks, backhands, and hammers. As soon as I picked up a disc I wanted to know how I could throw farther, faster, and better. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until my senior year in high school that I was able to figure out how to throw deep with consistency from both the backhand and forehand side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Checklist</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is probably the least rewarding aspect of Ultimate. Not only will you rarely be recognized for good sub-calling, but instead sub-calling is the easiest thing for many people to blame for problems on the field. Additionally, problems (real or perceived) with playing time and sub-calling are often the number one issue affecting team dynamics and player satisfaction. In my experience, the easiest way to avoid issues with subcalling is to have a plan ahead of time and to communicate as best as possible to individuals where their role fits into that plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Careful What You Wish For</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Be careful what you wish for.&amp;rdquo;
— Ken Dobyns over the phone, NYC to Hampton Bays, August 1995.
Calling the D line that season isn&amp;rsquo;t something I necessarily wished for, but blindly accepted the vacancy; possibly a dumb move for a not proved new face on a second year team still fielding much of the leftover NYNY dynasty. We beat Boston four times that season: Regionals, Tune-up, and two small pre- season tourneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elocution &amp; Enunciation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/elocution-enunciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/elocution-enunciation/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than calling a line a finding an uninvited guest has wandered onto the field. Not only do you have to recall the correct name, but you have to break the news to the overzealous player and watch them slink off sadly like Charlie Brown after failing to kick that football. Rats.
To avoid this situation you must speak with the uttermost clarity and amplification. You mustn&amp;rsquo;t slur your speech; too often names like Sean and John or Brett and Bren become confused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering The Team With Self Subbing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been very fortunate in my career to play on many successful teams that did not call subs, and this hypothetical situation could be a blessing in disguise. Most players at elite levels are fairly self-aware, and after a season of playing together most can recognize the hierarchy within the team and could make an honest appraisal of their optimum contribution to the team in terms of quantity and type (O or D) of points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Your Team, Not Your Teammates</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling, especially for one who one who plays at the same time, is one of the most difficult things to do. Personally, I hate doing it because I feel like it distracts me from my ability to remain focused while playing. But like everyone, I always have my own feelings about who should be playing at a particular time. Fortunately, as captain of my team, my opinion about who plays carries a bit of weight with the sub-caller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sub-Calling Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>1. If you pick the right personnel, there will always be a time when you can play each player. Think about when these times are for each player on your team and allow them to excel in these situations.
2. Be clear to your teammates about the team&amp;rsquo;s sub-calling philosophy. If it changes for a tournament, don&amp;rsquo;t make it a hush hush operation—let everyone know so nothing is a surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>When I was calling subs, I also usually was calling the &amp;ldquo;strategy&amp;rdquo; for the points. (Are we playing zone? Are we setting horizontal? Is this point the most critical point ever?). That helped me when it came to determining players based on the roles needed. It also made me pretty tired by the end of the day. How these decisions are made on your team will help dictate who should call subs when the sub-caller goes down with a freak throat injury (Larynxeum andibenitis).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</guid>
      <description>First things first—calling subs for a competitive team is a big job. It will take a lot away from anyone&amp;rsquo;s playing ability. There may be someone out there who can play at their best and call subs at the same time, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t met them. Because of this, I think it&amp;rsquo;s better to split sub-calling duties between two or three players, or expect that the person calling subs is not going to play very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Your Team For The Hard Decisions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/prepare-your-team-for-the-hard-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/prepare-your-team-for-the-hard-decisions/</guid>
      <description>It is a big point midway through a big game at the most important high school elite open tourney of the year. The opposing team has taken a timeout between points. You look at the team you coach to figure out what line you want in the game. You know that a number of your kids haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the game yet and that they paid a lot of money to make the plane trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Sub-Caller Is...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple little tricks that can really help you out.
This first technique is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never done, but I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna name it. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it Repeater. I saw it first at College Nationals this year, where Syzygy was using it (they crushed us) and I later overheard teams using it at Solstice (Eugene) and HoDown (Calgary). Basically, your sub caller yells out the names just as usual and then everyone repeats them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pod System</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is one of the most difficult parts of being a team leader, be it as a coach or a player. As coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have employed several different strategies throughout the years depending on the team. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give young players some insight into one coach&amp;rsquo;s perspective of sub-calling.
My sub-calling strategy begins in the organization of my sub sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipation &amp; Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</guid>
      <description>I am a firm believer that anticipation and focus are the most important elements for successful catching. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to others to discuss the finer points of catching techniques.
For anticipation, not only do you want to anticipate where the disc is headed, but you have to prepare your body for an anticipated catch. Anticipating the disc&amp;rsquo;s path is basically reading the disc. You need to be able to judge accurately how fast the disc is traveling and along what trajectory so that you can meet it at the best point possible, which is usually the earliest point possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Positioning On The Comeback Cut</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</guid>
      <description>The best thing I ever heard of for improving your receiving skills is this game called &amp;ldquo;catch&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s no replacement for repetition. You just have to do it over and over until you forget what it&amp;rsquo;s like to drop a frisbee.
The next step is simulating game situations. Personally, I feel like the most valuable catch to be 100% on is the in-cut: running full speed toward a disc coming at you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull &amp; Transitions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</guid>
      <description>Catching The Pull
Mentally, catching the pull is often thought of as being a job that one can only mess up, but the flip side is to think of it as an opportunity for a team to jump start its offense. The seconds saved by catching the pull help to get the offense in motion before the defense can set. I think of three main steps when catching the pull:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate The Unforced Turnover</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</guid>
      <description>Catching technique and practice are often overlooked components of player development. Catching instructions generally begin and end with a demonstration of the pancake catch and calls to &amp;ldquo;use two hands,&amp;rdquo; with players left to their own devices to improve their catching through repetitions. As a coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have developed a more proactive approach to teaching catching.
The reason for this is that drops are unforced turnovers that are preventable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting An Extra Foot Of Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</guid>
      <description>I think that for me, the main catching technique that can be practiced (and that I have learned from coaches and taught to players) is attacking the discs with two hands, thumbs down claw-style. When I was in high school, my coach Michael Baccarini used to always say that any catch you can clap, you can catch at least a foot further in front of you if you reach out with your pinchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>Catching the disc is all about practice. If a situation comes up in a game, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much easier if you&amp;rsquo;ve done it a hundred times in practice than if it&amp;rsquo;s totally foreign to you. What that means is that you need to practice catching in game situations, not just easy, uncovered, and standing still. Practice catching the disc out in front of you, practice catching with a defender on your back, off-hand catches, in the wind, hammers, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making It Routine</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</guid>
      <description>In the sixth grade, I played YMCA basketball and was coached by my classmate/neighbor&amp;rsquo;s father. His sadistic assistant used to routinely fire passes at Billy Nesbitt&amp;rsquo;s head because Billy had such terrible hands; his poor hands caused his braces to cause his mouth to bleed. Sobbing, snot, and blood are not too fun to witness when you&amp;rsquo;re in sixth grade. I never wanted to be anything like poor Billy. I think he&amp;rsquo;s an orthodontist now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Ideas</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The fundamental catch most players at the elite level of the game is one where you are running hard back to the disc with a defender on your back pressing you to keep your maximum speed until after the reception. The basic component to catching this is the mentality of attacking the disc.
I have seen many players drop this by trying to finesse the Frisbee into their hands rather than aggressively securing it, whether with a &amp;ldquo;clap catch&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;tiger claw&amp;rdquo; technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regimented Catching Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</guid>
      <description>Just like throwing, catching comes from practice.
How often do you see someone throwing before a game focus really hard on the throw and not on the catch? You&amp;rsquo;ll hear this player swear and scream when they miss a throw, and then catch the throw that came back with one hand while joking with the person next to them.
On Z, we used to do the a throwing medley at the start of every practice and every game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Catching: Two Drills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</guid>
      <description>It is a common misperception that catching cannot be taught. Learning how to catch comes down to repetition and focus. Here are two quick drills for teaching new players to catch and for honing experienced players&amp;rsquo; skills.
The first drill (unnamed) involves two people and ten (or more) discs. The players (thrower and catcher) stand about two yards apart. The thrower tosses disc after disc to the catcher. The thrower should place the discs so that the catcher is forced to catch high, low, left, right, one- and two-handed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Couple Of Thoughts On Zone D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</guid>
      <description>A couple of quick thoughts.
Sidelines are great for communication, but the people that need to be able to talk to each other are all on the field already. In a standard three-person cup, the communication streams are simple:
Deep talks to wings and short-deep Short-deep talks to points and middle Middle talks to points Wings talk to their side&amp;rsquo;s point With these streams, each player can adjust the positioning of the players they are covering for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tweak To The 1-3-3</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-tweak-to-the-1-3-3/</guid>
      <description>With zone defenses, I tend to lean away from the old standards, reasoning that if most defenders know them, most offenses know how to play against them. Almost everyone has run a standard three-person cup, and every offense has seen one. In order to get a good offense out of its rhythm enough to generate turnovers, you need to either run a well-known zone better than other teams do, or you need to do something different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Zone Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</guid>
      <description>From your experience, what zone configuration do you feel most confident in?
In general I prefer a three man cup mainly because it can be used to disguise other types of defensive schemes teams may use, such as a zone to man. The specific setup I prefer for the three man cup is with the short deep playing very close to the cup, if not actually part of the cup, working as a unit to trap the disc on the sideline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments To The 2-3-2</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a favorite zone depends on a few factors, including the personnel on my team, the personnel on the other team, the direction and strength of the wind, and the things the other team are doing that are working. Every team should have two different zone looks in their arsenal, ideally with a well practiced ability to transition out of the zone into a person defense. Choosing a zone is another question though, so I&amp;rsquo;ll go with the classic—the 2-3-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redistribute Their Resources</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</guid>
      <description>I believe that it is impossible to design a zone (or any defense for that matter) that takes away everything. If I knew that zone I would never lose a game. I think the important thing about a zone is to make sure that everyone is clear of what the zone&amp;rsquo;s objectives are, and when they are forced to make a decision on the field, they do it within the context of that zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>For most of my teams (coaching and playing) we have been most comfortable in a 4-person cup recently. The goal with this zone is to prevent throws through the cup or around it with yardage gainers—we want to force the throws backward and we want to force a lot of them. I was taught to see this as a math problem—even the simplest throw will only be completed 99% of the time (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wham!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</guid>
      <description>2001 in Sarasota was crazy. Hurricane Michelle was causing major havoc for most of the Mixed division&amp;rsquo;s offenses. The wind started mild on Thursday and picked up through the week. One of my teammates on Trigger Hippy, Scott &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; Runkel (who played for Boston back when they were Big Brother, and, as far as I know, was the original &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; of the three that I know), along with Mike &amp;ldquo;the Wizard&amp;rdquo; Faris, came up with a zone to man to zone to man, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trap Hard &amp; Smart</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</guid>
      <description>A trap cup zone is a common and effective configuration in Mixed Ultimate. It looks to create pressure and mismatches at the disc. The handlers, who touch the disc most in zone offense, are depended upon by the rest of the team to be consistent and unflappable when working a zone D. An aggressive trap cup can serve to fluster and frustrate the handlers, whether it&amp;rsquo;s because they themselves are having trouble moving the disc or because others are having trouble getting them the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should We Contain?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</guid>
      <description>Zone Basics
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of a good trapping zone, but in unpredictable winds even a very conservative and basic zone would produce turns. There are way too many specifics and permutations to cover in this forum, but below are three principles of a trapping zone.
Basically, a trapping zone consists of three things. First, how are you going to allow the disc to move to a sideline. This is a combination of making it hard to move the disc in the middle, and making a lateral throw an easy pass without giving up too many yards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone Observations From The NYNY Days</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</guid>
      <description>Pike ran an imposing 1-3-3 for a number of years, a set that may or may not have morphed into a 4-man cup at times. Mike Jaeger (formerly of Michigan, currently of Sockeye) was great at the one spot.
The Warrior squad I played for in 2001 ran a 1-3-3 as well and that look got us to Nationals. Rhett Russ also the right man for the one spot. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the 1-3-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance &amp; Explosiveness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</guid>
      <description>I still remember being at Worlds in 1999 in Scotland and it was sort of the debut of Fortunat Mueller with Boston. He was a young workhorse at that time and DoG knew how to use him, as he was probably catching half their goals. I remember watching a pool play game of theirs and a more experienced player pointing out his footwork, how he was always on balance. While we had begun some very basic footwork drills, it was the first time I remember noticing someone&amp;rsquo;s footwork in a game situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>The player that has excellent footwork in my mind has a football and track background. He has great body positioning while cutting that I think leads to his strong footwork. His cuts are strong as a result of pushing his weight into the ground and exploding after getting low and chopping his feet. This helps his play because I believe he is able to get open on players that are bigger and stronger and faster than him by using good technical footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get On The Ladder!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</guid>
      <description>A big part of footwork is quickness, and the best tool I know of to improve quickness is a speed ladder. I would highly recommend getting one—the longer the better. The various drills and exercises are pretty easy to find and learn, and they&amp;rsquo;re pretty fun to do.
You can just Google &amp;ldquo;speed ladder drills&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ll get plenty of sites that do a far better job of explaining the drills than I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</guid>
      <description>Improving footwork is just one of many ways to improve quickness and efficiency on offense and defense. Other ways to improve quickness and efficiency include weight training, plyos to train muscles often overlooked/underused, learning to lower your center of gravity, core strengthening, and balance. As a team, Truck Stop has chosen to focuses on some of these other factors to improve quickness and efficiency.
However, there are two instances where I think a focus on footwork, more so than the other factors, can vastly improve performance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Other Sports</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</guid>
      <description>Ring of Fire&amp;rsquo;s Dave Snoke has tremendous footwork. Of course, Dave was a star soccer player for the NC State Wolfpack before switching over to Ultimate so it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise this skill is to his advantage. On offense, he constantly seems to accomplish more with less, taking the least amount of steps to get a big gain or get the O out of a tight situation, time and again. On the D side of things it&amp;rsquo;s not a matter of beating the receiver to the spot, but he excels at the cat and mouse game prior to the cut due to the economy of his footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay On Your Toes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/stay-on-your-toes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/stay-on-your-toes/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of simple rules that can be followed that have far reaching implications for improving your individual game. Staying on your toes, or more appropriately, keeping your weight on the balls of your feet, is one of the best, and can be the foundation for all improvement in footwork that increase your basic skills set. My mentor in the game, Steve Joye, one of the best players of the 80&amp;rsquo;s and early 90&amp;rsquo;s was a big (almost manic) proponent on this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Players of Note</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</guid>
      <description>Two players that come to mind when I think of good footwork are Idris Nolan offensively and Hensley Sejour defensively. Idris is quite a good basketball player, which requires a significant amount of body control as well as footwork. Hensley, coming from a football background as a defensive back (I believe) has worked on his footwork extensively.
Whether offensively or defensively, Idris and Hensley have the same traits in common:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Coach Arambula Is Preaching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</guid>
      <description>Is footwork important? Only if winning games is important. Ultimate, maybe more than any sport, has layers of pretty arm and upper-body movement that disguise a game primarily decided by feet. Basketball is right up there.
As a handler, I get lots of different body-types defending me during big games. I&amp;rsquo;m just as likely to look across the line and see Jit (Revolver&amp;rsquo;s tiny handler-defender extraordinaire) as I am to see some massive athlete that I have no hope of running with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Prescribed Rotation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</guid>
      <description>In this situation, it seems that it would be best to prescribe some movement, team-wide, which will give the thrower some better options than &amp;ldquo;turn to the dump.&amp;rdquo; Expressing some coordinated movement where all players (or at least those around the disc) have certain responsibilities will help clear up confusion and provide purpose to people&amp;rsquo;s movement.
On a previous team I played for, we had very specific dump rotations, and we ran a specific rotation for the first half and then switched that movement at halftime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>A good offense should be able to reset against even a very good defense. If we&amp;rsquo;re having trouble resetting, chances are that we&amp;rsquo;re suffering from a problem of our own making: either A. The design of our reset protocol is flawed; or B. We&amp;rsquo;re executing it poorly. †
A. There are many effective ways to reset a disc, but any effective way will probably have these elements:
The reset cutters give the thrower at least two options, simultaneously or in close succession, such that the marker must leave at least one throw open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipating The Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</guid>
      <description>One of the attributes of teams that do well at Nationals and other high-level tournaments is their handler defense. Many teams can do a pretty good job at containing handlers (e.g. getting the mark on to stop upfield break throws, adjusting to stop give-go&amp;rsquo;s, preventing up-the-line cuts). However, I think there are only a few teams that have the personnel and strategy to consistently pressure and generate D&amp;rsquo;s on handler resets—this includes pressure on both the thrower who may or may not be a handler, and on the actual handler who makes the reset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Your Rhythm &amp; Your Roles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</guid>
      <description>Three thoughts.
First, this is just the way high pressure games are. As the stakes increase, the defense ratchets up and the offense needs to ratchet up accordingly. How do you do this? Be mentally strong. The best path to this kind of mental fortitude is playing in and winning these games. The second best path (and the one reserved for those not on championship teams) is practicing all out. You play how you practice, so if you challenge yourself and your teammates every practice, you gameday performance will be correspondingly superior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic &amp; Potential Energy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</guid>
      <description>I believe that good chemistry between handlers can affect the game more than at any other position. Having two or three experienced handlers that really know each other is such an advantage because they likely have withstood defensive pressure like this before and they likely have talked about it and figured out, between them, how to deal with it. Because they can predict what the other is going to do, they don&amp;rsquo;t panic when the stall count gets higher and they can reset the disc accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor &amp; Major Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>My first impression of this situation would be to not over-react. There have been close calls, and one turn on handler cuts. If you are getting close to, or are already at the half, this is a pretty good tally to have, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make major changes.
Some small things to consider:
If the other team is counting the stall quickly (most likely the case), the thrower should make the fast-count call as he turns to the dump, or earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement, Movement, Movement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</guid>
      <description>The best way to attack a team that is playing good shut-down defense is to keep the disc moving, and moving quickly. This is not a novel concept by any means, but it&amp;rsquo;s rare that a team actually hits the first open pass consistently. Throwers tend to get antsy if you&amp;rsquo;re not gaining yardage and instead of looking to get rid of the frisbee, will instead hold it looking for something upfiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>When this happens I need to assess what about our reset isn&amp;rsquo;t working before I change anything. Generally, there are a few problems that are typical of this sort of situation.
The dump is not working hard enough. This is actually not the most likely explanation, but it does happen. This typically results from lack of readiness—the dump fails to get to position in a timely matter, or relies on the thrower to thread the needle rather than actually getting open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial &amp; Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>If this is in the middle of an elimination game, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to make an effective adjustment, it needs to be simple. It sounds like the defence is playing particularly tight around the disc, and putting enough pressure downfield to force us to take bad looks. If this is the case, these are probably the things I would try early on:
Look for the reset earlier in the count.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Progression Of Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It seems sensible to find the disc as early as possible. However, I think first I need to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m matching the receiver stride for stride, so I let them do the work of finding the disc early on and use that time to make up some ground.
Any work they do finding the disc will also help me pinpoint where to look for it. Once I&amp;rsquo;m matching their stride, I&amp;rsquo;ll look for the disc and start making judgments about how the contest is going to pan out</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Texas Hold&#39;em Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</guid>
      <description>Deep D is a lot like poker in three significant ways:
1. Information is more important than anything else.
2. You play the hand you are dealt, and try to win more than your share given the cards in your hand.
3. It ain&amp;rsquo;t over until til it&amp;rsquo;s over.
Information: As I turn to head deep and hear that &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call, I need to get a read on the disc as quickly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>As I am already behind, my priority is to catch up. It&amp;rsquo;s harder to run fast with your head turned, so I will sometimes let the intended receiver read the disc for me and take the hit, in terms of speed. At this point, help from the sideline, in terms of which direction to go, is very helpful.
As soon as I know that I can catch up, or I hear from the sideline that the throw is short, I will turn my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Quickly Based On The Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/calculate-quickly-based-on-the-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/calculate-quickly-based-on-the-throw/</guid>
      <description>When I hear the &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call I try to spot the disc, briefly and without giving up any more ground.
I need to ascertain if it has truly gone up, and if it is intended for the player I am now chasing. If both of these things are true, then I try to make some quick calculations based on what type of throw has been made.
If it is low or short, I can simply go to it and have position underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Defensive Speed</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</guid>
      <description>There is a big factor that comes into play here that I should use to set the stage:
Why are big time football receivers 6&#39;2&amp;quot; or 6&#39;3&amp;quot; and 220lbs (think Terrell Owens), while big time defensive backs are 5&#39;10&amp;quot; or 5&#39;11&amp;quot; and 190lbs?
And: Why does it generally seem that DBs are the fastest guys, but you routinely see them getting beat deep by receivers who should be slower?
There are two speeds that ultimate defenders (and football defenders) have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get In Front</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</guid>
      <description>Even though the answer to this question is pretty straightforward—a surprising number of club players make errors on this play.
First of all, if I am only a stride or two behind my check when a huck goes up then I am feeling pretty good about my positioning. Only a perfectly thrown disc will not allow me to have a play on it. Secondly—and this is where many players make an error—I always make the inside play on the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Position Relative To Your Opponent</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</guid>
      <description>Being a receiver, this scenario is one of my favorite moments in ultimate. The adrenaline kicks in and it dawns on you that it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to make the play you have been training all season. My training regimen is focused on maximizing acceleration and jumping ability, both of which are essential to getting the block in this scenario. But before putting those skills to use, you have to look up quickly and find the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Get It</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/go-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/go-get-it/</guid>
      <description>In the deep-D scenario, the disc is already in the air. But let&amp;rsquo;s rewind just a bit. As a defender, my goal is for the &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call to be the second sign that the disc is coming. The first sign should be my anticipation of the play as it develops. The more I am aware of what is happening with the disc, the mark, and the other cutters, the easier it is to anticipate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play The Player First, Then The Disc</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</guid>
      <description>When I hear the up-call, my first instinct is to get between my player and where I think the disc is going to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t look for the disc yet because the disc is secondary to my player when I&amp;rsquo;m on defense. If I can get my body into the proper position, I will get the disc every time.
Typically in this situation, I will try to make some kind of body contact (not with arms or legs)—jockeying for position using my butt or shoulders to maintain my position between my player and the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train For The Launch Pad</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</guid>
      <description>More than any other skill in ultimate—besides, maybe, getting layout blocks—dominating in the air has largely to do with raw athleticism, aggressiveness, and instinct. There&amp;rsquo;s really no substitute for being a physical beast. If you&amp;rsquo;re tall and fast, and you have springs for legs, you&amp;rsquo;re going to posterize some poor souls, and in the process you&amp;rsquo;ll develop confidence and intuition that you&amp;rsquo;ll bring into every future matchup.
So: train. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not a premium genetic specimen, effective training can bring out the inner beast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Your Body As The Cut Starts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</guid>
      <description>If your man starts heading deep and you hear an up-call, you have to assume the thrower is putting up a huck&amp;hellip;so, obviously, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to try to beat your guy to the spot.
Back to Ultimate 101 for a second: if you were guarding the last guy in the stack, you probably have last-back responsibilities. An unguarded deep look is a lot more dangerous than an open under cut, so make sure the deep is shut down first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternating Matchups</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s too bad you can&amp;rsquo;t put the World&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Defender on this person, because they sound like they are the World&amp;rsquo;s Best Offensive Player.
I would probably get two defenders to alternate defensive points with the intention of solely guarding this person. Ideally, one defender would be the quick/squirrelly type with a good mark to challenge him around the disc and apply pressure on the mark. The second defender would be fast and preferably able to out-jump this person, with the intention of continuing to push him deep (but maybe not quite as much as in the first half).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box-And-One</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</guid>
      <description>A player like this, who clearly has multiple offensive weapons, presents a serious match up challenge. Individual defensive match ups are an odd thing, and it can be difficult to predict which defender would be most effective. Given the past experience of this player being most effective as a deep thrower, I would continue to push them away from the disc. I would try different defenders on them until finding a player who could be successful in keeping the player away from the disc, and in containing their deep game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containing A Big Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</guid>
      <description>The best strategy for containing good deep throwers depends in part on the type of handler position they are playing. If the thrower is frequently in a dump reset position, the number one priority must be that he does not get the disc moving up field. A good thrower with momentum and a trailing mark is deadly. You will often find a defender guard this player well for the first two or three resets and then the defender will get impatient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cue The Comeback!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</guid>
      <description>Well&amp;hellip;the answer to a situation like this (defending a handler in the lanes) is going to be dependant on a number of factors and variables that are unknown in this scenario (athletic ability, height, speed, etc.). However, in a general sense, if you have one of the main players on the opposing team drastically altering their game due to your defensive strategy then your defensive strategy is effective. Forcing a &amp;ldquo;main handler&amp;rdquo; to strike and cut downfield is a great situation for the defensive team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Goals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</guid>
      <description>On defense, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to shut down all options , because that&amp;rsquo;s impossible against a good offense. Rather, your goal is to dictate to the offense those options it can take. So, the first thing to realize here is: if Big Thrower hasn&amp;rsquo;t been able to make big throws, you&amp;rsquo;ve done something successful.
The question to ask yourself now: Is Big Thrower hurting us more now as a deep receiver than he/she usually does as a thrower?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Opponent Guessing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s question is essentially asking what do you do if your original game plan and strategy for how to play a certain player doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working. In this case, I would consider coming up with multiple different strategies for minimizing that players&amp;rsquo; apparent strengths. Here are four possible strategies (and in the order I would attempt them) for dealing with a player with dominant throws:
1. Front her to try and deny her the disc on any easy pass, forcing her to make plays in a way that is not her preference (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Any Adjustment...Just Make It Now</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</guid>
      <description>This is a very interesting scenario because there are so many adjustments that could be made to respond to this player. You could assign a speedy defender to outrun him on the deep cuts, you could assign a tall defender to pull down floaty passes, you could assign a physical defender to disrupt the flow of his cuts, you could keep playing the same defense on him but put a straight-up mark on everyone else, you could go zone, you could play last back, or you could even throw your scouting report out the window and let him hang around the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It A Team Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</guid>
      <description>They say that coaching is the art of making decisions without statistical significance in the data. Ok, they don&amp;rsquo;t say that&amp;hellip;I say that. We have 6 minutes left in halftime, and our captains are getting together to decide if Big Thrower is just having a great half, or if this is a tactical change. To any reasonable statistical measure, we are flipping a coin here. The data just doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist to tell us for sure whether or not this might happen in the second half, and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a gut call if we want to switch tactics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make The Offense Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Adjustments made before during a game can win&amp;hellip;or lose a game. Pre-game scouting reports or prior encounters can give clues for how each team&amp;rsquo;s offense and defense should come out of the gate. However, there is no substitute for actually playing the game and making real-time evaluations. There is a fine line to walk between jumping the gun on an adjustment and not acting soon enough and I think that one of the hardest jobs of a team strategist is this evaluation and subsequent decision for adjustment or non- adjustment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Lose A Game Without</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</guid>
      <description>As a wise woman once said (props to those who get the joke), never lose a game without playing zone. I think this thought answers the question but taken to a broader sense: never get beat over and over again without changing something.
So your scouting report was wrong or the team has adjusted to all their opponents having the same scouting report on their strong player. This happens very often with great, specialized players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old School Vs. New School</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be two diverging philosophies on how to defend against a very skilled deep thrower that has also hurt you going deep. The first philosophy is perhaps considered old school, focusing on team defense and changing the team&amp;rsquo;s defensive strategy. The second, new school, philosophy is what I like to call the &amp;ldquo;hack-a-Shaq&amp;rdquo; tactic, and although not exactly the same as its namesake, the results are comparable. The hack-a-Shaq consists of intentionally fouling the thrower to significantly disrupt the offensive flow (and deep shot) without consequence to the defending team and, I hate to say, is indelibly efficacious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Your First-Half Performance</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</guid>
      <description>I like to look at the bigger picture before making adjustments for just one player. (This is assuming you have used the same strategy in previous meetings and have been successful).
Assumptions
1. The third goal was scored in the normal flow of the O (whether Man or Zone).
2. Two goals were scored while the D was in a straight man D, ie no zone transition.
3. The game is not determined by the wind, ie a windy upwind/downwind game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Resilient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You take away a team&amp;rsquo;s strength and make them beat you with their weakness. If they do, you make them do it again, because it’s their f***ing weakness!&amp;rdquo; — Jon Gewirtz
This situation is so similar to what Jam did with Damien Scott in the 04 finals that I almost think that &amp;ldquo;The Huddle&amp;rdquo; ripped it right off of the video. All season long, Damien had handled. He wasn’t a great hucker, but he could always get open for a reset and hand a very nice forehand inside out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suggested Team &amp; Individual Tactics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/suggested-team-individual-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/suggested-team-individual-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In ultimate, good offense beats good defense. Defense becomes especially difficult when the opponent has a dynamic player that is both a threat with the disc and down field. Down 8-6 at the half our defensive goal is to make the opponents offense, and most importantly this dynamic player, uncomfortable. We can do this with both team and individual defensive tactics.
Suggested Team Tactics
Zone Defense: Makes the offense complete many throws to score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Answer May Be On The Field Already</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and assume we&amp;rsquo;re pulling, so that will give our guy what we hope to be two chances to make up for the first half, even the score, and allow us to see if what was said at halftime served any purpose; or was the guy simply standing there nodding his head like a boxer, in one ear and out the other, all the while wondering if he should&amp;rsquo;ve run off to the Honey Bucket or maybe he should put on a different wrist band, maybe someone has some tape he can borrow, maybe some Gu will help, maybe some Red Bull, maybe he should go mess around in his bag and look for something he knows isn&amp;rsquo;t there—the things they didn&amp;rsquo;t carry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do They Want To Do?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-do-they-want-to-do-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-do-they-want-to-do-/</guid>
      <description>Whenever lining up against a gifted opponent I have always found it helpful to ask myself: what does this player want to do? In this case, this player is most comfortable and probably most confident in a handler role, staying behind the disc and throwing goals rather than receiving them. When playing against teams that have a player like this, someone who excels in many aspects, always make them beat you with their Plan B or Plan C, never Plan A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Concede &amp; What To Take Away</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</guid>
      <description>This one is pretty straightforward: as with any player, you have to determine what you want to give up and what you want to take away (or try to, anyway). You&amp;rsquo;re going to want to deny any player&amp;rsquo;s greatest strength or whatever facet of his game is capable of hurting you most. If this guy has beaten you repeatedly with his throws, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a very good idea to allow him to get the disc underneath - even if he has caught a couple hucks today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers To All Of These Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player? What about as a handler? As a hucker? What would they have to show you to prove their worth?
Sure they do and it depends on their skill set. It&amp;rsquo;s more than likely easier for one to make it as a hucker first; pretty much everyone can huck it. Making it as a primary handler (a &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;) is somewhat tougher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athleticism First, Attitude Close Behind</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</guid>
      <description>The most important things I want to see from a tryout are, in no particular order:
Athleticism/speed Field sense Confidence with the disc Ability &amp;amp; willingness to take direction The first point speaks for itself. If a player can&amp;rsquo;t run fast, jump, layout, and exhibit a reasonable level of body control, they don&amp;rsquo;t stand much of a chance.
For field sense, I want to see that a player knows where the next pass is likely to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus On What You Can Control</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</guid>
      <description>Trying out for a club team is like interviewing for any job. There are some things that are in your control and some things that aren’t. It’s important to focus on the things you can control and understand that the other things aren’t worth worrying about. Even if you are a great thrower, if the team already has great throwers then the 6’9&amp;quot; guy that can’t throw may get selected over you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go After Similar, More Experienced Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</guid>
      <description>I think the first thing that a player should evaluate is their own talents and strengths. During the tryout you should be focusing on accentuating those strengths when given the chance. If you&amp;rsquo;re a tall deep threat, don&amp;rsquo;t waste time in a scrimmage squirelling around the disc, and in any huck drill make sure you are going up strong to show that you can climb. If you&amp;rsquo;re a squirrely quick guy, make sure you are getting open on all short cuts, and that if there are any sprints to be done that you are winning them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Work Stands Out</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</guid>
      <description>At tryouts, I am looking for someone who will fit into the TOP HALF of our roster if they are a new player. I prefer having all-team tryouts so that each member, even if they have played on the team previously, brings great intensity to tryouts — this is the best way to start a season (and the most fair way to choose a team).
In terms of skills, this means you need to have all the basics without flaw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective From The Team &amp; From A Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</guid>
      <description>A couple of thoughts that I always have when tryouts roll around:
Any young player that wants to improve should be trying out for any team possible. Tryout ultimate is typically intense, cheap, and with players that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally play with. This can be an amazing opportunity to improve&amp;hellip;especially with experienced players available that are motivated (or at least ready) to give constructive feedback. This can be a great opportunity for developing players, regardless of your own chances of making the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play To Your Best, Tone Down The Rest</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</guid>
      <description>You have to ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What do I do that is great?&amp;rdquo; This is your ticket onto a team. For most young players, this is blue-collar Ultimate: tough D, swing passes and safe choices. If what you have to offer is something different (big throws, great recievership), then showcase those skills.
The two quickest ways to get yourself cut are poor atheleticism (nothing much to be done about that) and poor choices with the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Fundamentals Trump Team Needs</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</guid>
      <description>Tryouts are such a weird time for me. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting the season is starting and so many people want to tryout for our team, but at the same time the decisions can be stressful and as much pressure as one might feel when trying out, the team is also some amount of pressure on the team being tried out to find a good fit. Since there are a few different options in Boston, it is very important for our team to put our best foot forward and we try to do it as accurately as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things To Focus On At Any Level</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/things-to-focus-on-at-any-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/things-to-focus-on-at-any-level/</guid>
      <description>Here are my six recommendations to anyone who is trying out for a team of any level:
1. Be on time and have all of the appropriate equipment for the tryout.
2. Relax — tryouts are a high stress process for everyone involved, but as a captain/coach I&amp;rsquo;m looking to see how players handle themselves throughout the process. Tryouts are a decent representation of how players will handle high-stress situations during tournaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Chris Ashbrook</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player?
Absolutely. There are a number of college players that have now played on club teams while still in college (Watson, Heijman, Cahill, Gibson, etc), some while in high school. These players are usually the best offensive players on their teams and have been to college nationals, at least once, if not multiple times. Although they may have inexperience on the club seen, they have crunch time experience and are able to eventually translate that to the club scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts From Team USA Tryouts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on this topic are at the front of my mind today!
Advice to tryouts:
1. Distinguish yourself on defense, even if you consider yourself an offensive player. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the offensive system of the new team, you can always make an impression on D. In particular, focus on marks and shut-down defense.
Be the defender who uses intelligence, positioning, and quickness to prevent his guy from getting open for uncontested passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advantages Of A Spread Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</guid>
      <description>Without question, the horizontal offense is a better wind offense. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s the right choice for your team. The horizontal offense offers a couple really nice advantages in a high wind situation, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the personnel to run it, it&amp;rsquo;ll be worse than a vertical offense. Ben wrote &amp;ldquo;equivalent talent,&amp;rdquo; but I ask what talent?
(Quick aside: Sockeye and Furious are the two most effective teams at running the horizontal offense, but they are fundamentally different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advantages Of Either Offensive Set</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-either-offensive-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-either-offensive-set/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost I will say that I am completely biased in favor of a horizontal based offense in a non-windy environment. While there are certain advantages in starting out of a vertical, I believe that a horizontal flow gives players the maximum amount of freedom and space to run the offense. However, in windy conditions (depending on the severity) vertical, if run correctly, does have its advantages.
Provided that the wind isn&amp;rsquo;t brutal (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cater to Your Team&#39;s Particular Skills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</guid>
      <description>Any offense is difficult in the wind, so when conditions are windy a team should play the offense that it has practiced the most. Both vertical and horizontal stack offenses have advantages and disadvantages in the wind and the decision to play one over the other depends on how well your team can be on the same page while running it&amp;rsquo;s O.
When my team first made the transition from vertical stack to horizontal stack back in 2005, we struggled in the wind and often would switch back to the vert stack when it was windy and we were having difficulty scoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience &amp; Coordination</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</guid>
      <description>To my eyes, the advantage of the spread/horizontal is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a whole group of people working together, but can be effective by working in just pairs of upfield cutters or on occasion an isolated receiver. Of course, the better teams will have coordination of all the players, but for a young team, or a team using a new system, things can get up and running effectively with the horizontal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal Stack in Windy Conditions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/horizontal-stack-in-windy-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/horizontal-stack-in-windy-conditions/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure what equivalent talent is but you simply have more options in a HORIZONTAL stack and the cutters are generally all closer to the ball. This is important because all four cutters are options, in and out, almost simultaneously. Additionally, using the field as 4 cutting lanes as opposed to two, for seasoned cutters is easier. The problem is most cutters don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are doing. I think you need to play a lot of Vertical stack to learn how to cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On The Stack Debate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</guid>
      <description>Given the chess game that&amp;rsquo;s taking place, the O should be keeping the D on their toes equally as much, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a matter Of which type of O I&amp;rsquo;d &amp;ldquo;rather&amp;rdquo; run. Considering the conditions are windy enough, I&amp;rsquo;d more than likely prefer the Ho stack mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m thinking the D is coming zone or zone for a certain number of passes. If the D looks to transition after 4/5/6 passes, the secondary outside players are already set in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts From Australia</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</guid>
      <description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about this a lot, surprisingly. I find I&amp;rsquo;m generally on a team that&amp;rsquo;s drilled a lot of vertical or drilled a lot of horizontal, so we&amp;rsquo;re better at one particular offence in most conditions.
All other things being equal, horizontal relies on using static structure to create space on the field, whereas vertical relies on cutting (dynamic structure?) to create space on the field.
Wind tends to nullify cutting advantages, so theoretically horizontally should be preferred in the wind, all other things being equal, including your team&amp;rsquo;s ability to play either offence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent Determines Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</guid>
      <description>I would say that the absolute talents of your team will likely favor one offense over the other. If you cannot consistently complete passes greater than forty yards, a stack offense is more favorable than a horizontal. Any situation where the defense no longer has to defend the deep pass puts the horizontal stack offense at a significant disadvantage. This generality can be extrapolated to any situation, not just wind condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vouching For the Vert Stack</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</guid>
      <description>I guess I&amp;rsquo;m pretty old school on this one. One of the main advantages of the horizontal offense is the deep space it affords throwers, particularly once cutters get the disc in their hands. In a crosswind or upwind situation, deep looks for any thrower become less of an option so I would prefer to run the vertical stack. This usually gives the thrower multiple in looks and I find the dump-swing to be much easier out of a vertical set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Team Are We?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</guid>
      <description>I want to first analyze what type of team we are and what type of team we are playing in determining which offense (and defense) to run.
Downwind
Here I generally prefer the horizontal stack, regardless (and variations), as I feel you a thrower is given more choices from nearly every position. Players also tend to overplay defensively when guarding an O that is going downwind which I feel tends to open up cutters underneath and away more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Type of Offense Fits Your Team?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</guid>
      <description>There are numerous factors to consider when deciding whether to run a horizontal stack (HO) or vertical stack (Vert) offense such as: recent success rate with a particular offense against your opponent, probable individual match-ups with your opponent, and how critical the particular point is. In this scenario we are asked to discuss how another factor, wind, affects that decision. Before that discussion, however, it is necessary to look generally at the relative costs and benefits of the Vert versus the HO offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Ho-Stack Is Currently In Favor</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</guid>
      <description>The horizontal stack has all but replaced the vertical stack because it does such a good job of creating space. When run effectively, four cutters typically are spread across the width of the field. This spacing between cutters makes defensive switches very difficult, thereby putting each downfield defender on an island one-on-one with their man. As any cutter will tell you, when you know your defender doesn&amp;rsquo;t have help, you have the advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
