<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peri Kurshan on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/peri-kurshan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peri Kurshan on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/peri-kurshan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nuture What You Like, Overcome What You Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/nuture-what-you-like-overcome-what-you-don-t/</guid>
      <description>Team culture can often be overlooked as an important contributor to your team’s success, both in the short and long term. The culture of your team determines what types of players will be attracted to the team, will enjoy playing on your team, and will stick around season after season. There is no one &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; team culture, and it can be defined as much from the actions of a single individual (founder, strong personality, etc) as shaped over time by the collective actions and personalities of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Intensity, Concepts, and Fun</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning can be daunting and it’s often hard to know where to start. It can be difficult to strike the right balance between fun and intense, learning and playing, covering everything and getting enough reps on any individual thing, etc. In my experience, it helps to have a broad, season-long outline from which to flesh out individual practices. This means having a rough idea of all the different strategies you want to cover in a season (specific offenses, specific defenses, fundamentals, etc), and making sure there are enough practices to cover everything (and if there aren’t, then to scale back your expectations of how much to cover in the season!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotate 90°</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark can effectively make the backfield dump a very difficult throw. Here are a few ways to prevent this defense from making your life as a thrower difficult.
First of all, the D is most effective on a high stall count when you are running out of time and options (and many teams will only shift their marks to take away the dump once the stall count gets high).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips &amp; Insights</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</guid>
      <description>When the disc is dead, always check behind your back to see where the first threats are and position yourself to take those away most effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s the one chance you have to see what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen behind you before you set up your mark—use it!
I try to think of my arms and legs separately as a &amp;rsquo;two-pronged&amp;rsquo; defense. Think of your arms as being on a separate vertical plane from your legs, so that the thrower has to get through 2 vertical planes of extremities rather than just one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Slow-Developing Chess Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/a-slow-developing-chess-game/</guid>
      <description>Zone O is like a game of chess- you spend a while moving your pieces around the board, not making much apparent headway, trying to find the weakness in the other team&amp;rsquo;s defense, and then suddenly you see your opportunity to capture their queen and it&amp;rsquo;s off to the races! Zone O also often showcases the triumph of craftiness over athleticism. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be faster or taller or quicker than the other team- you just need to be skilled with the disc, disciplined, and know how to take advantage of the opportunities that present themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use All Of Your Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</guid>
      <description>I believe that what makes a team successful is its ability to use all of its players. Most good teams have a few superstars- those players that are game- changers and whose absence can really hurt the team&amp;rsquo;s chances. However, the difference between good teams and great teams, I believe, lies in how the team utilizes its role players. Ultimate is truly a team sport, and if the top players on a team aren&amp;rsquo;t supported by a solid and confident group of role players, the team will have many exploitable weaknesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Do When The Field Shrinks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</guid>
      <description>The field shrinks when you reach the endzone.
Your defender no longer has to worry about your deep cuts, and so can front you by a larger margin. The pressure builds- a turnover here in the &amp;ldquo;red zone&amp;rdquo; seems particularly disheartening. All of a sudden, everyone is cutting at once, forgetting about rules and technique, just anxious to get the disc and finish the point.
However, it is precisely here in the red zone that it becomes all the more important to remember your team&amp;rsquo;s strategies and offense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
