<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lou Burruss on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/lou-burruss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lou Burruss on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/lou-burruss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Teens Again</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/it-s-teens-again/</guid>
      <description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t there, but as I was watching the live feed of Fury dismantling Brute Squad I was struck by a sense of déjà vu; I felt like I was watching Godiva. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about Fury and Godiva&amp;rsquo;s dominance, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about a single little cut that is the backbone of both team&amp;rsquo;s offenses. It&amp;rsquo;s a cut I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen other teams (men&amp;rsquo;s or women&amp;rsquo;s) use. I remember watching Teens (Christine Dunlap) wreck people with this cut, getting wide open again and again and again, so it was a little weird to watch Fury doing the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfailing Terminology</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</guid>
      <description>Catching the pull requires four players: a 1, a 2, a Short Fill, and a Deep Fill. Everyone else can have their heads up their asses and it&amp;rsquo;ll be okay.
The 1&amp;rsquo;s job is to catch the pull and make the first pass.
The 2&amp;rsquo;s job is to set themselves up to catch the first pass, catch the first pass and then deliver the big throw to the 3.
The Short Fill&amp;rsquo;s job is to read the pull and the defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Unpredictable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</guid>
      <description>1. Face the mark. This classic piece of throwing technology dates back to the dawn of modern Ultimate when Windy City and NYNY ruled. The uneducated thrower looks upfield at the stack and they position their body to reflect this. When they want to throw a dump they have to turn 270 degrees, which is incredibly slow. (Or turn their back to the field, which is incredibly dumb.) By facing the mark, you shorten the turn to 180 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice, No More</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve mastered the basics (like the two-spot mark) and the not-so-basic- but-standard (like denying the dump on stalling 8), it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to learning individual players.
Of course you know all the moves of your nemesis; you play him five times a season and cover him every point you&amp;rsquo;re in. Of course you adjust your game to meet the challenge. Your match-ups become games within games within games where the slightest mistake yields victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Issues With Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-real-issues-with-spirit/</guid>
      <description>I love the Huddle. I think the work they do is a great contribution to Ultimate, I love reading the other contributors&amp;rsquo; work and I am honored that they would include me as an author. That said, I can&amp;rsquo;t believe they are making such a colossal mistake in having ONE Spirit of the Game issue.
Spirit of the Game is essential to Ultimate. Every time we step on the field to play, we are participating in what makes Ultimate unique and special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Plays For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The trick to a good set play package is selecting the right plays for your team. Here are some basic guidelines:
1. Make it worth your time. There is only so much your team can learn, so you want to make sure you are getting the most out of what you are practicing. If you are playing elite club ultimate, over half of your possessions are going to be off of the pull, so learn more pull plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Condor Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-condor-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>Up through the 90s, teams played a mix of two- and three-handler sets, but all zone offenses emphasized swinging the disc and attacking the far side of the field against a zone on the run. Then, the Condors, led by handlers James Studarus, Steve Dugan and Taro Ramberg began to run something fundamentally different. This was a two-handler set that didn&amp;rsquo;t swing and attacked a stagnant zone. Their philosophy was that no matter how many defenders you pulled in, you weren&amp;rsquo;t going to be able to stop two of them from throwing it back and forth to each other on little two to five yard passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-Legged Stool</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</guid>
      <description>Think of the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offense as a three-legged stool. You want to knock it over. Do you kick the sturdiest leg? No, that&amp;rsquo;d be silly. Kick the weak leg.
Look, marquee players are going to get theirs. You can put your best defender on them, rotate defenders, do what you want; they are still going to get open, still get the disc and still make throws. But we all know Ultimate isn&amp;rsquo;t a one person game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It All Comes Back To Throwing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</guid>
      <description>The most important piece to an effective initiation cut is the thrower. To get open, you need to be able to challenge the defender into at least two different places. In the typical flat-stack set, there are three spaces open to the interior cutters: open-side, break-side, and deep. If the thrower can hit all of those spots, getting open is no problem. Fake to one of them, cut to another. Throw, catch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Chris Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</guid>
      <description>You need Chris Page. Chris who? Remember back when Sockeye was good the first time? Back in the 90s and you watched those epic battles on NBC? Dreaming of how it was gonna be you? Sockeye-Double Happiness? Sockeye-Rhino? All those heart-breakers against DoG? Remember that shaggy headed blonde kid ripping it forehand, backhand, marked, didn&amp;rsquo;t matter? That was Chris Page.
When I hit the big time in 96, I had some power, but no control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Sub-Caller Is...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple little tricks that can really help you out.
This first technique is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never done, but I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna name it. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it Repeater. I saw it first at College Nationals this year, where Syzygy was using it (they crushed us) and I later overheard teams using it at Solstice (Eugene) and HoDown (Calgary). Basically, your sub caller yells out the names just as usual and then everyone repeats them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Catching: Two Drills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</guid>
      <description>It is a common misperception that catching cannot be taught. Learning how to catch comes down to repetition and focus. Here are two quick drills for teaching new players to catch and for honing experienced players&amp;rsquo; skills.
The first drill (unnamed) involves two people and ten (or more) discs. The players (thrower and catcher) stand about two yards apart. The thrower tosses disc after disc to the catcher. The thrower should place the discs so that the catcher is forced to catch high, low, left, right, one- and two-handed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Your Rhythm &amp; Your Roles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</guid>
      <description>Three thoughts.
First, this is just the way high pressure games are. As the stakes increase, the defense ratchets up and the offense needs to ratchet up accordingly. How do you do this? Be mentally strong. The best path to this kind of mental fortitude is playing in and winning these games. The second best path (and the one reserved for those not on championship teams) is practicing all out. You play how you practice, so if you challenge yourself and your teammates every practice, you gameday performance will be correspondingly superior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Resilient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You take away a team&amp;rsquo;s strength and make them beat you with their weakness. If they do, you make them do it again, because it’s their f***ing weakness!&amp;rdquo; — Jon Gewirtz
This situation is so similar to what Jam did with Damien Scott in the 04 finals that I almost think that &amp;ldquo;The Huddle&amp;rdquo; ripped it right off of the video. All season long, Damien had handled. He wasn’t a great hucker, but he could always get open for a reset and hand a very nice forehand inside out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play To Your Best, Tone Down The Rest</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</guid>
      <description>You have to ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What do I do that is great?&amp;rdquo; This is your ticket onto a team. For most young players, this is blue-collar Ultimate: tough D, swing passes and safe choices. If what you have to offer is something different (big throws, great recievership), then showcase those skills.
The two quickest ways to get yourself cut are poor atheleticism (nothing much to be done about that) and poor choices with the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advantages Of A Spread Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</guid>
      <description>Without question, the horizontal offense is a better wind offense. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s the right choice for your team. The horizontal offense offers a couple really nice advantages in a high wind situation, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the personnel to run it, it&amp;rsquo;ll be worse than a vertical offense. Ben wrote &amp;ldquo;equivalent talent,&amp;rdquo; but I ask what talent?
(Quick aside: Sockeye and Furious are the two most effective teams at running the horizontal offense, but they are fundamentally different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
