<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretically Helpful Exercise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t really answer these questions. The right answers depend on too many factors, many of which can only be judged during your game. Variables such as individual&amp;rsquo;s athleticism, defensive abilities, your opponent&amp;rsquo;s strengths, current conditions, number of defenders available, ect, are all part of the equation.
Having an answer to these questions is hard, but judging the quality of your answer is even harder. At best it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly difficult to evaluate results based on your coaching input alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Your Defenders A Chance</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/give-your-defenders-a-chance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/give-your-defenders-a-chance/</guid>
      <description>Just as with an offensive squad, each player on the defensive line has a few areas that he or she excels at. Some may be good at running down the long, streaking cuts, while other will be good at then tight, close-to-the-disc cuts. There may be another who has a very active mark that comes up with more point blocks than anyone else. And just as the offense trains players to fill certain roles, so should the defense train players to stop certain roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations To Matchup Theory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</guid>
      <description>Defensive matchups can be a positive aspect of successfully implementing a defensive strategy, but they can also serve to be a limitation. There are certain instances where a defender just has another players number and as a team you would be foolish to not consider that, but if you let certain matchups become the focus of the defensive strategy it may prevent you from running the defenses that are most successful for the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matching Up With Defensive Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/matching-up-with-defensive-characteristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/matching-up-with-defensive-characteristics/</guid>
      <description>I have a fairly low tolerance for good defenders getting beat. On the other hand, I&amp;rsquo;m always telling my girls (until I&amp;rsquo;m blue in the face) that the offensive player always has an advantage because she always know where she&amp;rsquo;s going to cut, and the defensive player is always a step behind. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m always going to put my best defender on the other team&amp;rsquo;s best offensive threat, unless there&amp;rsquo;s a reason that I don&amp;rsquo;t want that matchup—be it height, or speed, or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Defensive Assets</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</guid>
      <description>Know your foe.
There are lots of ways you can get the most out of your defensive matchups and it starts with not only knowing your own players but also knowing your opponents. The more familiar you are with the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offensive weapons ahead of time, the better you can prepare to counter them quickly and effectively. Furthermore, as important as it is to recognize primary play makers, it&amp;rsquo;s just as important to know how the rest of your roster compares overall to the other team&amp;rsquo;s personnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Impact</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</guid>
      <description>Lets step away from Ultimate, and assume you are playing a card game in which there are five random cards face up on the table and you will get dealt five cards randomly; your job is to pair each one of your cards up with one on the table. There are many ways of doing this (five to be exact!).
Example
Presented on the table: 7 J 3 9 K</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May The Best Man Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</guid>
      <description>I have an image, indelible perhaps, of UCSC&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Hagar and ECU&amp;rsquo;s Nat Taylor standing before each other after their battle at College Nationals in 1993 [not sure but this game may have decided semis]. Each was covered in grass stains, dirt, sweat, and knowing Hager probably some blood and a new scar. Standing their considering the other, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell who won, except the Slugs had more points.
For the many of us who have played at the top level, and for the many that will one day get there, we know that playing through a Section and a Region and later a National is not unlike getting through each round of a fortnight of tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>In a person defense, getting the right matchups can be critically important. It can also require some trial and error. Teams which face each other all the time get to try out a number of different approaches until they get most comfortable. Teams that don&amp;rsquo;t see each other often have a challenge at the start—but fortunately both teams have that challenge. The team that figures out how to neutralize (or at least slow down) the key threat from the other team the fastest can get an advantage early in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-Legged Stool</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/three-legged-stool/</guid>
      <description>Think of the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offense as a three-legged stool. You want to knock it over. Do you kick the sturdiest leg? No, that&amp;rsquo;d be silly. Kick the weak leg.
Look, marquee players are going to get theirs. You can put your best defender on them, rotate defenders, do what you want; they are still going to get open, still get the disc and still make throws. But we all know Ultimate isn&amp;rsquo;t a one person game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Rotate Or Not To Rotate?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</guid>
      <description>To rotate or not to rotate? That is the question. Well, that depends on what type of game we are talking about. If we are talking about semis at Nationals, and I have a great downfield defender and the other team has a great downfield offensive player, then my defender is going to be on that offensive player for as long as they are effective. If this is pool play at Nationals, than I feel like it is somewhat necessary to share the load for fear that you may wear out your best defensive player during Day One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Should Guard Their Best Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</guid>
      <description>Let me answer this question with a question. When was the last time your best cutter defender spent a scrimmage covering your best handler? How about the other way around? Sure, your best on the ball defender talks all the time about hounding the region&amp;rsquo;s best handler, and your best athlete wants to stop the receiver all others fear, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a game hoping (or just hoping) your top players match up well against their top players.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
