<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Beating&#34; The Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</guid>
      <description>When most players think about breaking the mark, they envision a thrower throwing around or over a stationary mark. However, I&amp;rsquo;d argue that the majority of break throws in high level ultimate don&amp;rsquo;t happen this way. Most breaks I see are simple forehands and backhands thrown in motion with the mark trailing behind the thrower.
You can be a great at switching fields with the Frisbee and have terrible &amp;ldquo;break throws&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allowing Mistakes, Deceiving Marks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</guid>
      <description>What is your favorite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; for breaking the mark? How do you do it, and in what situations do you find it most useful?
To break the mark, I typically like to convince, or deceive, the mark that I am going to throw a different throw than what I want.
For example, if I am being forced flick and I want to throw the around backhand break, I will get into a very threatening inside out forehand flick position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Easier Way</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the easiest way to break the mark is just to let someone else do it. I mean, break throws are hard. Do I really want to go to the trouble of pivoting all over the place, faking out the mark, getting off a potentially risky throw&amp;hellip; and then perhaps get hacked by the mark for my efforts? Forget it. I just don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of hassle.
Not everyone can break the mark at will, and even for those who have great break throws, it can still be a somewhat risky pass at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Fake Make Be A Viable Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</guid>
      <description>The best piece of advice I ever received about breaking the mark is that every fake must be a viable throw. You need to create space in order to break the mark; strong fakes are going to make that happen. Many defenders choose to watch only the disc when they are marking (don&amp;rsquo;t do that, defenders!) and therefore they are reacting to your fakes. By making realistic fakes, with the disc and your upper body movement, you will get your defender to shift their weight and be off-balance for a moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From The 2000 UPA Finals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</guid>
      <description>2000 Open Finals: Condors vs Furious George. It&amp;rsquo;s four even. Mike Grant [of FG] is defended by Corey Sanford. Mike runs a sort of S-cut in the end zone. Jeff Cruicshank with the disc. He seems to look break mark for a righty backhand, then he pivots big for his lefty inside out backhand, throws a quick, strong fake, and then he throws the inside out backhand to Grant. The throw is right in the sweet spot, safely away from Corey&amp;rsquo;s extended hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Breaking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite fakes is really quite quick (maybe a quarter of a second of motion), and from the waist up looks exactly like I am going to move my pivot foot for an around break, but I immediately step out for an inside break. My head and torso kind of lunge to one side, and I move the disc quite quickly in the same direction, but my lower body remains stationary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan Ahead</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/plan-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/plan-ahead/</guid>
      <description>By far the most effective &amp;ldquo;move&amp;rdquo; for breaking the mark that I&amp;rsquo;ve found is one that is rarely (but with increasing frequency) used in the women&amp;rsquo;s game. The general idea is that you throw a backhand over the mark&amp;rsquo;s shoulder (while being forced backhand) to the I/O lane, while using the step forward to throw as your first step running for the give-go.
Specifically, I try to throw in the space above the mark&amp;rsquo;s shoulder (not too near their face), and I throw down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Consistently</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</guid>
      <description>What I like to do is to not let the mark dictate the throw, but for the thrower to dictate the markers positioning and movements. In doing so, I find teaching young players to break the mark that you must first teach them to make themselves a threat while holding the disc. I consider the way I hold the disc similar to what is called a triple threat in basketball. To me, this means holding the disc in a throwing position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal Is To Make It Easy To Score</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</guid>
      <description>Every time a team moves the disc, this changes the defense. It puts the defensive players out of position, if even for a short period of time. The greater change is better for the offense, and this means putting the disc as far from where the defense wants it to be as possible. If a team is forcing you to throw forehand, and you get a chance to complete a pass straight up field, you just made a good move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shimmy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</guid>
      <description>My favorite move, that is very popular and can be used by any player, is the shimmy flick. This is a move that I was taught at Carleton but is based on principles that I learned in my first sport, basketball. In basketball as a defender, you are always taught to look at the offense&amp;rsquo;s belly-button because that is the hardest part of the body to fake with. You can get faked out if you look at the ball, the player&amp;rsquo;s head, feet or hands, but the belly button&amp;rsquo;s not going anywhere unless the whole player is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Your Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</guid>
      <description>Breaking the mark is key to scoring against solid defense and an important factor to any offense. Here are 5 ways to dictate play and gain an advantage over your mark:
1. Expanding your options early (become more threatening)
Since at the beginning of the game the defense is trying to figure out your strengths and weaknesses to properly apply pressure, this is your opportunity to take advantage and become more threatening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Never Have To Break The Mark If...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</guid>
      <description>There are some basic concepts that everyone talks about to effectively break the mark:
use your core to stay balanced while you fake and pivot to get your marker off balance; learn to fake and throw/release at different heights; engage your marker by drawing them closer or moving them side-to-side with your pivots. However, my favourite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; to teach, regardless of playing level, is how to redefine your throwing lanes when you have the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
