<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alternating Matchups</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s too bad you can&amp;rsquo;t put the World&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Defender on this person, because they sound like they are the World&amp;rsquo;s Best Offensive Player.
I would probably get two defenders to alternate defensive points with the intention of solely guarding this person. Ideally, one defender would be the quick/squirrelly type with a good mark to challenge him around the disc and apply pressure on the mark. The second defender would be fast and preferably able to out-jump this person, with the intention of continuing to push him deep (but maybe not quite as much as in the first half).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box-And-One</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/box-and-one/</guid>
      <description>A player like this, who clearly has multiple offensive weapons, presents a serious match up challenge. Individual defensive match ups are an odd thing, and it can be difficult to predict which defender would be most effective. Given the past experience of this player being most effective as a deep thrower, I would continue to push them away from the disc. I would try different defenders on them until finding a player who could be successful in keeping the player away from the disc, and in containing their deep game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containing A Big Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</guid>
      <description>The best strategy for containing good deep throwers depends in part on the type of handler position they are playing. If the thrower is frequently in a dump reset position, the number one priority must be that he does not get the disc moving up field. A good thrower with momentum and a trailing mark is deadly. You will often find a defender guard this player well for the first two or three resets and then the defender will get impatient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cue The Comeback!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/cue-the-comeback-/</guid>
      <description>Well&amp;hellip;the answer to a situation like this (defending a handler in the lanes) is going to be dependant on a number of factors and variables that are unknown in this scenario (athletic ability, height, speed, etc.). However, in a general sense, if you have one of the main players on the opposing team drastically altering their game due to your defensive strategy then your defensive strategy is effective. Forcing a &amp;ldquo;main handler&amp;rdquo; to strike and cut downfield is a great situation for the defensive team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Goals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</guid>
      <description>On defense, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to shut down all options , because that&amp;rsquo;s impossible against a good offense. Rather, your goal is to dictate to the offense those options it can take. So, the first thing to realize here is: if Big Thrower hasn&amp;rsquo;t been able to make big throws, you&amp;rsquo;ve done something successful.
The question to ask yourself now: Is Big Thrower hurting us more now as a deep receiver than he/she usually does as a thrower?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Opponent Guessing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s question is essentially asking what do you do if your original game plan and strategy for how to play a certain player doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working. In this case, I would consider coming up with multiple different strategies for minimizing that players&amp;rsquo; apparent strengths. Here are four possible strategies (and in the order I would attempt them) for dealing with a player with dominant throws:
1. Front her to try and deny her the disc on any easy pass, forcing her to make plays in a way that is not her preference (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Any Adjustment...Just Make It Now</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</guid>
      <description>This is a very interesting scenario because there are so many adjustments that could be made to respond to this player. You could assign a speedy defender to outrun him on the deep cuts, you could assign a tall defender to pull down floaty passes, you could assign a physical defender to disrupt the flow of his cuts, you could keep playing the same defense on him but put a straight-up mark on everyone else, you could go zone, you could play last back, or you could even throw your scouting report out the window and let him hang around the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It A Team Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</guid>
      <description>They say that coaching is the art of making decisions without statistical significance in the data. Ok, they don&amp;rsquo;t say that&amp;hellip;I say that. We have 6 minutes left in halftime, and our captains are getting together to decide if Big Thrower is just having a great half, or if this is a tactical change. To any reasonable statistical measure, we are flipping a coin here. The data just doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist to tell us for sure whether or not this might happen in the second half, and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a gut call if we want to switch tactics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make The Offense Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Adjustments made before during a game can win&amp;hellip;or lose a game. Pre-game scouting reports or prior encounters can give clues for how each team&amp;rsquo;s offense and defense should come out of the gate. However, there is no substitute for actually playing the game and making real-time evaluations. There is a fine line to walk between jumping the gun on an adjustment and not acting soon enough and I think that one of the hardest jobs of a team strategist is this evaluation and subsequent decision for adjustment or non- adjustment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Lose A Game Without</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</guid>
      <description>As a wise woman once said (props to those who get the joke), never lose a game without playing zone. I think this thought answers the question but taken to a broader sense: never get beat over and over again without changing something.
So your scouting report was wrong or the team has adjusted to all their opponents having the same scouting report on their strong player. This happens very often with great, specialized players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old School Vs. New School</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be two diverging philosophies on how to defend against a very skilled deep thrower that has also hurt you going deep. The first philosophy is perhaps considered old school, focusing on team defense and changing the team&amp;rsquo;s defensive strategy. The second, new school, philosophy is what I like to call the &amp;ldquo;hack-a-Shaq&amp;rdquo; tactic, and although not exactly the same as its namesake, the results are comparable. The hack-a-Shaq consists of intentionally fouling the thrower to significantly disrupt the offensive flow (and deep shot) without consequence to the defending team and, I hate to say, is indelibly efficacious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Your First-Half Performance</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</guid>
      <description>I like to look at the bigger picture before making adjustments for just one player. (This is assuming you have used the same strategy in previous meetings and have been successful).
Assumptions
1. The third goal was scored in the normal flow of the O (whether Man or Zone).
2. Two goals were scored while the D was in a straight man D, ie no zone transition.
3. The game is not determined by the wind, ie a windy upwind/downwind game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Resilient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/stay-resilient/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You take away a team&amp;rsquo;s strength and make them beat you with their weakness. If they do, you make them do it again, because it’s their f***ing weakness!&amp;rdquo; — Jon Gewirtz
This situation is so similar to what Jam did with Damien Scott in the 04 finals that I almost think that &amp;ldquo;The Huddle&amp;rdquo; ripped it right off of the video. All season long, Damien had handled. He wasn’t a great hucker, but he could always get open for a reset and hand a very nice forehand inside out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suggested Team &amp; Individual Tactics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/suggested-team-individual-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/suggested-team-individual-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In ultimate, good offense beats good defense. Defense becomes especially difficult when the opponent has a dynamic player that is both a threat with the disc and down field. Down 8-6 at the half our defensive goal is to make the opponents offense, and most importantly this dynamic player, uncomfortable. We can do this with both team and individual defensive tactics.
Suggested Team Tactics
Zone Defense: Makes the offense complete many throws to score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Answer May Be On The Field Already</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and assume we&amp;rsquo;re pulling, so that will give our guy what we hope to be two chances to make up for the first half, even the score, and allow us to see if what was said at halftime served any purpose; or was the guy simply standing there nodding his head like a boxer, in one ear and out the other, all the while wondering if he should&amp;rsquo;ve run off to the Honey Bucket or maybe he should put on a different wrist band, maybe someone has some tape he can borrow, maybe some Gu will help, maybe some Red Bull, maybe he should go mess around in his bag and look for something he knows isn&amp;rsquo;t there—the things they didn&amp;rsquo;t carry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do They Want To Do?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-do-they-want-to-do-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-do-they-want-to-do-/</guid>
      <description>Whenever lining up against a gifted opponent I have always found it helpful to ask myself: what does this player want to do? In this case, this player is most comfortable and probably most confident in a handler role, staying behind the disc and throwing goals rather than receiving them. When playing against teams that have a player like this, someone who excels in many aspects, always make them beat you with their Plan B or Plan C, never Plan A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Concede &amp; What To Take Away</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</guid>
      <description>This one is pretty straightforward: as with any player, you have to determine what you want to give up and what you want to take away (or try to, anyway). You&amp;rsquo;re going to want to deny any player&amp;rsquo;s greatest strength or whatever facet of his game is capable of hurting you most. If this guy has beaten you repeatedly with his throws, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a very good idea to allow him to get the disc underneath - even if he has caught a couple hucks today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
