<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Wiggins on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ben-wiggins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ben Wiggins on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ben-wiggins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Will Laugh</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</guid>
      <description>Within 5 years, I firmly believe that we will look back on the warm-ups we use now and laugh. This isn&amp;rsquo;t true for every team, but I think that most high- level teams are warming up in ways that are more similar than they are different. Team huddle, jogging, stretching, plyos, throwing, catching drills, personal time, huck drills, 7v7, pre-game huddle, cheer, etc, etc. And those combined similarities are holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes Are Precious</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</guid>
      <description>Minutes at practice are precious. Here are my 5 relatively simple ways to maximize the amount of growth you can foster from each of your practices. At the end, I&amp;rsquo;ve included an example set of 3 practices to try and illustrate these points.
1) Use your warm-up time effectively
Warm-ups take a large percentage of total practice time. To focus that effort, I like to include warm-up drills or games that give a good mental introduction to the purpose of later practice drills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Do</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-we-do/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll let better writers and players describe why Spirit is, or is not, worth your time. I know my answer, and you have to find your own.
If you come away having decided that it is worth your your effort, here are a couple of things that your team can do to improve your own Spirit on the field in meaningful games. At the very least, they are things that my teams have done in the past that have helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Point Guard&#34; Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</guid>
      <description>When I play, I often pick up the disc after a turnover. When I coach, my teams are in this situation often (as Lou noted, college teams have dead-disc situations much more frequently than in club Ultimate). Given the inherent confusion of the moment, I value a simple communication system in order to create positive and coordinated disc movement in a chaotic environment.
I really don&amp;rsquo;t care if everyone on the team can call plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Example: Defending The Dump</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had some success teaching team D in the past, and I like to think that young players, especially bright ones, will often surprise you with their ability to learn complex concepts and make them work against very good offensive players and teams.
One example of our team-D philosophy is in how we taught dump D at U of Oregon. This would usually happen at some point during February or March, after the basics of defense and offense but before the real tournament schedule got up to speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Without Breaking A Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</guid>
      <description>The following is a couple of thoughts from a handler/team perspective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly what we asked our authors to write about (but we thought it appropriate to add in here). I first wrote this article in 2004, in response to this comment on rec.sport.disc:
&amp;gt; &amp;gt;scoring in the endzone is easy. just break the mark.
Yes, this will probably work most of the time. I think that the intrinsic difficulty in End Zone O is the pressure on the offense to score; the idea that &amp;ldquo;most of the time&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Couple Of Thoughts On Zone D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/a-couple-of-thoughts-on-zone-d/</guid>
      <description>A couple of quick thoughts.
Sidelines are great for communication, but the people that need to be able to talk to each other are all on the field already. In a standard three-person cup, the communication streams are simple:
Deep talks to wings and short-deep Short-deep talks to points and middle Middle talks to points Wings talk to their side&amp;rsquo;s point With these streams, each player can adjust the positioning of the players they are covering for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Coach Arambula Is Preaching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</guid>
      <description>Is footwork important? Only if winning games is important. Ultimate, maybe more than any sport, has layers of pretty arm and upper-body movement that disguise a game primarily decided by feet. Basketball is right up there.
As a handler, I get lots of different body-types defending me during big games. I&amp;rsquo;m just as likely to look across the line and see Jit (Revolver&amp;rsquo;s tiny handler-defender extraordinaire) as I am to see some massive athlete that I have no hope of running with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Texas Hold&#39;em Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</guid>
      <description>Deep D is a lot like poker in three significant ways:
1. Information is more important than anything else.
2. You play the hand you are dealt, and try to win more than your share given the cards in your hand.
3. It ain&amp;rsquo;t over until til it&amp;rsquo;s over.
Information: As I turn to head deep and hear that &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call, I need to get a read on the disc as quickly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It A Team Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-it-a-team-game/</guid>
      <description>They say that coaching is the art of making decisions without statistical significance in the data. Ok, they don&amp;rsquo;t say that&amp;hellip;I say that. We have 6 minutes left in halftime, and our captains are getting together to decide if Big Thrower is just having a great half, or if this is a tactical change. To any reasonable statistical measure, we are flipping a coin here. The data just doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist to tell us for sure whether or not this might happen in the second half, and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a gut call if we want to switch tactics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective From The Team &amp; From A Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</guid>
      <description>A couple of thoughts that I always have when tryouts roll around:
Any young player that wants to improve should be trying out for any team possible. Tryout ultimate is typically intense, cheap, and with players that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally play with. This can be an amazing opportunity to improve&amp;hellip;especially with experienced players available that are motivated (or at least ready) to give constructive feedback. This can be a great opportunity for developing players, regardless of your own chances of making the team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
