<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Downfield 1-On-1 Defense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re downfield, the disc has stopped, and you&amp;rsquo;re defending a cutter in the middle of a flat stack. You&amp;rsquo;ll need all the speed, agility, and strength you have—long before the point begins you can better your odds by improving your physical ability. Chances are if you are reading this you know how.
Although Ultimate is a team game, the flat stack does a good job at isolating one-on-one matchups. While switching and poaching can work against weaker offensive teams, intelligent ones will be able to change the position of both the disc and their cutters quicker than you can react, and will beat your defense without much effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Should Be Intentional</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/everything-should-be-intentional/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/everything-should-be-intentional/</guid>
      <description>If I was teaching a young player to learn to cut from the &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or iso&amp;rsquo;ed positions in the middle of a horizontal stack, I would emphasize a few keys points, which are generally applicable to getting open on a stopped disc within any offensive structure, but are particularly important for a horizontal offense. The points I make are assuming that the defense is not poaching, as cutting against a poaching defense would require a more in-depth discussion of how to run a horizontal offense in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Easy Steps</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/five-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/five-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>1st: Narrow the gap between you and your defender and engage him. If you get him on his heels then you can cut where ever you please.
2nd: Clear Out! It is much easier to cut from the side positions in the horizontal, as long as the middle is vacated. Make room for your teammates to get open.
3rd: Become a side cutter. Observe the field see who is going to get the disc, get your self out of the way and be aware of where your defender is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It All Comes Back To Throwing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/it-all-comes-back-to-throwing/</guid>
      <description>The most important piece to an effective initiation cut is the thrower. To get open, you need to be able to challenge the defender into at least two different places. In the typical flat-stack set, there are three spaces open to the interior cutters: open-side, break-side, and deep. If the thrower can hit all of those spots, getting open is no problem. Fake to one of them, cut to another. Throw, catch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sockeye&#39;s Wheelhouse</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/sockeye-s-wheelhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/sockeye-s-wheelhouse/</guid>
      <description>Cutting from the middle in a horizontal stack is a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, you have the freedom to cut in any direction, your defender is on an island with no deep help, and the offense is looking to you to make a play. Awesome.
On the other hand, the flat stack presents some unique challenges for cutters. I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on the unpredictability of the flat stack as a cutting problem, and explain a couple simple adjustments that address this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Keys To Being A Good Middle</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</guid>
      <description>I can think of three main points that will help you when you are trying to get open in the middle of a horizontal stack. The first is that your team needs to put the right type of player in that position. In my opinion, this is a player who is confident with the disc, is a threat as a deep thrower, and understands how to get open both going deep and coming under.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Offensive Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</guid>
      <description>As a defender this is one of the most uncomfortable positions to defend if the stack is well-spaced and with just the right depth to make both the deep cut and the underneath cut a viable option. If the disc is in the middle of the field (say at the brickmark), and your cutter is on the open side of the horizontal stack, there is a lot of space to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use On-Field Cues</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</guid>
      <description>Cutting from the middle of the flat stack requires good field sense. In my mind, good field sense involves the ability to accurately read three things simultaneously: reading the defense, reading the thrower, and reading the spaces on the field.
I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone has heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;take what the defense gives you.&amp;rdquo; This important concept necessitates knowing what your defender is trying to take away at any given moment. At its most basic level, you have to recognize the force and figure out which direction your D is trying to push your cut (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
