<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nancy Sun on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/nancy-sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nancy Sun on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/nancy-sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2¢ On Hucking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</guid>
      <description>When I think about throwing long, it helps me to visualize a spring in action. I try to activate four parts of my body that act as springs: legs, hips, shoulders, elbow, and wrist. As I wind up for the throw, I think about compressing these springs in turn and as I throw, I think about releasing each of the springs. The legs are an important part of the step; I step out as far as I can to still feel completely balanced throughout the throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull &amp; Transitions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</guid>
      <description>Catching The Pull
Mentally, catching the pull is often thought of as being a job that one can only mess up, but the flip side is to think of it as an opportunity for a team to jump start its offense. The seconds saved by catching the pull help to get the offense in motion before the defense can set. I think of three main steps when catching the pull:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipating The Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</guid>
      <description>One of the attributes of teams that do well at Nationals and other high-level tournaments is their handler defense. Many teams can do a pretty good job at containing handlers (e.g. getting the mark on to stop upfield break throws, adjusting to stop give-go&amp;rsquo;s, preventing up-the-line cuts). However, I think there are only a few teams that have the personnel and strategy to consistently pressure and generate D&amp;rsquo;s on handler resets—this includes pressure on both the thrower who may or may not be a handler, and on the actual handler who makes the reset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make The Offense Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-the-offense-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Adjustments made before during a game can win&amp;hellip;or lose a game. Pre-game scouting reports or prior encounters can give clues for how each team&amp;rsquo;s offense and defense should come out of the gate. However, there is no substitute for actually playing the game and making real-time evaluations. There is a fine line to walk between jumping the gun on an adjustment and not acting soon enough and I think that one of the hardest jobs of a team strategist is this evaluation and subsequent decision for adjustment or non- adjustment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Fundamentals Trump Team Needs</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</guid>
      <description>Tryouts are such a weird time for me. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting the season is starting and so many people want to tryout for our team, but at the same time the decisions can be stressful and as much pressure as one might feel when trying out, the team is also some amount of pressure on the team being tried out to find a good fit. Since there are a few different options in Boston, it is very important for our team to put our best foot forward and we try to do it as accurately as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
