<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gwen Ambler on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/gwen-ambler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gwen Ambler on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/gwen-ambler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</guid>
      <description>As others have mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s highly important to catch the pull whenever possible. In the Women&amp;rsquo;s game, far too many players let the pull hit the ground if it comes in at a hard angle. As a puller, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to take advantage of this by working on big outside-in pulls to gain an extra second or two while the player stops a roll and picks up the disc, possibly gain field position if the player misreads how the disc will roll, and give the offense a wet disc to work with if there&amp;rsquo;s dew on the grass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidbits</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of marking tidbits I&amp;rsquo;ve heard and dispensed over the years. I find myself repeatedly coming back to four in particular. Two of these pieces of wisdom have come from amazing coaches, one is from a legendary point-block machine, and one is from observations of what makes the biggest difference in my own marking.
From Jennifer &amp;ldquo;JD&amp;rdquo; Donnelly (while coaching Stanford Superfly): Your mark should take into account body mechanics and reaction time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well-Rounded Deep Threats</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/well-rounded-deep-threats/</guid>
      <description>In my experience, the toughest match-ups on receivers are against those players that are as big a threat going deep as they are coming under. Playing defense against a player like this, it is not obvious how you should play them. If you force them away, they&amp;rsquo;ll burn you deep and/or sky you for the score, but if you force them in, they&amp;rsquo;ll have a chance to use their throws to put the disc into the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use On-Field Cues</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/use-on-field-cues/</guid>
      <description>Cutting from the middle of the flat stack requires good field sense. In my mind, good field sense involves the ability to accurately read three things simultaneously: reading the defense, reading the thrower, and reading the spaces on the field.
I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone has heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;take what the defense gives you.&amp;rdquo; This important concept necessitates knowing what your defender is trying to take away at any given moment. At its most basic level, you have to recognize the force and figure out which direction your D is trying to push your cut (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Every Huck</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</guid>
      <description>I think a lot of people focus too much on how to throw the disc far rather than on how to complete their hucks. A lot of time, players will spend hours practicing throwing the disc really far, but then they don&amp;rsquo;t make disciplined decisions during a game about when to use those hucks. There are three questions to ask yourself before unleashing any bomb if you want to increase the chances of completing that huck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Checklist</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is probably the least rewarding aspect of Ultimate. Not only will you rarely be recognized for good sub-calling, but instead sub-calling is the easiest thing for many people to blame for problems on the field. Additionally, problems (real or perceived) with playing time and sub-calling are often the number one issue affecting team dynamics and player satisfaction. In my experience, the easiest way to avoid issues with subcalling is to have a plan ahead of time and to communicate as best as possible to individuals where their role fits into that plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipation &amp; Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</guid>
      <description>I am a firm believer that anticipation and focus are the most important elements for successful catching. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to others to discuss the finer points of catching techniques.
For anticipation, not only do you want to anticipate where the disc is headed, but you have to prepare your body for an anticipated catch. Anticipating the disc&amp;rsquo;s path is basically reading the disc. You need to be able to judge accurately how fast the disc is traveling and along what trajectory so that you can meet it at the best point possible, which is usually the earliest point possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Opponent Guessing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/keep-your-opponent-guessing/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s question is essentially asking what do you do if your original game plan and strategy for how to play a certain player doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working. In this case, I would consider coming up with multiple different strategies for minimizing that players&amp;rsquo; apparent strengths. Here are four possible strategies (and in the order I would attempt them) for dealing with a player with dominant throws:
1. Front her to try and deny her the disc on any easy pass, forcing her to make plays in a way that is not her preference (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cater to Your Team&#39;s Particular Skills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</guid>
      <description>Any offense is difficult in the wind, so when conditions are windy a team should play the offense that it has practiced the most. Both vertical and horizontal stack offenses have advantages and disadvantages in the wind and the decision to play one over the other depends on how well your team can be on the same page while running it&amp;rsquo;s O.
When my team first made the transition from vertical stack to horizontal stack back in 2005, we struggled in the wind and often would switch back to the vert stack when it was windy and we were having difficulty scoring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
