<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greg Husak on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/greg-husak/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greg Husak on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/greg-husak/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Team On One Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</guid>
      <description>The pre-game warmup can take on any number of forms, and I have seen successful routines span a huge range, from individual to team wide and from fully choreographed to ad hoc. In all cases, the general goal of the warmup should be to get the body ready to perform at a peak performance. This will require people to exert some energy, get a light sweat on and get the muscles firing, and should also include a few throws to help players calibrate to the conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Focus, Full Effort</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</guid>
      <description>When planning a practice, it is important to think about the personnel and goals of a practice. For instance, a fall practice for a college team is going to have very different objectives than a fall practice for an elite open team. The college team might be trying to have a lot of fun to &amp;ldquo;set the hook&amp;rdquo; with new players and give a lot of reps to players still learning the game, while an elite team is tuning up for the peak of their season and should be focusing on consistent execution of skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing A Team Way Of Communicating</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</guid>
      <description>Different teams have a very different approach to the role of individuals when they’re on the sideline. Some teams like to give the players on the sideline a chance to rest and have them sit in the shade to recover for their next time in the game. Others, especially in the college ranks, can have countless players making tons of useless noise from the sidelines. I think the best teams find a way to keep players involved in the success of the team when they are not one of the seven guys on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding The Information</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/understanding-the-information/</guid>
      <description>Understanding positioning and distribution of players on the field is an important skill, but also somewhat of an innate ability. How this skill manifests itself is sometimes subtle and other times overt. It can show up in the guy who always seems to be making the good cut to keep the offensive flow going or in the physically ungifted player who consistently finds themselves alone in the endzone. It can be the thrower who is able to find targets on the goal line or the defender who gets a lot of poach blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain&#39;s Big Assist From The Weather</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-s-big-assist-from-the-weather/</guid>
      <description>After twelve straight years as a nationals participant in the Open division (1997-2008), in 2009 as a masters player was a different experience. First, few people, and really nobody outside the division itself, care much about the Masters division. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say it isn&amp;rsquo;t competitive, or even that there isn&amp;rsquo;t good Ultimate being played there, it&amp;rsquo;s just that when you have the Open nationals to watch, why would you watch Masters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respond As It Comes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</guid>
      <description>The best offensive teams can get big yards from the first few passes off a pull, and immediately knock the defense on its heels. There are no shortage of ways to do this, and the best offenses I have been a part of have always had a few options for taking this advantage.
In all cases the critical first component is having a player who feels comfortable catching the pull and throwing the first pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Advantage Of The Given Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</guid>
      <description>Rotating the mark can be a very effective strategy against teams that effectively use the reset to work the disc upfield when the initial cut isn&amp;rsquo;t open. This defense works best when it has the element of surprise behind it. However, like many defenses, if offenses recognize that this strategy is being used they can develop a plan to counter it.
The easiest thing to think about is what the defense gives up when they implement this strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning &amp; Approach</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</guid>
      <description>While we call these hangers &amp;ldquo;50/50 discs,&amp;rdquo; I would bet that at the moment the disc is coming down an observer would have a better than coin-flip chance of guessing who will touch the disc first. Keying in on the information informing that decision will help guide a player in giving themselves a better than coin-flip chance of getting to it first.
I think that beyond obvious physical differences (&amp;ldquo;I like the guy who is 6&#39;8&amp;rdquo; over the short guy&amp;quot;) the two main components are positioning and approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One At A Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>One thing I remember an old teammate saying was that &amp;ldquo;there are no four- pointers in Ultimate.&amp;rdquo; What he meant was that you&amp;rsquo;re not going to bridge the gap in one play, so you have to stay with the gameplan and keep doing the things that your team needs to do to play their best.
The first key is to make sure that your offense is going to score every time they receive, because the worst thing for the team would be to add another break, which only lengthens the odds of a comeback while also being demoralizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value Of A Layout Block?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m frequently torn between the value of a layout block versus just shutting your guy down to the point that he&amp;rsquo;s not thrown to. Layout blocks, at least at the elite level, are typically the result of a bad decision or throw by the thrower, because it is very tough to get around elite receivers, and you&amp;rsquo;re generally just not going to make up enough ground to go from a guy being open to you blocking him unless the throw is in a bad spot or the receiver does a terrible job of sealing you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions About Your Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/questions-about-your-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of ways to try to approximate the weather approximations that a zone offense will face. Some of these strengthen the defense such as adding an 8th player to the d or shortening the stall count while others might hamper the offense no overheads or huck limits.
There is really no good way to approximate inclement weather for the offense, but at some point you can handcuff the offense enough that when they face a weather situation with standard playing conditions they will feel that things are easy, and really that is the goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations To Matchup Theory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/limitations-to-matchup-theory/</guid>
      <description>Defensive matchups can be a positive aspect of successfully implementing a defensive strategy, but they can also serve to be a limitation. There are certain instances where a defender just has another players number and as a team you would be foolish to not consider that, but if you let certain matchups become the focus of the defensive strategy it may prevent you from running the defenses that are most successful for the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Lane Theory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/three-lane-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/three-lane-theory/</guid>
      <description>I tend to think of the Ultimate field in three lanes running down the field. When the disc is in one of the side lanes, you really only have that lane and the middle lane available, as throws to the far lane are quite risky. Sometimes focusing on just two lanes can mean that you reduce the complexity for the thrower and the offense, and it limits the angles that poachers can come from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needs Of The Team And The Individual</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</guid>
      <description>Role players are valuable to any successful team. More than valuable, they may be essential. This is typically because they have the ability to throw their whole effort into a part of the game that the stars don&amp;rsquo;t have the effort for. An obvious example of this is a marker in the zone. Marking takes a lot of effort, and is very tiring both because of chasing the disc around, but also because working hard on the mark takes a lot of energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Offensive Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/understanding-offensive-priorities/</guid>
      <description>As a defender this is one of the most uncomfortable positions to defend if the stack is well-spaced and with just the right depth to make both the deep cut and the underneath cut a viable option. If the disc is in the middle of the field (say at the brickmark), and your cutter is on the open side of the horizontal stack, there is a lot of space to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering The Team With Self Subbing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been very fortunate in my career to play on many successful teams that did not call subs, and this hypothetical situation could be a blessing in disguise. Most players at elite levels are fairly self-aware, and after a season of playing together most can recognize the hierarchy within the team and could make an honest appraisal of their optimum contribution to the team in terms of quantity and type (O or D) of points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Ideas</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The fundamental catch most players at the elite level of the game is one where you are running hard back to the disc with a defender on your back pressing you to keep your maximum speed until after the reception. The basic component to catching this is the mentality of attacking the disc.
I have seen many players drop this by trying to finesse the Frisbee into their hands rather than aggressively securing it, whether with a &amp;ldquo;clap catch&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;tiger claw&amp;rdquo; technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redistribute Their Resources</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/redistribute-their-resources/</guid>
      <description>I believe that it is impossible to design a zone (or any defense for that matter) that takes away everything. If I knew that zone I would never lose a game. I think the important thing about a zone is to make sure that everyone is clear of what the zone&amp;rsquo;s objectives are, and when they are forced to make a decision on the field, they do it within the context of that zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance &amp; Explosiveness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</guid>
      <description>I still remember being at Worlds in 1999 in Scotland and it was sort of the debut of Fortunat Mueller with Boston. He was a young workhorse at that time and DoG knew how to use him, as he was probably catching half their goals. I remember watching a pool play game of theirs and a more experienced player pointing out his footwork, how he was always on balance. While we had begun some very basic footwork drills, it was the first time I remember noticing someone&amp;rsquo;s footwork in a game situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Prescribed Rotation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</guid>
      <description>In this situation, it seems that it would be best to prescribe some movement, team-wide, which will give the thrower some better options than &amp;ldquo;turn to the dump.&amp;rdquo; Expressing some coordinated movement where all players (or at least those around the disc) have certain responsibilities will help clear up confusion and provide purpose to people&amp;rsquo;s movement.
On a previous team I played for, we had very specific dump rotations, and we ran a specific rotation for the first half and then switched that movement at halftime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Defensive Speed</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</guid>
      <description>There is a big factor that comes into play here that I should use to set the stage:
Why are big time football receivers 6&#39;2&amp;quot; or 6&#39;3&amp;quot; and 220lbs (think Terrell Owens), while big time defensive backs are 5&#39;10&amp;quot; or 5&#39;11&amp;quot; and 190lbs?
And: Why does it generally seem that DBs are the fastest guys, but you routinely see them getting beat deep by receivers who should be slower?
There are two speeds that ultimate defenders (and football defenders) have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go After Similar, More Experienced Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</guid>
      <description>I think the first thing that a player should evaluate is their own talents and strengths. During the tryout you should be focusing on accentuating those strengths when given the chance. If you&amp;rsquo;re a tall deep threat, don&amp;rsquo;t waste time in a scrimmage squirelling around the disc, and in any huck drill make sure you are going up strong to show that you can climb. If you&amp;rsquo;re a squirrely quick guy, make sure you are getting open on all short cuts, and that if there are any sprints to be done that you are winning them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience &amp; Coordination</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</guid>
      <description>To my eyes, the advantage of the spread/horizontal is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a whole group of people working together, but can be effective by working in just pairs of upfield cutters or on occasion an isolated receiver. Of course, the better teams will have coordination of all the players, but for a young team, or a team using a new system, things can get up and running effectively with the horizontal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
