<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VY Chow on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/vy-chow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VY Chow on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/vy-chow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Never Have To Break The Mark If...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/you-never-have-to-break-the-mark-if-/</guid>
      <description>There are some basic concepts that everyone talks about to effectively break the mark:
use your core to stay balanced while you fake and pivot to get your marker off balance; learn to fake and throw/release at different heights; engage your marker by drawing them closer or moving them side-to-side with your pivots. However, my favourite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; to teach, regardless of playing level, is how to redefine your throwing lanes when you have the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Screw The Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</guid>
      <description>Team defense begins with an understanding and analysis of the strengths and weaknesses of your team&amp;rsquo;s defensive talents, followed by the development of defensive philosophies that are executed by specific team-oriented strategy. Too often, &amp;ldquo;team defense&amp;rdquo; is taught in terms of situational defensive sets such as zone, clam, poaching, and whatnot with an over-reliance on individual athleticism to play man-D. While high-flying layout blocks are at times warranted and necessary, it appears the spectacular has come to define a team&amp;rsquo;s defensive prowess along with foot-races and gravity-defying leaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old School Vs. New School</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/old-school-vs-new-school/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be two diverging philosophies on how to defend against a very skilled deep thrower that has also hurt you going deep. The first philosophy is perhaps considered old school, focusing on team defense and changing the team&amp;rsquo;s defensive strategy. The second, new school, philosophy is what I like to call the &amp;ldquo;hack-a-Shaq&amp;rdquo; tactic, and although not exactly the same as its namesake, the results are comparable. The hack-a-Shaq consists of intentionally fouling the thrower to significantly disrupt the offensive flow (and deep shot) without consequence to the defending team and, I hate to say, is indelibly efficacious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
