<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decisiveness Leads To Glory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/decisiveness-leads-to-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/decisiveness-leads-to-glory/</guid>
      <description>Goal line cutting starts with decisiveness and ends in glory—either for your or your teammates.
When your team moves into its red zone offense, begin by moving quickly into position. Your speed getting into position will determine whether they are going to stay with you or leave you and poach the lane. When you sprint to your attack point, your defender will instinctively feel like you are a threat and attempt to stay with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Defensive Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/exploiting-defensive-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/exploiting-defensive-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>When you transition from open field cutting to goal-line cutting, two major things change: (1) you are no longer a deep threat, and (2) a throw that gains only a few yards can be very advantageous. Both of these factors change how the defense will play you. For instance, many defenders will get closer to you, get physical, and perhaps force you away from the thrower with their body position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Quadrants</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/field-quadrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/field-quadrants/</guid>
      <description>Really, long points are earned at practice and at the track, well before the specific moment arrives on a Sunday afternoon.
It&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to think about being a successful endzone cutter as a personal achievement. More than any other position on the field, having the disc near the goal line requires a full team effort to create a good scoring chance. Stack discipline and spacing are crucial to avoiding clogged lanes and disruptive picks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Thrower, Make It Easy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about cutting in the endzone, the first thing to consider is if you even should cut. You have to assess where the space is and the convenience of your angle to that space. You need to know who your thrower is and what they are comfortable with (if you cut to where you intend to cut, will the thrower have the throw to hit you accurately enough for it to be a score?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Move</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m usually thinking, &amp;ldquo;Get open on the open side.&amp;rdquo;
When fatigue sets in, throws and finesse are the first thing to go and open side throws are generally easier. Cutters can push through fatigue with desire and brute strength. So, to get open on the open side, I usually start facing the thrower, juke hard toward the defender (they are on their heels), take a few steps really hard to the break side (this usually lures the off-balance defender to commit to the break side), then explode past them to the open side (this may require some stepping past/running through limbs of your defender).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Versus Efficient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</guid>
      <description>From an elementary basketball analogy (sorry readership to those that know a lot about basketball), if everyone is doing their job, the point guard is keeping the ball alive and getting it into the post when available for the forwards and center to finish off. Much like this, in open field, the handlers are keeping the disc alive and looking to get it to the cutters whenever available. To this end, the cutters are the primary workhorses during this phase of the offense by getting the big gains and opening up the downfield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Without Breaking A Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/scoring-without-breaking-a-mark/</guid>
      <description>The following is a couple of thoughts from a handler/team perspective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly what we asked our authors to write about (but we thought it appropriate to add in here). I first wrote this article in 2004, in response to this comment on rec.sport.disc:
&amp;gt; &amp;gt;scoring in the endzone is easy. just break the mark.
Yes, this will probably work most of the time. I think that the intrinsic difficulty in End Zone O is the pressure on the offense to score; the idea that &amp;ldquo;most of the time&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing Is Everything</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/timing-is-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/timing-is-everything/</guid>
      <description>Goal line cutting (especially in the elite division) is a difficult technique to master. The fact is, the closer you get to the endzone, the more effective a defensive player can be because you are shortening the field and removing the threat of a deep cut. In general, the offense always has the advantage, but close to the endzone, your advantage as a cutter is lessened.
All organized teams usually have a specific endzone offense that they default to when they get within ten yards or less of the goal line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Do When The Field Shrinks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/what-to-do-when-the-field-shrinks/</guid>
      <description>The field shrinks when you reach the endzone.
Your defender no longer has to worry about your deep cuts, and so can front you by a larger margin. The pressure builds- a turnover here in the &amp;ldquo;red zone&amp;rdquo; seems particularly disheartening. All of a sudden, everyone is cutting at once, forgetting about rules and technique, just anxious to get the disc and finish the point.
However, it is precisely here in the red zone that it becomes all the more important to remember your team&amp;rsquo;s strategies and offense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
