<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anticipation &amp; Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/anticipation-focus/</guid>
      <description>I am a firm believer that anticipation and focus are the most important elements for successful catching. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to others to discuss the finer points of catching techniques.
For anticipation, not only do you want to anticipate where the disc is headed, but you have to prepare your body for an anticipated catch. Anticipating the disc&amp;rsquo;s path is basically reading the disc. You need to be able to judge accurately how fast the disc is traveling and along what trajectory so that you can meet it at the best point possible, which is usually the earliest point possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Positioning On The Comeback Cut</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</guid>
      <description>The best thing I ever heard of for improving your receiving skills is this game called &amp;ldquo;catch&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s no replacement for repetition. You just have to do it over and over until you forget what it&amp;rsquo;s like to drop a frisbee.
The next step is simulating game situations. Personally, I feel like the most valuable catch to be 100% on is the in-cut: running full speed toward a disc coming at you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull &amp; Transitions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/catching-the-pull-transitions/</guid>
      <description>Catching The Pull
Mentally, catching the pull is often thought of as being a job that one can only mess up, but the flip side is to think of it as an opportunity for a team to jump start its offense. The seconds saved by catching the pull help to get the offense in motion before the defense can set. I think of three main steps when catching the pull:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate The Unforced Turnover</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</guid>
      <description>Catching technique and practice are often overlooked components of player development. Catching instructions generally begin and end with a demonstration of the pancake catch and calls to &amp;ldquo;use two hands,&amp;rdquo; with players left to their own devices to improve their catching through repetitions. As a coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have developed a more proactive approach to teaching catching.
The reason for this is that drops are unforced turnovers that are preventable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting An Extra Foot Of Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</guid>
      <description>I think that for me, the main catching technique that can be practiced (and that I have learned from coaches and taught to players) is attacking the discs with two hands, thumbs down claw-style. When I was in high school, my coach Michael Baccarini used to always say that any catch you can clap, you can catch at least a foot further in front of you if you reach out with your pinchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/honing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>Catching the disc is all about practice. If a situation comes up in a game, it&amp;rsquo;ll be much easier if you&amp;rsquo;ve done it a hundred times in practice than if it&amp;rsquo;s totally foreign to you. What that means is that you need to practice catching in game situations, not just easy, uncovered, and standing still. Practice catching the disc out in front of you, practice catching with a defender on your back, off-hand catches, in the wind, hammers, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making It Routine</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</guid>
      <description>In the sixth grade, I played YMCA basketball and was coached by my classmate/neighbor&amp;rsquo;s father. His sadistic assistant used to routinely fire passes at Billy Nesbitt&amp;rsquo;s head because Billy had such terrible hands; his poor hands caused his braces to cause his mouth to bleed. Sobbing, snot, and blood are not too fun to witness when you&amp;rsquo;re in sixth grade. I never wanted to be anything like poor Billy. I think he&amp;rsquo;s an orthodontist now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Ideas</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/practice-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The fundamental catch most players at the elite level of the game is one where you are running hard back to the disc with a defender on your back pressing you to keep your maximum speed until after the reception. The basic component to catching this is the mentality of attacking the disc.
I have seen many players drop this by trying to finesse the Frisbee into their hands rather than aggressively securing it, whether with a &amp;ldquo;clap catch&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;tiger claw&amp;rdquo; technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regimented Catching Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</guid>
      <description>Just like throwing, catching comes from practice.
How often do you see someone throwing before a game focus really hard on the throw and not on the catch? You&amp;rsquo;ll hear this player swear and scream when they miss a throw, and then catch the throw that came back with one hand while joking with the person next to them.
On Z, we used to do the a throwing medley at the start of every practice and every game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Catching: Two Drills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/teaching-catching-two-drills/</guid>
      <description>It is a common misperception that catching cannot be taught. Learning how to catch comes down to repetition and focus. Here are two quick drills for teaching new players to catch and for honing experienced players&amp;rsquo; skills.
The first drill (unnamed) involves two people and ten (or more) discs. The players (thrower and catcher) stand about two yards apart. The thrower tosses disc after disc to the catcher. The thrower should place the discs so that the catcher is forced to catch high, low, left, right, one- and two-handed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
