<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An In-Cut Adjustment Illustrated</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember ever thinking &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a layout block&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I need to be in a position to get a layout block on this throw.&amp;rdquo; My goal was simply to be in the best position I could be in to cover the person who was my responsibility at the time. I believe that layout blocks are simply &amp;lsquo;opportunities taken&amp;rsquo;—being in the right place at the right time, and the offense made just enough of a mistake for you to go get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baiting</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</guid>
      <description>This is a skill that many of the top defenders possess which generates lots of lay out blocks. There are 3 key components to a successful baited block.
1. Knowing the offense (thrower/cutter)
To many, this is just knowing how far away you can let your player get before you can&amp;rsquo;t make up the ground in time to get a bid on the pass. Knowing how much ground you can make up on your player when the disc goes up is the most important part to knowing the offense; if you can&amp;rsquo;t regain the ground when the disc is thrown, you surely won&amp;rsquo;t get the block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bide Your Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</guid>
      <description>D, they say, is for dummies. But no D player worth their salt should have the ability to do anything more than stare at their big toe Saturday night at the hotel. Why? Because they should be too mentally taxed from keeping the stall count each time they step on the field for D. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about counting the stall when marking your assignment; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about keeping the stall when playing D in the stack or spread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</guid>
      <description>The skill I&amp;rsquo;ve used most and tried to teach my players more than any other part of getting a layout block (aside from the obvious WANTING IT BAD part) is the footwork required to get a layout block. The obvious problem about getting a layout D is that you are trying to get to something that is being blocked by your offense&amp;rsquo;s body. I think getting a layout D without getting called for a foul/hurting anyone is huge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get A Layout Block</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/how-to-get-a-layout-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/how-to-get-a-layout-block/</guid>
      <description>In the perfect defensive scenario, no one ever has to get a layout block. The marker does a great job of taking away part of the field and preventing hucks. Lane cutter defenders deny any open space to downfield receivers and when the count is getting higher, the dump defender stuffs the reset option. The thrower is left with nothing and quietly puts down the disc after hearing the word ten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition &amp; Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</guid>
      <description>Two key factors of getting a block are:
Being able to recognize mistakes by the offense Being in a good position to capitalize upon them Being faster than the person you&amp;rsquo;re guarding helps, but paying attention to these two aspects will help your team defensively.
When it comes to positioning, as a defender I rarely bait throws in anticipation of a layout block, especially when it comes to cuts that are close to the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Glory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</guid>
      <description>Ah the layout block, the play that got you started, the one you still dream about, the slam dunk of our game. Or maybe the three-pointer.
On a bad throw everyone can get what looks like a good block. That&amp;rsquo;s why you play summer league. But when teams are executing well, coming up with a piece is tough. Don&amp;rsquo;t over-commit to laying out or you will end up getting burned on jukes and lying on the ground as the person you are supposed to cover has a free throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Grail Of This Sport</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</guid>
      <description>Like all things holy, the more you try to explain it with words, the farther you get from its essence&amp;hellip;
Look: If you are on the field and thinking about getting a layout block, you&amp;rsquo;re likely not playing good defense. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is a recipe for getting a layout block . I suppose you could practice, and I have seen people working on their diving and landing techniques. But it also requires a tremendous amount of luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value Of A Layout Block?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-value-of-a-layout-block-/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m frequently torn between the value of a layout block versus just shutting your guy down to the point that he&amp;rsquo;s not thrown to. Layout blocks, at least at the elite level, are typically the result of a bad decision or throw by the thrower, because it is very tough to get around elite receivers, and you&amp;rsquo;re generally just not going to make up enough ground to go from a guy being open to you blocking him unless the throw is in a bad spot or the receiver does a terrible job of sealing you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
