<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Find What Works For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>We all know how exciting it is to play Ultimate, and we all know what it feels like to have those butterflies before game time. Having a well executed pre- game warm-up can literally mean the difference, in my opinion, between winning or losing the game. Setting the appropriate tone for game time is essential because this game we play is at least 80% mental. Here are a few things to keep in mind when you are creating a warm-up:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Team On One Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/get-your-team-on-one-page/</guid>
      <description>The pre-game warmup can take on any number of forms, and I have seen successful routines span a huge range, from individual to team wide and from fully choreographed to ad hoc. In all cases, the general goal of the warmup should be to get the body ready to perform at a peak performance. This will require people to exert some energy, get a light sweat on and get the muscles firing, and should also include a few throws to help players calibrate to the conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing For The Game At Hand</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/preparing-for-the-game-at-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/preparing-for-the-game-at-hand/</guid>
      <description>There are many strategies for trying to prepare your team to get properly warmed up. I will hit on the main scenario for pre-game warm-up- preparing for the first game of the day.
Most teams have their own set warm-up that they perform; however, in my opinion the overall goal for warming up before the first game of day should be to get everyone’s body and mind ready to compete at its peak level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routine Need Not Mean Redundant</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</guid>
      <description>You show up early.
Your team has a routine: a slow jog to get the blood flowing, the usual dynamic warm-up routine. From there, you move into the handful of drills you always do, working out the kinks, getting ready for prime time. Sound like the warm-up you know and love?
While this is the current paradigm, I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room for continued innovation. Dynamic (active) warm-ups have become the norm over the past decade, but the next step is to make your dynamic warm-up more&amp;hellip;dynamic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift Your Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</guid>
      <description>The number one mistake teams make in their pregame warmup is too much focus on the muscles and cardiovascular system and too little focus on the nervous system. There is too much focus on volume and too little focus on intensity of movement.
Last year when I was coming out of retirement I enlisted the help of some speed and agility training professionals. These guys specialize in training football players for the combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Pregame Warm-Up Routines</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/team-pregame-warm-up-routines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/team-pregame-warm-up-routines/</guid>
      <description>Team Warm ups should accomplish two goals:
Prepare a team 1) mentally and 2) physically for the game ahead. Most teams perform at their peak if they can use their warm up to feel like they comfortable with their system and their bodies. Any team warm up should include enough things to get the team focused and ready for the task at hand without becoming drudgery.
The &amp;ldquo;warm up&amp;rdquo; should generally start an hour before the first pull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New School Warm-up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/the-new-school-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/the-new-school-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>A quality warm up should simply prepare the body for the work to follow. What is to follow? A match of our beautiful, dynamic sport that involves sprinting, jumping, throwing, marking and changing direction&amp;hellip;
Ok, so how do we prepare for all that?
The New School Warm Up: Pros: The most effective way to prepare the body to work out
Cons: Takes a relatively long time, requires tools, is not flashy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Warm-Up Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>While others may be more concerned with adjustments for each game, specific plyometrics, or the most useful drills, I have 3 solid beliefs on fundamentals of warm-ups:
Try to do the same thing for each game. No matter what you may include in your warm-ups, teams and individuals respond well to a routine. This way players don’t have to focus too much on the timing or progression of warm-ups and can instead focus on their skills, body and/or uncontrollables around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Will Laugh</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/we-will-laugh/</guid>
      <description>Within 5 years, I firmly believe that we will look back on the warm-ups we use now and laugh. This isn&amp;rsquo;t true for every team, but I think that most high- level teams are warming up in ways that are more similar than they are different. Team huddle, jogging, stretching, plyos, throwing, catching drills, personal time, huck drills, 7v7, pre-game huddle, cheer, etc, etc. And those combined similarities are holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
