<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Mackey on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/matt-mackey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matt Mackey on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/matt-mackey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Routine Need Not Mean Redundant</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/routine-need-not-mean-redundant/</guid>
      <description>You show up early.
Your team has a routine: a slow jog to get the blood flowing, the usual dynamic warm-up routine. From there, you move into the handful of drills you always do, working out the kinks, getting ready for prime time. Sound like the warm-up you know and love?
While this is the current paradigm, I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room for continued innovation. Dynamic (active) warm-ups have become the norm over the past decade, but the next step is to make your dynamic warm-up more&amp;hellip;dynamic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustaining Team Culture</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/self-sustaining-team-culture/</guid>
      <description>A former captain and then-coach of mine offered only this advice when I described to him the multitude of ideas and plans we rising seniors at Dartmouth had for team leadership and culture in the coming season: It’s always harder than you think.
This message is worth keeping in mind for anyone seeking to engineer or change something as amorphous yet integral as one’s team culture - it’s all too easy to get caught up in the energy and excitement of the season and neglect the grand ideas and notions you have for making this season the season for you and your teammates, to say nothing of the difficulty of managing people in general.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
