<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeff Eastham-Anderson on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jeff-eastham-anderson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeff Eastham-Anderson on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jeff-eastham-anderson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practice? We Talkin&#39; About Practice?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</guid>
      <description>Epic rants by NBA legends belittling the importance of practice aside, there is a wealth of evidence that points to the importance of practice, both quantity and quality, when it comes to improving athletic performance. Many people have noted that athletes seem to require at least 10 years from the time they begin a sport until they are able to reach the top of their game. Others have taken this analysis further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Things Durings A Point</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</guid>
      <description>When you find yourself on the sideline, there are two obvious things to do during a point. You should serve as an extra brain and pair of eyes to help them execute the team’s strategy, and you need to encourage them to keep putting in effort. I’ll skip over these two aspects of sideline help (which I hope others will cover in more detail), and focus on one aspect which takes place after a point is over, and one aspect which is believed to be helpful, but is frequently not, and should be discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move As Early As Possible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</guid>
      <description>In framing this discussion, I think it is important to note that some teams have a static approach to shifting the mark, while others are more dynamic. In the static case, the mark starts off taking away more of the reset look only on the sideline, while giving up more of an angle downfield. In the dynamic case, the marker starts off with a conventional angle, but rotates with the marker when they turn to hit the dump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition &amp; Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/recognition-position/</guid>
      <description>Two key factors of getting a block are:
Being able to recognize mistakes by the offense Being in a good position to capitalize upon them Being faster than the person you&amp;rsquo;re guarding helps, but paying attention to these two aspects will help your team defensively.
When it comes to positioning, as a defender I rarely bait throws in anticipation of a layout block, especially when it comes to cuts that are close to the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments &amp; Positioning</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/adjustments-positioning/</guid>
      <description>The easiest way to simulate bad-weather conditions in a drill or a game is to simply tell your players to not throw the throws you can&amp;rsquo;t realistically complete in those conditions. The idea is to gain confidence in beating a zone with flat, crisp, high percentage throws. And if for some reason they decide to throw a cross-field hammer, or 10 yard push pass, stop the drill and reset, or just call it a turnover and continue playing from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extra Defender</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/the-extra-defender/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/the-extra-defender/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always viewed the sideline as an extra defender that can be utilized by the defense to gain an advantage, especially in a vertical stack offense. As the disc moves to the sideline, the thrower and cutters have less viable space to work with, which restricts them to two kinds of viable cuts; a deep cut and an under cut. For a defender, shutting down these two sideline options simplifies the task that is presented when the disc is in the middle; a deep cut, an under cut, and a break mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles Can Be Difficult To Observe</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</guid>
      <description>Apart from specific match-ups on defense that require certain roles (being tall and fast, or short and quick), there are lots of roles in zone defenses and in some offensive sets. The best example I can think of is the marker on a trap-side zone defense. This is the position that anchors the zone when it is within 5 yards of the sideline, and can make or break the scheme. This person has the opportunity to take away more options that any other defensive player on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Breaking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/mark-breaking/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite fakes is really quite quick (maybe a quarter of a second of motion), and from the waist up looks exactly like I am going to move my pivot foot for an around break, but I immediately step out for an inside break. My head and torso kind of lunge to one side, and I move the disc quite quickly in the same direction, but my lower body remains stationary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should We Contain?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/what-should-we-contain-/</guid>
      <description>Zone Basics
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of a good trapping zone, but in unpredictable winds even a very conservative and basic zone would produce turns. There are way too many specifics and permutations to cover in this forum, but below are three principles of a trapping zone.
Basically, a trapping zone consists of three things. First, how are you going to allow the disc to move to a sideline. This is a combination of making it hard to move the disc in the middle, and making a lateral throw an easy pass without giving up too many yards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor &amp; Major Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>My first impression of this situation would be to not over-react. There have been close calls, and one turn on handler cuts. If you are getting close to, or are already at the half, this is a pretty good tally to have, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make major changes.
Some small things to consider:
If the other team is counting the stall quickly (most likely the case), the thrower should make the fast-count call as he turns to the dump, or earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>As I am already behind, my priority is to catch up. It&amp;rsquo;s harder to run fast with your head turned, so I will sometimes let the intended receiver read the disc for me and take the hit, in terms of speed. At this point, help from the sideline, in terms of which direction to go, is very helpful.
As soon as I know that I can catch up, or I hear from the sideline that the throw is short, I will turn my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternating Matchups</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/alternating-matchups/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s too bad you can&amp;rsquo;t put the World&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Defender on this person, because they sound like they are the World&amp;rsquo;s Best Offensive Player.
I would probably get two defenders to alternate defensive points with the intention of solely guarding this person. Ideally, one defender would be the quick/squirrelly type with a good mark to challenge him around the disc and apply pressure on the mark. The second defender would be fast and preferably able to out-jump this person, with the intention of continuing to push him deep (but maybe not quite as much as in the first half).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent Determines Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</guid>
      <description>I would say that the absolute talents of your team will likely favor one offense over the other. If you cannot consistently complete passes greater than forty yards, a stack offense is more favorable than a horizontal. Any situation where the defense no longer has to defend the deep pass puts the horizontal stack offense at a significant disadvantage. This generality can be extrapolated to any situation, not just wind condition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
