<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Progression Of Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It seems sensible to find the disc as early as possible. However, I think first I need to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m matching the receiver stride for stride, so I let them do the work of finding the disc early on and use that time to make up some ground.
Any work they do finding the disc will also help me pinpoint where to look for it. Once I&amp;rsquo;m matching their stride, I&amp;rsquo;ll look for the disc and start making judgments about how the contest is going to pan out</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Texas Hold&#39;em Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-texas-hold-em-analogy/</guid>
      <description>Deep D is a lot like poker in three significant ways:
1. Information is more important than anything else.
2. You play the hand you are dealt, and try to win more than your share given the cards in your hand.
3. It ain&amp;rsquo;t over until til it&amp;rsquo;s over.
Information: As I turn to head deep and hear that &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call, I need to get a read on the disc as quickly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/body-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>As I am already behind, my priority is to catch up. It&amp;rsquo;s harder to run fast with your head turned, so I will sometimes let the intended receiver read the disc for me and take the hit, in terms of speed. At this point, help from the sideline, in terms of which direction to go, is very helpful.
As soon as I know that I can catch up, or I hear from the sideline that the throw is short, I will turn my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Quickly Based On The Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/calculate-quickly-based-on-the-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/calculate-quickly-based-on-the-throw/</guid>
      <description>When I hear the &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call I try to spot the disc, briefly and without giving up any more ground.
I need to ascertain if it has truly gone up, and if it is intended for the player I am now chasing. If both of these things are true, then I try to make some quick calculations based on what type of throw has been made.
If it is low or short, I can simply go to it and have position underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Defensive Speed</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/changing-defensive-speed/</guid>
      <description>There is a big factor that comes into play here that I should use to set the stage:
Why are big time football receivers 6&#39;2&amp;quot; or 6&#39;3&amp;quot; and 220lbs (think Terrell Owens), while big time defensive backs are 5&#39;10&amp;quot; or 5&#39;11&amp;quot; and 190lbs?
And: Why does it generally seem that DBs are the fastest guys, but you routinely see them getting beat deep by receivers who should be slower?
There are two speeds that ultimate defenders (and football defenders) have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get In Front</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-in-front/</guid>
      <description>Even though the answer to this question is pretty straightforward—a surprising number of club players make errors on this play.
First of all, if I am only a stride or two behind my check when a huck goes up then I am feeling pretty good about my positioning. Only a perfectly thrown disc will not allow me to have a play on it. Secondly—and this is where many players make an error—I always make the inside play on the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Position Relative To Your Opponent</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</guid>
      <description>Being a receiver, this scenario is one of my favorite moments in ultimate. The adrenaline kicks in and it dawns on you that it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to make the play you have been training all season. My training regimen is focused on maximizing acceleration and jumping ability, both of which are essential to getting the block in this scenario. But before putting those skills to use, you have to look up quickly and find the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Get It</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/go-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/go-get-it/</guid>
      <description>In the deep-D scenario, the disc is already in the air. But let&amp;rsquo;s rewind just a bit. As a defender, my goal is for the &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; call to be the second sign that the disc is coming. The first sign should be my anticipation of the play as it develops. The more I am aware of what is happening with the disc, the mark, and the other cutters, the easier it is to anticipate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play The Player First, Then The Disc</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</guid>
      <description>When I hear the up-call, my first instinct is to get between my player and where I think the disc is going to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t look for the disc yet because the disc is secondary to my player when I&amp;rsquo;m on defense. If I can get my body into the proper position, I will get the disc every time.
Typically in this situation, I will try to make some kind of body contact (not with arms or legs)—jockeying for position using my butt or shoulders to maintain my position between my player and the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train For The Launch Pad</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</guid>
      <description>More than any other skill in ultimate—besides, maybe, getting layout blocks—dominating in the air has largely to do with raw athleticism, aggressiveness, and instinct. There&amp;rsquo;s really no substitute for being a physical beast. If you&amp;rsquo;re tall and fast, and you have springs for legs, you&amp;rsquo;re going to posterize some poor souls, and in the process you&amp;rsquo;ll develop confidence and intuition that you&amp;rsquo;ll bring into every future matchup.
So: train. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not a premium genetic specimen, effective training can bring out the inner beast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Your Body As The Cut Starts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</guid>
      <description>If your man starts heading deep and you hear an up-call, you have to assume the thrower is putting up a huck&amp;hellip;so, obviously, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to try to beat your guy to the spot.
Back to Ultimate 101 for a second: if you were guarding the last guy in the stack, you probably have last-back responsibilities. An unguarded deep look is a lot more dangerous than an open under cut, so make sure the deep is shut down first.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
