<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonathan Potts on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jonathan-potts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jonathan Potts on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jonathan-potts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trial &amp; Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>If this is in the middle of an elimination game, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to make an effective adjustment, it needs to be simple. It sounds like the defence is playing particularly tight around the disc, and putting enough pressure downfield to force us to take bad looks. If this is the case, these are probably the things I would try early on:
Look for the reset earlier in the count.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Progression Of Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/a-progression-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It seems sensible to find the disc as early as possible. However, I think first I need to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m matching the receiver stride for stride, so I let them do the work of finding the disc early on and use that time to make up some ground.
Any work they do finding the disc will also help me pinpoint where to look for it. Once I&amp;rsquo;m matching their stride, I&amp;rsquo;ll look for the disc and start making judgments about how the contest is going to pan out</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts From Australia</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</guid>
      <description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about this a lot, surprisingly. I find I&amp;rsquo;m generally on a team that&amp;rsquo;s drilled a lot of vertical or drilled a lot of horizontal, so we&amp;rsquo;re better at one particular offence in most conditions.
All other things being equal, horizontal relies on using static structure to create space on the field, whereas vertical relies on cutting (dynamic structure?) to create space on the field.
Wind tends to nullify cutting advantages, so theoretically horizontally should be preferred in the wind, all other things being equal, including your team&amp;rsquo;s ability to play either offence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
