<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Full Focus, Full Effort</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/full-focus-full-effort/</guid>
      <description>When planning a practice, it is important to think about the personnel and goals of a practice. For instance, a fall practice for a college team is going to have very different objectives than a fall practice for an elite open team. The college team might be trying to have a lot of fun to &amp;ldquo;set the hook&amp;rdquo; with new players and give a lot of reps to players still learning the game, while an elite team is tuning up for the peak of their season and should be focusing on consistent execution of skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting More Out of the Practice Warm-Up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/getting-more-out-of-the-practice-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/getting-more-out-of-the-practice-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>Nearly every team I&amp;rsquo;ve played on had what I would call the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; ultimate warm up. You jog/plyo/stretch in some combination, and then you do some set of drills which can be roughly summarized as: the down field under &amp;ldquo;cutting&amp;rdquo; drill (Go To, etc), the dump/swing/continue &amp;ldquo;handler&amp;rdquo; drill and the huck drill. There are lots of different flavors of them, with or without marks, where you start, etc, but at their core, these drills focus on 2 or 3 players while everyone else is watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Intensity, Concepts, and Fun</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/managing-intensity-concepts-and-fun/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning can be daunting and it’s often hard to know where to start. It can be difficult to strike the right balance between fun and intense, learning and playing, covering everything and getting enough reps on any individual thing, etc. In my experience, it helps to have a broad, season-long outline from which to flesh out individual practices. This means having a rough idea of all the different strategies you want to cover in a season (specific offenses, specific defenses, fundamentals, etc), and making sure there are enough practices to cover everything (and if there aren’t, then to scale back your expectations of how much to cover in the season!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes Are Precious</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/minutes-are-precious/</guid>
      <description>Minutes at practice are precious. Here are my 5 relatively simple ways to maximize the amount of growth you can foster from each of your practices. At the end, I&amp;rsquo;ve included an example set of 3 practices to try and illustrate these points.
1) Use your warm-up time effectively
Warm-ups take a large percentage of total practice time. To focus that effort, I like to include warm-up drills or games that give a good mental introduction to the purpose of later practice drills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parts of a Whole</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</guid>
      <description>Everything that happens at practice should be a building block and not an isolated event. You need to design practices behind a theme that&amp;rsquo;s overtly stated to the whole team and repeated often throughout the day. Never let the participants lose track of the day&amp;rsquo;s goal or remain unclear about the lesson at hand. Emphasizing concrete points of focus over the course of practice as well as the course of the season gives your players a measure of their progress, in addition to game-time tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Ahead</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Great practices don&amp;rsquo;t just happen. A lot of work goes on behind the scenes to plan practices that run smoothly and effortlessly, as well as accomplishing the main goal of making the team better.
Plan your practices in advance - not just the drills for one practice, but figure out what concepts you want and need to cover over the course of the season. Then break down the concepts and spread them over the available practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Youth Practices</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-youth-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/planning-youth-practices/</guid>
      <description>Elementary Ultimate (Ages 8-11) Beginners
Fun, fun fun.
When it comes down to it, these guys just aren’t quite developed enough to hold attention on one thing for anything longer than 15 minutes. So first things first, you really have to chunk your practice out. Secondly, these kids are just learning how to use their bodies in an athletic way and ultimately a lot of what you do will be teaching them overall coordination and control of their bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Planning Musts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-planning-musts/</guid>
      <description>1. Write it down.
This helps you remember your plan, creates a document that you can return to, and can be emailed to the team beforehand if you feel it would help.
2. Specify time allotments for each segment of practice.
This creates a schedule, and is easier on you (you know when to start/stop a drill) and your team (they know there&amp;rsquo;s a plan to stick to).
3. Don&amp;rsquo;t perform a drill for more than 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice? We Talkin&#39; About Practice?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/practice-we-talkin-about-practice-/</guid>
      <description>Epic rants by NBA legends belittling the importance of practice aside, there is a wealth of evidence that points to the importance of practice, both quantity and quality, when it comes to improving athletic performance. Many people have noted that athletes seem to require at least 10 years from the time they begin a sport until they are able to reach the top of their game. Others have taken this analysis further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Habits of Highly Effective Throwers: How to Plan a Throwing Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning isn&amp;rsquo;t just for the team captain. Every player should take it upon themselves to have throwing practice in addition to team practice. Make the most of your practice hours by incorporating these habits into your throwing regimen.
1. Choose the right throwing partner(s)
Before you can even practice, you need a throwing partner!
Find a good throwing partner or several partners. If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about becoming an all-star handler, you will probably need more than one partner to get in the amount of hours required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Control of Your Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/take-control-of-your-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/take-control-of-your-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice is a vital part of mastering any skill, and team sports are no exception. A quality practice structure can transform a meaningless few hours running around into a valuable and productive growth opportunity for your team. While the content covered in a given practice clearly varies heavily with the level, division, weather, time of year, etc, some of the basics of running a quality practice are nearly always applicable. Here are a few of my favorites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Easy Targets</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/three-easy-targets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/three-easy-targets/</guid>
      <description>It’s the end of the day, and it feels like nothing has been accomplished. Teammates barely listened to instruction, drills were sloppy and unfocused, everything took twice as long as it should have, and you walk away with a sick taste in your mouth, directing your anger and frustration towards the most vocal trouble-makers. That’s right, you’ve just experienced another bad practice.
We’ve all had this feeling before, and while you’ll probably have it again, there are ways we can reduce the severity of the bad practice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
