<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shane Rubenfeld on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/shane-rubenfeld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shane Rubenfeld on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/shane-rubenfeld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parts of a Whole</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/parts-of-a-whole/</guid>
      <description>Everything that happens at practice should be a building block and not an isolated event. You need to design practices behind a theme that&amp;rsquo;s overtly stated to the whole team and repeated often throughout the day. Never let the participants lose track of the day&amp;rsquo;s goal or remain unclear about the lesson at hand. Emphasizing concrete points of focus over the course of practice as well as the course of the season gives your players a measure of their progress, in addition to game-time tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide New Information and Reinforcement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>Sideline talk should make the players on the field more effective in two ways: it should help them make different decisions than they might make otherwise, and it should help them (re)act more quickly to game situations. In other words, the primary functions of sideline talk are to provide new information, and to provide reinforcement that cuts down processing time.
&amp;lsquo;Provide new information&amp;rsquo;: tell the player on the field anything they can&amp;rsquo;t see that might- or should- change the way they play for the next few seconds or passes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
