<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Point Guard&#34; Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/-point-guard-options/</guid>
      <description>When I play, I often pick up the disc after a turnover. When I coach, my teams are in this situation often (as Lou noted, college teams have dead-disc situations much more frequently than in club Ultimate). Given the inherent confusion of the moment, I value a simple communication system in order to create positive and coordinated disc movement in a chaotic environment.
I really don&amp;rsquo;t care if everyone on the team can call plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Play(er)s</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play is if it works on the field with the players you have. No matter the nomenclature, strategic genius, or underlying theory: what happens on paper matters little.
In general, I would say most team&amp;rsquo;s playbooks (and plays) are too complicated. Go simple. And a few simple rules are:
1. Does the play work? (Not, &amp;ldquo;it would have worked if&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;)
2. What is option B if the first pass doesn&amp;rsquo;t go as designed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</guid>
      <description>In game two of this year&amp;rsquo;s Eastern Conference Finals against the Orlando Magic, LeBron and the Cavs had a set play. They were down by 2 with seconds left and needed a quick bucket. LeBron was to cut hard to the hoop for an alley-oop. Magic forward Hedo Turkoglu had an idea what would happen and positioned himself between LeBron and the basket. As the play unfolded, LeBron took a few steps towards the rim, and Turkoglu sags off him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secrecy &amp; Spying In Ultimate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2006 Sub Zero cut a player then accidentally left him on our email list. This guy later played for our competition. He forwarded to them our &amp;ldquo;playbook.&amp;rdquo; But before we uncovered the leak, Zero and this team played in finals of Sectionals. Early in the game we got our first defensive possession, near our opponent&amp;rsquo;s endzone. Mark &amp;ldquo;Paco&amp;rdquo; Enright picked up the disc and called the audible for me to cut for an immediate swing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Plays For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/selecting-plays-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The trick to a good set play package is selecting the right plays for your team. Here are some basic guidelines:
1. Make it worth your time. There is only so much your team can learn, so you want to make sure you are getting the most out of what you are practicing. If you are playing elite club ultimate, over half of your possessions are going to be off of the pull, so learn more pull plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity, Creatvity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play great is simplicity and creativity. It should be designed to have a main cut, but also a bail out. It should be taught on paper, on a whiteboard, with walk-throughs and at full speed. In the past, we have relied more on designing our own plays. My women&amp;rsquo;s club team has minimal to no plays, but the college team I coach has a playbook that they rely on probably 20% of the time off a dead disc situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits Of Theft</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</guid>
      <description>Steal, steal, steal. If you are the smartest play to have ever played the game, you may have reason to rely on your own originality. If not, find out who is—be it player, team, or just a better division—and how they position themselves to be successful. Any stoppage of play, between points, after timeouts, after violations, will allow you to see what they want to do, given the context on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Double Flat Stack</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-double-flat-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-double-flat-stack/</guid>
      <description>It was late 2007, and Western Washington University was fielding an alumni team at the Sundodger Invitational. It was early on Saturday—round one or two, and I believe we were playing Simon Fraser University. A nice group of lads if ever I&amp;rsquo;d seen. They had just put a goal in, and I was trotting back to line with Dave Bestock, Ben Wiggins, and Aly Lenon, among others.
When we arrived to the line, Aly tells me to call a line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
