<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chelsea Putnam on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chelsea-putnam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chelsea Putnam on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chelsea-putnam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Find What Works For Your Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/find-what-works-for-your-team/</guid>
      <description>We all know how exciting it is to play Ultimate, and we all know what it feels like to have those butterflies before game time. Having a well executed pre- game warm-up can literally mean the difference, in my opinion, between winning or losing the game. Setting the appropriate tone for game time is essential because this game we play is at least 80% mental. Here are a few things to keep in mind when you are creating a warm-up:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character When It Matters Most</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/character-when-it-matters-most/</guid>
      <description>Spirit of the Game is easy when the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;hellip;but that is certainly not the case with Northwest Regionals. Every game is a battle and every game is intense. In my opinion, it is when the UPA Series starts that Spirit matters most.
The best players in the game can play at an incredibly high level without compromising their personal integrity or the reputation of their team. I think that sometimes Spirit of the Game is mistaken for not contesting calls or not being willing to make a call, but really it is honoring your opponents and yourself by playing 100% and making calls if true violations or fouls occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schwa&#39;s D-Handler</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/schwa-s-d-handler/</guid>
      <description>Great defensive handlers are typically people who are aggressive, able to see the field really well, and have a solid understanding of when it is appropriate to play transition offense. In my opinion, one of the most important parts of being a defensive handler is leading your team when you guys do get the D. This may be calling a play, running to the disc to transition, creating space for a teammate, or cutting to get the disc off the transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Fake Make Be A Viable Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/every-fake-make-be-a-viable-throw/</guid>
      <description>The best piece of advice I ever received about breaking the mark is that every fake must be a viable throw. You need to create space in order to break the mark; strong fakes are going to make that happen. Many defenders choose to watch only the disc when they are marking (don&amp;rsquo;t do that, defenders!) and therefore they are reacting to your fakes. By making realistic fakes, with the disc and your upper body movement, you will get your defender to shift their weight and be off-balance for a moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Keys To Being A Good Middle</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/three-keys-to-being-a-good-middle/</guid>
      <description>I can think of three main points that will help you when you are trying to get open in the middle of a horizontal stack. The first is that your team needs to put the right type of player in that position. In my opinion, this is a player who is confident with the disc, is a threat as a deep thrower, and understands how to get open both going deep and coming under.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
