<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Ashbrook on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chris-ashbrook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chris Ashbrook on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chris-ashbrook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Consistently</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/scoring-consistently/</guid>
      <description>What I like to do is to not let the mark dictate the throw, but for the thrower to dictate the markers positioning and movements. In doing so, I find teaching young players to break the mark that you must first teach them to make themselves a threat while holding the disc. I consider the way I hold the disc similar to what is called a triple threat in basketball. To me, this means holding the disc in a throwing position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Zone Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/addressing-zone-questions/</guid>
      <description>From your experience, what zone configuration do you feel most confident in?
In general I prefer a three man cup mainly because it can be used to disguise other types of defensive schemes teams may use, such as a zone to man. The specific setup I prefer for the three man cup is with the short deep playing very close to the cup, if not actually part of the cup, working as a unit to trap the disc on the sideline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Players of Note</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</guid>
      <description>Two players that come to mind when I think of good footwork are Idris Nolan offensively and Hensley Sejour defensively. Idris is quite a good basketball player, which requires a significant amount of body control as well as footwork. Hensley, coming from a football background as a defensive back (I believe) has worked on his footwork extensively.
Whether offensively or defensively, Idris and Hensley have the same traits in common:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Your First-Half Performance</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/question-your-first-half-performance/</guid>
      <description>I like to look at the bigger picture before making adjustments for just one player. (This is assuming you have used the same strategy in previous meetings and have been successful).
Assumptions
1. The third goal was scored in the normal flow of the O (whether Man or Zone).
2. Two goals were scored while the D was in a straight man D, ie no zone transition.
3. The game is not determined by the wind, ie a windy upwind/downwind game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Chris Ashbrook</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player?
Absolutely. There are a number of college players that have now played on club teams while still in college (Watson, Heijman, Cahill, Gibson, etc), some while in high school. These players are usually the best offensive players on their teams and have been to college nationals, at least once, if not multiple times. Although they may have inexperience on the club seen, they have crunch time experience and are able to eventually translate that to the club scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Team Are We?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</guid>
      <description>I want to first analyze what type of team we are and what type of team we are playing in determining which offense (and defense) to run.
Downwind
Here I generally prefer the horizontal stack, regardless (and variations), as I feel you a thrower is given more choices from nearly every position. Players also tend to overplay defensively when guarding an O that is going downwind which I feel tends to open up cutters underneath and away more often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
