<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avoid The Pile-Up</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/avoid-the-pile-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/avoid-the-pile-up/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there before. The throw goes up, the disc catches some wind, and just hangs. As the intended offensive receiver, you are forced to slow down and track the path of the disc. It soon becomes quite crowded around you as multiple players converge on what seems like the optimal position to vie for the disc. Soon it&amp;rsquo;s time to jump for the disc and hope everything works out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beating The Pack From Below The Canopy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</guid>
      <description>Usually being the shortest guy on the teams I play on, catching 50/50 (jump ball) discs from my perspective is a different game altogether. There are two situations you can encounter with a 50/50 disc. Either you are in the eye of the storm, in which case you were the initial receiver or your the first defender to get into the play, and a multitude of others are collapsing down upon you from all places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</guid>
      <description>In order to catch a 50/50 disc a player needs to be able to do a number of things correctly to win the battle.
1. Reading
The player must be able to read the disc and understand how the wind and the way the disc was thrown is going to affect its flight path.
2. Positioning
Once that player has a good grasp of where that disc is going to float down to earth, that player must establish that position firmly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting The Advantage</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/getting-the-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/getting-the-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Catching a 50/50 disc is not an exact science just like every other aspect of Ultimate and unfortunately there aren&amp;rsquo;t a lot of aspects you can practice if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to sky the best receivers in the game. Superior athleticism and your ability to read the disc almost always win. However, there are a few things (besides improving vertical leap, experience, etc.) that can set you apart from the rest of the pack if you want to have an advantage at catching a disc over someone of similar or greater ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Into The Sky Club</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/how-to-get-into-the-sky-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/how-to-get-into-the-sky-club/</guid>
      <description>My first action, after recognizing that I am about to engage in a 50/50 disc tango, is to take the appropriate angle of attack based on where I think the disc is going to go. This is obviously stale information for veterans. But for the beginners out there, you&amp;rsquo;ll always be considered a member of the grounds crew if you keep running directly underneath the disc expecting that it will drop down to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Them Make A Play</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/make-them-make-a-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/make-them-make-a-play/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to catching a floating 50/50 disc, one of the most important things to think about is that if the other person is going to get the disc then at least make them make a play. Force them to make a great play to catch it, don&amp;rsquo;t let it be easy. This philosophy most directly applies to playing defence, but still applies to offensive situations.
Too often I see players setting up position behind their opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning &amp; Approach</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/positioning-approach/</guid>
      <description>While we call these hangers &amp;ldquo;50/50 discs,&amp;rdquo; I would bet that at the moment the disc is coming down an observer would have a better than coin-flip chance of guessing who will touch the disc first. Keying in on the information informing that decision will help guide a player in giving themselves a better than coin-flip chance of getting to it first.
I think that beyond obvious physical differences (&amp;ldquo;I like the guy who is 6&#39;8&amp;rdquo; over the short guy&amp;quot;) the two main components are positioning and approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retain That!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</guid>
      <description>To catch a 50/50 disc, you need to somehow make the chances better than 50/50 for yourself. The first thing you can do is be tall—and yes, I know you can&amp;rsquo;t teach height, but this also includes putting your hand up outstretched and trying to catch the disc at your &amp;ldquo;tallest point&amp;rdquo; including your jump. This is related to the second thing which is timing your jump. I know lots of players (particularly new women) who think just putting their hand up will work—well, it won&amp;rsquo;t work against good competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning On Both Sides Of The Disc</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/winning-on-both-sides-of-the-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/winning-on-both-sides-of-the-disc/</guid>
      <description>On Offense
You ought to have done much of the work up front. You were out in the lane first, making an open cut to the end zone, you were looking over your shoulder and saw the release point of the throw. You made your read early, calculated the trajectory of the disc, and picked your line before your defender even heard an up call.
Realizing that your thrower has laid you out to dry with a floaty throw (at least they didn&amp;rsquo;t pump fake and make you come under), you pick a spot four to five yards from where the disc will come down between the disc and the defender to hold your ground.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
