<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Checklist</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/a-basic-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is probably the least rewarding aspect of Ultimate. Not only will you rarely be recognized for good sub-calling, but instead sub-calling is the easiest thing for many people to blame for problems on the field. Additionally, problems (real or perceived) with playing time and sub-calling are often the number one issue affecting team dynamics and player satisfaction. In my experience, the easiest way to avoid issues with subcalling is to have a plan ahead of time and to communicate as best as possible to individuals where their role fits into that plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Careful What You Wish For</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Be careful what you wish for.&amp;rdquo;
— Ken Dobyns over the phone, NYC to Hampton Bays, August 1995.
Calling the D line that season isn&amp;rsquo;t something I necessarily wished for, but blindly accepted the vacancy; possibly a dumb move for a not proved new face on a second year team still fielding much of the leftover NYNY dynasty. We beat Boston four times that season: Regionals, Tune-up, and two small pre- season tourneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elocution &amp; Enunciation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/elocution-enunciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/elocution-enunciation/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than calling a line a finding an uninvited guest has wandered onto the field. Not only do you have to recall the correct name, but you have to break the news to the overzealous player and watch them slink off sadly like Charlie Brown after failing to kick that football. Rats.
To avoid this situation you must speak with the uttermost clarity and amplification. You mustn&amp;rsquo;t slur your speech; too often names like Sean and John or Brett and Bren become confused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering The Team With Self Subbing</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/empowering-the-team-with-self-subbing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been very fortunate in my career to play on many successful teams that did not call subs, and this hypothetical situation could be a blessing in disguise. Most players at elite levels are fairly self-aware, and after a season of playing together most can recognize the hierarchy within the team and could make an honest appraisal of their optimum contribution to the team in terms of quantity and type (O or D) of points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Your Team, Not Your Teammates</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling, especially for one who one who plays at the same time, is one of the most difficult things to do. Personally, I hate doing it because I feel like it distracts me from my ability to remain focused while playing. But like everyone, I always have my own feelings about who should be playing at a particular time. Fortunately, as captain of my team, my opinion about who plays carries a bit of weight with the sub-caller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sub-Calling Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>1. If you pick the right personnel, there will always be a time when you can play each player. Think about when these times are for each player on your team and allow them to excel in these situations.
2. Be clear to your teammates about the team&amp;rsquo;s sub-calling philosophy. If it changes for a tournament, don&amp;rsquo;t make it a hush hush operation—let everyone know so nothing is a surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>When I was calling subs, I also usually was calling the &amp;ldquo;strategy&amp;rdquo; for the points. (Are we playing zone? Are we setting horizontal? Is this point the most critical point ever?). That helped me when it came to determining players based on the roles needed. It also made me pretty tired by the end of the day. How these decisions are made on your team will help dictate who should call subs when the sub-caller goes down with a freak throat injury (Larynxeum andibenitis).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/preparation/</guid>
      <description>First things first—calling subs for a competitive team is a big job. It will take a lot away from anyone&amp;rsquo;s playing ability. There may be someone out there who can play at their best and call subs at the same time, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t met them. Because of this, I think it&amp;rsquo;s better to split sub-calling duties between two or three players, or expect that the person calling subs is not going to play very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Your Team For The Hard Decisions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/prepare-your-team-for-the-hard-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/prepare-your-team-for-the-hard-decisions/</guid>
      <description>It is a big point midway through a big game at the most important high school elite open tourney of the year. The opposing team has taken a timeout between points. You look at the team you coach to figure out what line you want in the game. You know that a number of your kids haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the game yet and that they paid a lot of money to make the plane trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Sub-Caller Is...</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-best-sub-caller-is-/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple little tricks that can really help you out.
This first technique is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never done, but I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna name it. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it Repeater. I saw it first at College Nationals this year, where Syzygy was using it (they crushed us) and I later overheard teams using it at Solstice (Eugene) and HoDown (Calgary). Basically, your sub caller yells out the names just as usual and then everyone repeats them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pod System</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is one of the most difficult parts of being a team leader, be it as a coach or a player. As coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have employed several different strategies throughout the years depending on the team. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give young players some insight into one coach&amp;rsquo;s perspective of sub-calling.
My sub-calling strategy begins in the organization of my sub sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
