<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Talarico on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chris-talarico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chris Talarico on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/chris-talarico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yardage Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/yardage-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/yardage-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>The sideline is a great space to look to gain yardage. If your dump can beat his defender up the line, it should be a relatively easy pass to space in front of him, and he can then potentially hit a deep throw. This is probably the best way to get off a high percentage huck (and doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to happen on the sideline). It&amp;rsquo;s easy for the downfield cutters to time a deep cut when they see this up-line cut developing, and the thrower can use his momentum to get off a big throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Easier Way</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/an-easier-way/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the easiest way to break the mark is just to let someone else do it. I mean, break throws are hard. Do I really want to go to the trouble of pivoting all over the place, faking out the mark, getting off a potentially risky throw&amp;hellip; and then perhaps get hacked by the mark for my efforts? Forget it. I just don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of hassle.
Not everyone can break the mark at will, and even for those who have great break throws, it can still be a somewhat risky pass at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Positioning On The Comeback Cut</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/body-positioning-on-the-comeback-cut/</guid>
      <description>The best thing I ever heard of for improving your receiving skills is this game called &amp;ldquo;catch&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s no replacement for repetition. You just have to do it over and over until you forget what it&amp;rsquo;s like to drop a frisbee.
The next step is simulating game situations. Personally, I feel like the most valuable catch to be 100% on is the in-cut: running full speed toward a disc coming at you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get On The Ladder!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</guid>
      <description>A big part of footwork is quickness, and the best tool I know of to improve quickness is a speed ladder. I would highly recommend getting one—the longer the better. The various drills and exercises are pretty easy to find and learn, and they&amp;rsquo;re pretty fun to do.
You can just Google &amp;ldquo;speed ladder drills&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ll get plenty of sites that do a far better job of explaining the drills than I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement, Movement, Movement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</guid>
      <description>The best way to attack a team that is playing good shut-down defense is to keep the disc moving, and moving quickly. This is not a novel concept by any means, but it&amp;rsquo;s rare that a team actually hits the first open pass consistently. Throwers tend to get antsy if you&amp;rsquo;re not gaining yardage and instead of looking to get rid of the frisbee, will instead hold it looking for something upfiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Your Body As The Cut Starts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/use-your-body-as-the-cut-starts/</guid>
      <description>If your man starts heading deep and you hear an up-call, you have to assume the thrower is putting up a huck&amp;hellip;so, obviously, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to try to beat your guy to the spot.
Back to Ultimate 101 for a second: if you were guarding the last guy in the stack, you probably have last-back responsibilities. An unguarded deep look is a lot more dangerous than an open under cut, so make sure the deep is shut down first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Concede &amp; What To Take Away</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/what-to-concede-what-to-take-away/</guid>
      <description>This one is pretty straightforward: as with any player, you have to determine what you want to give up and what you want to take away (or try to, anyway). You&amp;rsquo;re going to want to deny any player&amp;rsquo;s greatest strength or whatever facet of his game is capable of hurting you most. If this guy has beaten you repeatedly with his throws, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a very good idea to allow him to get the disc underneath - even if he has caught a couple hucks today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athleticism First, Attitude Close Behind</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</guid>
      <description>The most important things I want to see from a tryout are, in no particular order:
Athleticism/speed Field sense Confidence with the disc Ability &amp;amp; willingness to take direction The first point speaks for itself. If a player can&amp;rsquo;t run fast, jump, layout, and exhibit a reasonable level of body control, they don&amp;rsquo;t stand much of a chance.
For field sense, I want to see that a player knows where the next pass is likely to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Ho-Stack Is Currently In Favor</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</guid>
      <description>The horizontal stack has all but replaced the vertical stack because it does such a good job of creating space. When run effectively, four cutters typically are spread across the width of the field. This spacing between cutters makes defensive switches very difficult, thereby putting each downfield defender on an island one-on-one with their man. As any cutter will tell you, when you know your defender doesn&amp;rsquo;t have help, you have the advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
