<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Change A Losing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</guid>
      <description>First and farmost, attitude is everything. If you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have 7 players who believe you can actually win, then this isnt worth reading and the rest of your game isn&amp;rsquo;t worth playing.
Most teams I have played on, in this situation, would try and load the Defensive line with the top defenders. However, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t just to stop the offense and gain possession, but to actually catch the disc in the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countering &amp; Changing Defenses</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</guid>
      <description>While I have not been personally very successful in this situation, other teams have been successful at times against my teams so I can tell you what it seems like they did. You must call tight lines—having players in the games that can create Ds and capitalize on them is imperative. Now is not the time to give players a chance to show their stuff for the first time—use people that are tried and true on D and O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute Your Changes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</guid>
      <description>If you are behind because the team has something you can&amp;rsquo;t handle (a few players or a defense) you are not behind, you are getting beaten. Change it up. Play a different D, run the counter play, even if you have to invent it. Maybe the risk means you go down 13-7 and later people whisper about how you got blown out. But if you can&amp;rsquo;t get the score to 11-9 or 12-10 so what?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One At A Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/one-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>One thing I remember an old teammate saying was that &amp;ldquo;there are no four- pointers in Ultimate.&amp;rdquo; What he meant was that you&amp;rsquo;re not going to bridge the gap in one play, so you have to stay with the gameplan and keep doing the things that your team needs to do to play their best.
The first key is to make sure that your offense is going to score every time they receive, because the worst thing for the team would be to add another break, which only lengthens the odds of a comeback while also being demoralizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short, Aggresive Risks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</guid>
      <description>As a coach, I feel it is necessary to take some risks defensively and call a few different defensive looks that may create enough confusion and lead to a quick turnover by the offense. If you have been playing man the entire game, try a little zone. If you have been forcing one way the entire time, try some middle or straight up. At that point, you must try something different to get the other team out of their comfort zone because clearly, they are comfortable right now in the driver&amp;rsquo;s seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful Attitudes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/successful-attitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/successful-attitudes/</guid>
      <description>The opportunity to be successful in the face of difficult odds is created long before you&amp;rsquo;ve been put in to that situation. It is an attitude that is built in practices, team meetings, and work-outs from the beginning of the season. The focus needs to be on what you and your team have control over in any given moment. Things that you do not have control over include the score of the game—those scores are now part of the past and we are unable to have any affect on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Scenarios For A 2nd Half Comeback</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</guid>
      <description>Scenario #1. Your opponent has a short roster. In the first half they got breaks early. But they are starting to look tired and predictable in their offense. You have identified their play-makers. Your D line has already generated some grueling points for their O line. Meanwhile your team has legs, intensity, they just can&amp;rsquo;t cash in with breaks. In this scenario I&amp;rsquo;d turn up the defensive intensity with a straight up mark, specific match ups, and hard physical D.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
