<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catching The Pull</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/catching-the-pull/</guid>
      <description>As others have mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s highly important to catch the pull whenever possible. In the Women&amp;rsquo;s game, far too many players let the pull hit the ground if it comes in at a hard angle. As a puller, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to take advantage of this by working on big outside-in pulls to gain an extra second or two while the player stops a roll and picks up the disc, possibly gain field position if the player misreads how the disc will roll, and give the offense a wet disc to work with if there&amp;rsquo;s dew on the grass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate 2-3 Breaks A Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</guid>
      <description>Preface: Ever since I started playing competitive Ultimate, I have been on the D team. So, receiving the pull isn&amp;rsquo;t something that I have partaken in very often. That being said, I have done it and can give a viewpoint from a defensive standpoint.
Most important and crucial part of receiving the pull is the reception. I mean pure and simple, having someone there to initially catch the disc. From an offensive standpoint, catching the pull is where the offense begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left &amp; Right Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I would be very intrigued to hear the Open authors&amp;rsquo; answers on this question because, for the most part, Women&amp;rsquo;s pulls do not involve a ridiculous amount of rocket science to field (or maybe I have been missing out on something for years).
Typically, we will call a pull play where one person on the left side of the field fields the pull if it goes left and one person on the right side of the field fields the pull if it goes right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respond As It Comes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/respond-as-it-comes/</guid>
      <description>The best offensive teams can get big yards from the first few passes off a pull, and immediately knock the defense on its heels. There are no shortage of ways to do this, and the best offenses I have been a part of have always had a few options for taking this advantage.
In all cases the critical first component is having a player who feels comfortable catching the pull and throwing the first pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</guid>
      <description>The key goal when receiving the pull is to get into your play/offense as quickly and safely as possible. A few thoughts on how to do this:
Unless the pull is going out of bounds or a big blade in a nice wind, catch it and get it moving. If it&amp;rsquo;s a big blade, stop it as soon as it hits and do the same thing. The only situation which I can think of in which you would not want to do this is if the pull is going to hit and slide out of bounds AND the defense is already set up on all the people you might throw to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Catch To The Hitch</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</guid>
      <description>I have traditionally posted to this website with answers that questioned the question instead of answered it. I feel that I owe Ben and Andy a single straightforward response.
My teams have traditionally fielded the pull with the three handlers. The &amp;ldquo;Catch,&amp;rdquo; not surprisingly, catches the pull. I am surprised how often capable players choose to let pulls hit the ground instead of catching them on the fly. I encourage attempting to catch all but the most vertical of pulls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfailing Terminology</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/unfailing-terminology/</guid>
      <description>Catching the pull requires four players: a 1, a 2, a Short Fill, and a Deep Fill. Everyone else can have their heads up their asses and it&amp;rsquo;ll be okay.
The 1&amp;rsquo;s job is to catch the pull and make the first pass.
The 2&amp;rsquo;s job is to set themselves up to catch the first pass, catch the first pass and then deliver the big throw to the 3.
The Short Fill&amp;rsquo;s job is to read the pull and the defense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
