<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Witmer on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/melissa-witmer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Melissa Witmer on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/melissa-witmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shift Your Focus</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/shift-your-focus/</guid>
      <description>The number one mistake teams make in their pregame warmup is too much focus on the muscles and cardiovascular system and too little focus on the nervous system. There is too much focus on volume and too little focus on intensity of movement.
Last year when I was coming out of retirement I enlisted the help of some speed and agility training professionals. These guys specialize in training football players for the combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Habits of Highly Effective Throwers: How to Plan a Throwing Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-031/seven-habits-of-highly-effective-throwers-how-to-plan-a-throwing-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice planning isn&amp;rsquo;t just for the team captain. Every player should take it upon themselves to have throwing practice in addition to team practice. Make the most of your practice hours by incorporating these habits into your throwing regimen.
1. Choose the right throwing partner(s)
Before you can even practice, you need a throwing partner!
Find a good throwing partner or several partners. If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about becoming an all-star handler, you will probably need more than one partner to get in the amount of hours required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
