<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charlie Reznikoff on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/charlie-reznikoff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Charlie Reznikoff on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/charlie-reznikoff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Recognition</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/pattern-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Psychologist John Dewey debunked a commonly held belief called the stimulus- response reflex arc: you see something, you decide what to do, you respond. Instead, Dewey proposed, you only see what you have a mental framework for; this framework contains your response within it. In other words, your response exists before you see the stimulus. Many players have the experience of knowing they&amp;rsquo;ve thrown the goal before the disc leaves their hands, or &amp;ldquo;seeing&amp;rdquo; the lay out D before it happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Marking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</guid>
      <description>When marking, face to face, one-on-one with your opponent, you are more closed off from the game around you than at any other moment in Ultimate. This leads some markers to try for too much, going for every block. Others miss opportunities to help their teammates by adhering too closely to the force. Effective marking requires a balance between these extremes. One trick to achieving this balance (and knowing when to take a risk on the mark) is glancing over your shoulder at the oncoming cuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blender</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/the-blender/</guid>
      <description>What if the Minnesota Timerwolves had to play Macalaster College and a YWCA pick-up team on their road to an NBA Championship? What if the Commissioner of MLB also governed little league and summer softball league? Those levels of play differ so much they are hardly the same sport. Yet in the Club Series of Ultimate, players from all levels comingle on the same field. The best players in the world compete against absolute novices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secrecy &amp; Spying In Ultimate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/secrecy-spying-in-ultimate/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2006 Sub Zero cut a player then accidentally left him on our email list. This guy later played for our competition. He forwarded to them our &amp;ldquo;playbook.&amp;rdquo; But before we uncovered the leak, Zero and this team played in finals of Sectionals. Early in the game we got our first defensive possession, near our opponent&amp;rsquo;s endzone. Mark &amp;ldquo;Paco&amp;rdquo; Enright picked up the disc and called the audible for me to cut for an immediate swing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Scenarios For A 2nd Half Comeback</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/two-scenarios-for-a-2nd-half-comeback/</guid>
      <description>Scenario #1. Your opponent has a short roster. In the first half they got breaks early. But they are starting to look tired and predictable in their offense. You have identified their play-makers. Your D line has already generated some grueling points for their O line. Meanwhile your team has legs, intensity, they just can&amp;rsquo;t cash in with breaks. In this scenario I&amp;rsquo;d turn up the defensive intensity with a straight up mark, specific match ups, and hard physical D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/the-jailbreak/</guid>
      <description>For most zones, the vulnerable spot is ten yards behind the cup (or front wall). To get there you can go through the cup, over the cup, or around the cup. Through and over involve risk. Around requires patience and planned cuts. Ideally after the swing, before the cup is reset, the handler has two cutters available for the next throw, one a continuation to the line and the other a throw to the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drilling For The Sideline Trap</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/drilling-for-the-sideline-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/drilling-for-the-sideline-trap/</guid>
      <description>An organized approach to sideline situations gives the offense a great advantage. For example: a well-isolated huck down the line or a series of swings to the breakside. Unprepared and against a good defense, a team facing a sideline trap will likely turn the disc over. I would challenge any team to spend more time practicing from the sideline. Most teams have only one play for the sideline, and many for a centered disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is A Role Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen certain players take over games, throwing hucks, getting lay out Ds, or getting open against good defenders. These players are revered. What is a role player? Everyone else.
I avoid using the term &amp;ldquo;role player&amp;rdquo; because it implies a value judgment on those players who don&amp;rsquo;t get the glory. The player who throws hucks isn&amp;rsquo;t a role player. The player who uses his mark to stop the hucks is a role player.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
