<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Sigelman on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/adam-sigelman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adam Sigelman on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/adam-sigelman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chain: Building A Core</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-building-a-core/</guid>
      <description>Good club teams often have a core of stars who have played with each other for a while. Looking at Chain Lightning&amp;rsquo;s roster last year, I was struck by how little turnover the team experienced. With a few notable exceptions, last year&amp;rsquo;s Chain team was the same team that lost in the semifinals in 2008, bolstered by the addition of five rookies, all of whom Chain used in key defensive roles (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Catch To The Hitch</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-catch-to-the-hitch/</guid>
      <description>I have traditionally posted to this website with answers that questioned the question instead of answered it. I feel that I owe Ben and Andy a single straightforward response.
My teams have traditionally fielded the pull with the three handlers. The &amp;ldquo;Catch,&amp;rdquo; not surprisingly, catches the pull. I am surprised how often capable players choose to let pulls hit the ground instead of catching them on the fly. I encourage attempting to catch all but the most vertical of pulls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition From The Grabled Mess</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark is very effective at putting throwers in an uncomfortable position. You&amp;rsquo;ve been working it up the line effectively, dumping when needed, but generally marching up the field. Now, the defense has shifted, and you either have to make a tough break backwards or hope that your resets can break free up the line. The sideline, as the 8th defender, limits your options. Typically in these situations there is a flood of players close to you, as cutters come in for the bail or defenders sag a bit into the lane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Principal Components</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/two-principal-components/</guid>
      <description>To me, Spirit of the Game has two principal components: respect (don&amp;rsquo;t be an ass) and integrity (don&amp;rsquo;t be a cheater). I think you could go through reams of paper defining how those two principles should and do play out, which is not my intent here.
My point is that playing with Spirit is much harder than I think we give it credit for. What we are asking of people is to fight against their ego, their desire for appreciation and status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/improvise/</guid>
      <description>In game two of this year&amp;rsquo;s Eastern Conference Finals against the Orlando Magic, LeBron and the Cavs had a set play. They were down by 2 with seconds left and needed a quick bucket. LeBron was to cut hard to the hoop for an alley-oop. Magic forward Hedo Turkoglu had an idea what would happen and positioned himself between LeBron and the basket. As the play unfolded, LeBron took a few steps towards the rim, and Turkoglu sags off him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Grail Of This Sport</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/the-holy-grail-of-this-sport/</guid>
      <description>Like all things holy, the more you try to explain it with words, the farther you get from its essence&amp;hellip;
Look: If you are on the field and thinking about getting a layout block, you&amp;rsquo;re likely not playing good defense. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is a recipe for getting a layout block . I suppose you could practice, and I have seen people working on their diving and landing techniques. But it also requires a tremendous amount of luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Beating&#34; The Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/-beating-the-mark/</guid>
      <description>When most players think about breaking the mark, they envision a thrower throwing around or over a stationary mark. However, I&amp;rsquo;d argue that the majority of break throws in high level ultimate don&amp;rsquo;t happen this way. Most breaks I see are simple forehands and backhands thrown in motion with the mark trailing behind the thrower.
You can be a great at switching fields with the Frisbee and have terrible &amp;ldquo;break throws&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
