<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tully Beatty on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/tully-beatty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tully Beatty on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/tully-beatty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Them</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/us-vs-them/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the WUFF Warriors defeated FBI from Portland, Oregon 11-6 at Chicago Tune Up. That win was probably the biggest win for a Wilmington club team since the Slickers defeated NY Graffiti at Worlds in 1993 [one could argue that the victory over Philly in the regional final in ’95 was larger, but I’ll take ‘93]. Later that weekend the Warriors defeated Ring of Fire 11-10; the first win over Ring for a Wilmington team since 1996 [though in ’96 they called themselves En Fuego I believe].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury By The Numbers: Conversion &amp; Psyche</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-by-the-numbers-conversion-psyche/</guid>
      <description>Despite Backhoe outscoring Brute Squad 9-7 in the second half after starting out the game 0-6, 2-8 at half, Brute never allowed the game to get ugly [ugly meaning a turnover-fest]. Of the 16 goals (37 possessions) scored between the teams in the second half, 12 were scored on one possession: Backhoe was 8 for 9, Brute was 4 for 7; two of the remaining four were 2nd possession goals. Regardless of our unusual second half efficiency (statistically we were strong on O2D and had a high percentage of Offense 2nd possession [O2] goals), we still walked into our match-up with Fury like a wounded animal looking to make too many corrections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platoon</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/platoon/</guid>
      <description>ECC and Chesapeake are behind us, as is Sectionals. We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past 8 weeks running 120s. We started Cones after Sectionals. In what will have been a mere stepping stone of a game for us, the trust building and empathy through conditioning mentioned above will raise its beautiful head at Regionals, as will the burden of self-officiating.
2nd round and it&amp;rsquo;s 5 all and on serve. hile there are no certainties, except that one that says we&amp;rsquo;ll receive for the 2nd half, they will only score 3 more points to our 10; but at 5 all, nobody but nobody knows this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bide Your Time</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/bide-your-time/</guid>
      <description>D, they say, is for dummies. But no D player worth their salt should have the ability to do anything more than stare at their big toe Saturday night at the hotel. Why? Because they should be too mentally taxed from keeping the stall count each time they step on the field for D. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about counting the stall when marking your assignment; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about keeping the stall when playing D in the stack or spread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May The Best Man Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/may-the-best-man-win/</guid>
      <description>I have an image, indelible perhaps, of UCSC&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Hagar and ECU&amp;rsquo;s Nat Taylor standing before each other after their battle at College Nationals in 1993 [not sure but this game may have decided semis]. Each was covered in grass stains, dirt, sweat, and knowing Hager probably some blood and a new scar. Standing their considering the other, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell who won, except the Slugs had more points.
For the many of us who have played at the top level, and for the many that will one day get there, we know that playing through a Section and a Region and later a National is not unlike getting through each round of a fortnight of tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From The 2000 UPA Finals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/from-the-2000-upa-finals/</guid>
      <description>2000 Open Finals: Condors vs Furious George. It&amp;rsquo;s four even. Mike Grant [of FG] is defended by Corey Sanford. Mike runs a sort of S-cut in the end zone. Jeff Cruicshank with the disc. He seems to look break mark for a righty backhand, then he pivots big for his lefty inside out backhand, throws a quick, strong fake, and then he throws the inside out backhand to Grant. The throw is right in the sweet spot, safely away from Corey&amp;rsquo;s extended hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Careful What You Wish For</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/be-careful-what-you-wish-for/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Be careful what you wish for.&amp;rdquo;
— Ken Dobyns over the phone, NYC to Hampton Bays, August 1995.
Calling the D line that season isn&amp;rsquo;t something I necessarily wished for, but blindly accepted the vacancy; possibly a dumb move for a not proved new face on a second year team still fielding much of the leftover NYNY dynasty. We beat Boston four times that season: Regionals, Tune-up, and two small pre- season tourneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making It Routine</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/making-it-routine/</guid>
      <description>In the sixth grade, I played YMCA basketball and was coached by my classmate/neighbor&amp;rsquo;s father. His sadistic assistant used to routinely fire passes at Billy Nesbitt&amp;rsquo;s head because Billy had such terrible hands; his poor hands caused his braces to cause his mouth to bleed. Sobbing, snot, and blood are not too fun to witness when you&amp;rsquo;re in sixth grade. I never wanted to be anything like poor Billy. I think he&amp;rsquo;s an orthodontist now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone Observations From The NYNY Days</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/zone-observations-from-the-nyny-days/</guid>
      <description>Pike ran an imposing 1-3-3 for a number of years, a set that may or may not have morphed into a 4-man cup at times. Mike Jaeger (formerly of Michigan, currently of Sockeye) was great at the one spot.
The Warrior squad I played for in 2001 ran a 1-3-3 as well and that look got us to Nationals. Rhett Russ also the right man for the one spot. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the 1-3-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Other Sports</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</guid>
      <description>Ring of Fire&amp;rsquo;s Dave Snoke has tremendous footwork. Of course, Dave was a star soccer player for the NC State Wolfpack before switching over to Ultimate so it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise this skill is to his advantage. On offense, he constantly seems to accomplish more with less, taking the least amount of steps to get a big gain or get the O out of a tight situation, time and again. On the D side of things it&amp;rsquo;s not a matter of beating the receiver to the spot, but he excels at the cat and mouse game prior to the cut due to the economy of his footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Answer May Be On The Field Already</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/the-answer-may-be-on-the-field-already/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and assume we&amp;rsquo;re pulling, so that will give our guy what we hope to be two chances to make up for the first half, even the score, and allow us to see if what was said at halftime served any purpose; or was the guy simply standing there nodding his head like a boxer, in one ear and out the other, all the while wondering if he should&amp;rsquo;ve run off to the Honey Bucket or maybe he should put on a different wrist band, maybe someone has some tape he can borrow, maybe some Gu will help, maybe some Red Bull, maybe he should go mess around in his bag and look for something he knows isn&amp;rsquo;t there—the things they didn&amp;rsquo;t carry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers To All Of These Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player? What about as a handler? As a hucker? What would they have to show you to prove their worth?
Sure they do and it depends on their skill set. It&amp;rsquo;s more than likely easier for one to make it as a hucker first; pretty much everyone can huck it. Making it as a primary handler (a &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;) is somewhat tougher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On The Stack Debate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</guid>
      <description>Given the chess game that&amp;rsquo;s taking place, the O should be keeping the D on their toes equally as much, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a matter Of which type of O I&amp;rsquo;d &amp;ldquo;rather&amp;rdquo; run. Considering the conditions are windy enough, I&amp;rsquo;d more than likely prefer the Ho stack mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m thinking the D is coming zone or zone for a certain number of passes. If the D looks to transition after 4/5/6 passes, the secondary outside players are already set in place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
