<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advantages Of A Spread Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-a-spread-offense/</guid>
      <description>Without question, the horizontal offense is a better wind offense. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s the right choice for your team. The horizontal offense offers a couple really nice advantages in a high wind situation, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the personnel to run it, it&amp;rsquo;ll be worse than a vertical offense. Ben wrote &amp;ldquo;equivalent talent,&amp;rdquo; but I ask what talent?
(Quick aside: Sockeye and Furious are the two most effective teams at running the horizontal offense, but they are fundamentally different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advantages Of Either Offensive Set</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-either-offensive-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/advantages-of-either-offensive-set/</guid>
      <description>First and foremost I will say that I am completely biased in favor of a horizontal based offense in a non-windy environment. While there are certain advantages in starting out of a vertical, I believe that a horizontal flow gives players the maximum amount of freedom and space to run the offense. However, in windy conditions (depending on the severity) vertical, if run correctly, does have its advantages.
Provided that the wind isn&amp;rsquo;t brutal (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cater to Your Team&#39;s Particular Skills</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/cater-to-your-team-s-particular-skills/</guid>
      <description>Any offense is difficult in the wind, so when conditions are windy a team should play the offense that it has practiced the most. Both vertical and horizontal stack offenses have advantages and disadvantages in the wind and the decision to play one over the other depends on how well your team can be on the same page while running it&amp;rsquo;s O.
When my team first made the transition from vertical stack to horizontal stack back in 2005, we struggled in the wind and often would switch back to the vert stack when it was windy and we were having difficulty scoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience &amp; Coordination</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/experience-coordination/</guid>
      <description>To my eyes, the advantage of the spread/horizontal is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a whole group of people working together, but can be effective by working in just pairs of upfield cutters or on occasion an isolated receiver. Of course, the better teams will have coordination of all the players, but for a young team, or a team using a new system, things can get up and running effectively with the horizontal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal Stack in Windy Conditions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/horizontal-stack-in-windy-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/horizontal-stack-in-windy-conditions/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure what equivalent talent is but you simply have more options in a HORIZONTAL stack and the cutters are generally all closer to the ball. This is important because all four cutters are options, in and out, almost simultaneously. Additionally, using the field as 4 cutting lanes as opposed to two, for seasoned cutters is easier. The problem is most cutters don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are doing. I think you need to play a lot of Vertical stack to learn how to cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On The Stack Debate</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/my-thoughts-on-the-stack-debate/</guid>
      <description>Given the chess game that&amp;rsquo;s taking place, the O should be keeping the D on their toes equally as much, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a matter Of which type of O I&amp;rsquo;d &amp;ldquo;rather&amp;rdquo; run. Considering the conditions are windy enough, I&amp;rsquo;d more than likely prefer the Ho stack mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m thinking the D is coming zone or zone for a certain number of passes. If the D looks to transition after 4/5/6 passes, the secondary outside players are already set in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts From Australia</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/some-thoughts-from-australia/</guid>
      <description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about this a lot, surprisingly. I find I&amp;rsquo;m generally on a team that&amp;rsquo;s drilled a lot of vertical or drilled a lot of horizontal, so we&amp;rsquo;re better at one particular offence in most conditions.
All other things being equal, horizontal relies on using static structure to create space on the field, whereas vertical relies on cutting (dynamic structure?) to create space on the field.
Wind tends to nullify cutting advantages, so theoretically horizontally should be preferred in the wind, all other things being equal, including your team&amp;rsquo;s ability to play either offence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent Determines Offense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/talent-determines-offense/</guid>
      <description>I would say that the absolute talents of your team will likely favor one offense over the other. If you cannot consistently complete passes greater than forty yards, a stack offense is more favorable than a horizontal. Any situation where the defense no longer has to defend the deep pass puts the horizontal stack offense at a significant disadvantage. This generality can be extrapolated to any situation, not just wind condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vouching For the Vert Stack</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</guid>
      <description>I guess I&amp;rsquo;m pretty old school on this one. One of the main advantages of the horizontal offense is the deep space it affords throwers, particularly once cutters get the disc in their hands. In a crosswind or upwind situation, deep looks for any thrower become less of an option so I would prefer to run the vertical stack. This usually gives the thrower multiple in looks and I find the dump-swing to be much easier out of a vertical set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Team Are We?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/what-kind-of-team-are-we-/</guid>
      <description>I want to first analyze what type of team we are and what type of team we are playing in determining which offense (and defense) to run.
Downwind
Here I generally prefer the horizontal stack, regardless (and variations), as I feel you a thrower is given more choices from nearly every position. Players also tend to overplay defensively when guarding an O that is going downwind which I feel tends to open up cutters underneath and away more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Type of Offense Fits Your Team?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</guid>
      <description>There are numerous factors to consider when deciding whether to run a horizontal stack (HO) or vertical stack (Vert) offense such as: recent success rate with a particular offense against your opponent, probable individual match-ups with your opponent, and how critical the particular point is. In this scenario we are asked to discuss how another factor, wind, affects that decision. Before that discussion, however, it is necessary to look generally at the relative costs and benefits of the Vert versus the HO offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Ho-Stack Is Currently In Favor</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/why-the-ho-stack-is-currently-in-favor/</guid>
      <description>The horizontal stack has all but replaced the vertical stack because it does such a good job of creating space. When run effectively, four cutters typically are spread across the width of the field. This spacing between cutters makes defensive switches very difficult, thereby putting each downfield defender on an island one-on-one with their man. As any cutter will tell you, when you know your defender doesn&amp;rsquo;t have help, you have the advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
