<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brett Matzuka on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/brett-matzuka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brett Matzuka on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/brett-matzuka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tangible vs. Intangible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</guid>
      <description>As cliché as it may be, it is true that the sideline can equate to the eighth man (woman) for a team. However, I would say the sideline can mean much more than just an eighth man. The sideline can be a symbolic representation of the morale and demeanor of the game.
Most speak of the sideline and the tangible benefits of using your voices to motivate and push your teammates in the heat of battle on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate 2-3 Breaks A Game</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/eliminate-2-3-breaks-a-game/</guid>
      <description>Preface: Ever since I started playing competitive Ultimate, I have been on the D team. So, receiving the pull isn&amp;rsquo;t something that I have partaken in very often. That being said, I have done it and can give a viewpoint from a defensive standpoint.
Most important and crucial part of receiving the pull is the reception. I mean pure and simple, having someone there to initially catch the disc. From an offensive standpoint, catching the pull is where the offense begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventative vs. Deceptive</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</guid>
      <description>The most common mark you see on the frisbee field is what I would define as a preventative mark. The mark has each arm extended out fully, explicitly placed to take away a specific throw. This is a useful mark as it does prevent the intended throws and it is seen at every level of frisbee (see photo 1). However, though it is useful, it has certain disadvantages. It allows the thrower to know which throws you are trying to take away before they even attempt to throw or fake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tennis Analogy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/a-tennis-analogy/</guid>
      <description>I usually try to write on the presented topic from a objective and scientific viewpoint, however, due to the nature of this topic, this will be rather subjective and opinionated. Also, much of this is a comparison to tennis since that is where I have participated in the highest levels of competition prior to frisbee.
Growing up learning the sport of Ultimate in Australia, my viewpoint of SOTG comes from a more global perspective of competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beating The Pack From Below The Canopy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/beating-the-pack-from-below-the-canopy/</guid>
      <description>Usually being the shortest guy on the teams I play on, catching 50/50 (jump ball) discs from my perspective is a different game altogether. There are two situations you can encounter with a 50/50 disc. Either you are in the eye of the storm, in which case you were the initial receiver or your the first defender to get into the play, and a multitude of others are collapsing down upon you from all places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change A Losing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/change-a-losing-strategy/</guid>
      <description>First and farmost, attitude is everything. If you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have 7 players who believe you can actually win, then this isnt worth reading and the rest of your game isn&amp;rsquo;t worth playing.
Most teams I have played on, in this situation, would try and load the Defensive line with the top defenders. However, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t just to stop the offense and gain possession, but to actually catch the disc in the endzone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baiting</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/baiting/</guid>
      <description>This is a skill that many of the top defenders possess which generates lots of lay out blocks. There are 3 key components to a successful baited block.
1. Knowing the offense (thrower/cutter)
To many, this is just knowing how far away you can let your player get before you can&amp;rsquo;t make up the ground in time to get a bid on the pass. Knowing how much ground you can make up on your player when the disc goes up is the most important part to knowing the offense; if you can&amp;rsquo;t regain the ground when the disc is thrown, you surely won&amp;rsquo;t get the block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Impact</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-impact/</guid>
      <description>Lets step away from Ultimate, and assume you are playing a card game in which there are five random cards face up on the table and you will get dealt five cards randomly; your job is to pair each one of your cards up with one on the table. There are many ways of doing this (five to be exact!).
Example
Presented on the table: 7 J 3 9 K</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Your Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/utilizing-your-arsenal/</guid>
      <description>Breaking the mark is key to scoring against solid defense and an important factor to any offense. Here are 5 ways to dictate play and gain an advantage over your mark:
1. Expanding your options early (become more threatening)
Since at the beginning of the game the defense is trying to figure out your strengths and weaknesses to properly apply pressure, this is your opportunity to take advantage and become more threatening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-By-Step Approach At Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</guid>
      <description>Understanding that each player is an integral part in the defensive machine precludes all other aspects of defense. Getting everyone on the same page is of utmost importance as 6 players playing together and fulfilling their responsibilities does not equate to a block. So, this is the initial step in teaching team defense.
From here, it is a matter of understanding the defense we are running (zone, man, clam, junk, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Versus Efficient</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/pretty-versus-efficient/</guid>
      <description>From an elementary basketball analogy (sorry readership to those that know a lot about basketball), if everyone is doing their job, the point guard is keeping the ball alive and getting it into the post when available for the forwards and center to finish off. Much like this, in open field, the handlers are keeping the disc alive and looking to get it to the cutters whenever available. To this end, the cutters are the primary workhorses during this phase of the offense by getting the big gains and opening up the downfield.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
