<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Goff on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/adam-goff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adam Goff on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/adam-goff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Basics</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/the-basics/</guid>
      <description>The key goal when receiving the pull is to get into your play/offense as quickly and safely as possible. A few thoughts on how to do this:
Unless the pull is going out of bounds or a big blade in a nice wind, catch it and get it moving. If it&amp;rsquo;s a big blade, stop it as soon as it hits and do the same thing. The only situation which I can think of in which you would not want to do this is if the pull is going to hit and slide out of bounds AND the defense is already set up on all the people you might throw to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Looks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</guid>
      <description>Nothing earth-shattering here, but first and most important: the easiest way to get out of this situation is to avoid it. A good offense recognizes what the D is playing early (see the zone, see the clam, see everything). An anti- reset mark can be set up by the defense several throws ahead. A person sits in the lane, leaving the handler on the sideline open. It&amp;rsquo;s an obvious throw. The first way to avoid this is to have that receiver (the person who would be trapped) move towards the thrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</guid>
      <description>There are a few key tricks that I have found make an effective mark. Some are commonly talked about and pretty well agreed. I do think that not all of these are universally agreed. This is mostly a list of key points, rather than in depth on each one.
The first is mental. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to relax when you get to a mark. It&amp;rsquo;s important to remind yourself that you are responsible for more of the field than any other single defender on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An In-Cut Adjustment Illustrated</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/an-in-cut-adjustment-illustrated/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember ever thinking &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a layout block&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I need to be in a position to get a layout block on this throw.&amp;rdquo; My goal was simply to be in the best position I could be in to cover the person who was my responsibility at the time. I believe that layout blocks are simply &amp;lsquo;opportunities taken&amp;rsquo;—being in the right place at the right time, and the offense made just enough of a mistake for you to go get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/the-right-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>In a person defense, getting the right matchups can be critically important. It can also require some trial and error. Teams which face each other all the time get to try out a number of different approaches until they get most comfortable. Teams that don&amp;rsquo;t see each other often have a challenge at the start—but fortunately both teams have that challenge. The team that figures out how to neutralize (or at least slow down) the key threat from the other team the fastest can get an advantage early in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack Both Sidelines</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/attack-both-sidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/attack-both-sidelines/</guid>
      <description>Offenses used to look to get the disc near the sideline and then attack from there. Teams didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be right on the sideline—with a foot on the edge hoping to attack from there, but a vertical stack offense looks to move the disc to ~5-10 yards from one sideline, take a good long look up field and then swing it around and try the other sideline. This offense can still be effective and all teams should have the ability to use this, even as simply a change of pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal Is To Make It Easy To Score</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-goal-is-to-make-it-easy-to-score/</guid>
      <description>Every time a team moves the disc, this changes the defense. It puts the defensive players out of position, if even for a short period of time. The greater change is better for the offense, and this means putting the disc as far from where the defense wants it to be as possible. If a team is forcing you to throw forehand, and you get a chance to complete a pass straight up field, you just made a good move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Specific Calls To Your D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</guid>
      <description>Rich &amp;ldquo;Farmer&amp;rdquo; Hollingsworth once said that when a team is on offense, seven people is too many (a crowd), but when a team is on defense, seven isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Communication is the extra player, and it&amp;rsquo;s the key to successful team defense. For team defense, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there is a more important skill or a more simple one. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to develop and I have always found it to be really difficult to teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/practical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>When I was calling subs, I also usually was calling the &amp;ldquo;strategy&amp;rdquo; for the points. (Are we playing zone? Are we setting horizontal? Is this point the most critical point ever?). That helped me when it came to determining players based on the roles needed. It also made me pretty tired by the end of the day. How these decisions are made on your team will help dictate who should call subs when the sub-caller goes down with a freak throat injury (Larynxeum andibenitis).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regimented Catching Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/regimented-catching-practice/</guid>
      <description>Just like throwing, catching comes from practice.
How often do you see someone throwing before a game focus really hard on the throw and not on the catch? You&amp;rsquo;ll hear this player swear and scream when they miss a throw, and then catch the throw that came back with one hand while joking with the person next to them.
On Z, we used to do the a throwing medley at the start of every practice and every game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments To The 2-3-2</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/adjustments-to-the-2-3-2/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a favorite zone depends on a few factors, including the personnel on my team, the personnel on the other team, the direction and strength of the wind, and the things the other team are doing that are working. Every team should have two different zone looks in their arsenal, ideally with a well practiced ability to transition out of the zone into a person defense. Choosing a zone is another question though, so I&amp;rsquo;ll go with the classic—the 2-3-2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
