<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Answers To All Of These Questions</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/answers-to-all-of-these-questions/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player? What about as a handler? As a hucker? What would they have to show you to prove their worth?
Sure they do and it depends on their skill set. It&amp;rsquo;s more than likely easier for one to make it as a hucker first; pretty much everyone can huck it. Making it as a primary handler (a &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;) is somewhat tougher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athleticism First, Attitude Close Behind</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/athleticism-first-attitude-close-behind/</guid>
      <description>The most important things I want to see from a tryout are, in no particular order:
Athleticism/speed Field sense Confidence with the disc Ability &amp;amp; willingness to take direction The first point speaks for itself. If a player can&amp;rsquo;t run fast, jump, layout, and exhibit a reasonable level of body control, they don&amp;rsquo;t stand much of a chance.
For field sense, I want to see that a player knows where the next pass is likely to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus On What You Can Control</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</guid>
      <description>Trying out for a club team is like interviewing for any job. There are some things that are in your control and some things that aren’t. It’s important to focus on the things you can control and understand that the other things aren’t worth worrying about. Even if you are a great thrower, if the team already has great throwers then the 6’9&amp;quot; guy that can’t throw may get selected over you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go After Similar, More Experienced Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/go-after-similar-more-experienced-players/</guid>
      <description>I think the first thing that a player should evaluate is their own talents and strengths. During the tryout you should be focusing on accentuating those strengths when given the chance. If you&amp;rsquo;re a tall deep threat, don&amp;rsquo;t waste time in a scrimmage squirelling around the disc, and in any huck drill make sure you are going up strong to show that you can climb. If you&amp;rsquo;re a squirrely quick guy, make sure you are getting open on all short cuts, and that if there are any sprints to be done that you are winning them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Work Stands Out</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</guid>
      <description>At tryouts, I am looking for someone who will fit into the TOP HALF of our roster if they are a new player. I prefer having all-team tryouts so that each member, even if they have played on the team previously, brings great intensity to tryouts — this is the best way to start a season (and the most fair way to choose a team).
In terms of skills, this means you need to have all the basics without flaw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective From The Team &amp; From A Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/perspective-from-the-team-from-a-player/</guid>
      <description>A couple of thoughts that I always have when tryouts roll around:
Any young player that wants to improve should be trying out for any team possible. Tryout ultimate is typically intense, cheap, and with players that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally play with. This can be an amazing opportunity to improve&amp;hellip;especially with experienced players available that are motivated (or at least ready) to give constructive feedback. This can be a great opportunity for developing players, regardless of your own chances of making the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play To Your Best, Tone Down The Rest</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/play-to-your-best-tone-down-the-rest/</guid>
      <description>You have to ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What do I do that is great?&amp;rdquo; This is your ticket onto a team. For most young players, this is blue-collar Ultimate: tough D, swing passes and safe choices. If what you have to offer is something different (big throws, great recievership), then showcase those skills.
The two quickest ways to get yourself cut are poor atheleticism (nothing much to be done about that) and poor choices with the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Fundamentals Trump Team Needs</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/strong-fundamentals-trump-team-needs/</guid>
      <description>Tryouts are such a weird time for me. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting the season is starting and so many people want to tryout for our team, but at the same time the decisions can be stressful and as much pressure as one might feel when trying out, the team is also some amount of pressure on the team being tried out to find a good fit. Since there are a few different options in Boston, it is very important for our team to put our best foot forward and we try to do it as accurately as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things To Focus On At Any Level</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/things-to-focus-on-at-any-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/things-to-focus-on-at-any-level/</guid>
      <description>Here are my six recommendations to anyone who is trying out for a team of any level:
1. Be on time and have all of the appropriate equipment for the tryout.
2. Relax — tryouts are a high stress process for everyone involved, but as a captain/coach I&amp;rsquo;m looking to see how players handle themselves throughout the process. Tryouts are a decent representation of how players will handle high-stress situations during tournaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Chris Ashbrook</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-chris-ashbrook/</guid>
      <description>Do young players have any chance of making the team as an offensive player?
Absolutely. There are a number of college players that have now played on club teams while still in college (Watson, Heijman, Cahill, Gibson, etc), some while in high school. These players are usually the best offensive players on their teams and have been to college nationals, at least once, if not multiple times. Although they may have inexperience on the club seen, they have crunch time experience and are able to eventually translate that to the club scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts From Team USA Tryouts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on this topic are at the front of my mind today!
Advice to tryouts:
1. Distinguish yourself on defense, even if you consider yourself an offensive player. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the offensive system of the new team, you can always make an impression on D. In particular, focus on marks and shut-down defense.
Be the defender who uses intelligence, positioning, and quickness to prevent his guy from getting open for uncontested passes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
