<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kris Kelly on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/kris-kelly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kris Kelly on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/kris-kelly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Defensive Assets</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/maximizing-defensive-assets/</guid>
      <description>Know your foe.
There are lots of ways you can get the most out of your defensive matchups and it starts with not only knowing your own players but also knowing your opponents. The more familiar you are with the opposing team&amp;rsquo;s offensive weapons ahead of time, the better you can prepare to counter them quickly and effectively. Furthermore, as important as it is to recognize primary play makers, it&amp;rsquo;s just as important to know how the rest of your roster compares overall to the other team&amp;rsquo;s personnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Theory &amp; A Lot Of Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</guid>
      <description>It can be easy to make excuses for not playing team defense in Mixed Ultimate, especially in man-to-man set-ups. About half the people on the field you would never choose to mark up on/cover prior to the pull, the people you want to set up switches with may not be the closest people to you, and the person in the best position to help you might not be the obvious choice given the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Thrower, Make It Easy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/know-your-thrower-make-it-easy/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about cutting in the endzone, the first thing to consider is if you even should cut. You have to assess where the space is and the convenience of your angle to that space. You need to know who your thrower is and what they are comfortable with (if you cut to where you intend to cut, will the thrower have the throw to hit you accurately enough for it to be a score?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trap Hard &amp; Smart</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/trap-hard-smart/</guid>
      <description>A trap cup zone is a common and effective configuration in Mixed Ultimate. It looks to create pressure and mismatches at the disc. The handlers, who touch the disc most in zone offense, are depended upon by the rest of the team to be consistent and unflappable when working a zone D. An aggressive trap cup can serve to fluster and frustrate the handlers, whether it&amp;rsquo;s because they themselves are having trouble moving the disc or because others are having trouble getting them the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
