<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Prescribed Rotation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/a-prescribed-rotation/</guid>
      <description>In this situation, it seems that it would be best to prescribe some movement, team-wide, which will give the thrower some better options than &amp;ldquo;turn to the dump.&amp;rdquo; Expressing some coordinated movement where all players (or at least those around the disc) have certain responsibilities will help clear up confusion and provide purpose to people&amp;rsquo;s movement.
On a previous team I played for, we had very specific dump rotations, and we ran a specific rotation for the first half and then switched that movement at halftime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>A good offense should be able to reset against even a very good defense. If we&amp;rsquo;re having trouble resetting, chances are that we&amp;rsquo;re suffering from a problem of our own making: either A. The design of our reset protocol is flawed; or B. We&amp;rsquo;re executing it poorly. †
A. There are many effective ways to reset a disc, but any effective way will probably have these elements:
The reset cutters give the thrower at least two options, simultaneously or in close succession, such that the marker must leave at least one throw open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipating The Throw</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/anticipating-the-throw/</guid>
      <description>One of the attributes of teams that do well at Nationals and other high-level tournaments is their handler defense. Many teams can do a pretty good job at containing handlers (e.g. getting the mark on to stop upfield break throws, adjusting to stop give-go&amp;rsquo;s, preventing up-the-line cuts). However, I think there are only a few teams that have the personnel and strategy to consistently pressure and generate D&amp;rsquo;s on handler resets—this includes pressure on both the thrower who may or may not be a handler, and on the actual handler who makes the reset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Your Rhythm &amp; Your Roles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/challenge-your-rhythm-your-roles/</guid>
      <description>Three thoughts.
First, this is just the way high pressure games are. As the stakes increase, the defense ratchets up and the offense needs to ratchet up accordingly. How do you do this? Be mentally strong. The best path to this kind of mental fortitude is playing in and winning these games. The second best path (and the one reserved for those not on championship teams) is practicing all out. You play how you practice, so if you challenge yourself and your teammates every practice, you gameday performance will be correspondingly superior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic &amp; Potential Energy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</guid>
      <description>I believe that good chemistry between handlers can affect the game more than at any other position. Having two or three experienced handlers that really know each other is such an advantage because they likely have withstood defensive pressure like this before and they likely have talked about it and figured out, between them, how to deal with it. Because they can predict what the other is going to do, they don&amp;rsquo;t panic when the stall count gets higher and they can reset the disc accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor &amp; Major Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/minor-major-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>My first impression of this situation would be to not over-react. There have been close calls, and one turn on handler cuts. If you are getting close to, or are already at the half, this is a pretty good tally to have, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make major changes.
Some small things to consider:
If the other team is counting the stall quickly (most likely the case), the thrower should make the fast-count call as he turns to the dump, or earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement, Movement, Movement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/movement-movement-movement/</guid>
      <description>The best way to attack a team that is playing good shut-down defense is to keep the disc moving, and moving quickly. This is not a novel concept by any means, but it&amp;rsquo;s rare that a team actually hits the first open pass consistently. Throwers tend to get antsy if you&amp;rsquo;re not gaining yardage and instead of looking to get rid of the frisbee, will instead hold it looking for something upfiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>When this happens I need to assess what about our reset isn&amp;rsquo;t working before I change anything. Generally, there are a few problems that are typical of this sort of situation.
The dump is not working hard enough. This is actually not the most likely explanation, but it does happen. This typically results from lack of readiness—the dump fails to get to position in a timely matter, or relies on the thrower to thread the needle rather than actually getting open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial &amp; Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/trial-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>If this is in the middle of an elimination game, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to make an effective adjustment, it needs to be simple. It sounds like the defence is playing particularly tight around the disc, and putting enough pressure downfield to force us to take bad looks. If this is the case, these are probably the things I would try early on:
Look for the reset earlier in the count.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
