<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miranda Roth on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/miranda-roth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miranda Roth on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/miranda-roth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Warm-Up Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-033/three-warm-up-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>While others may be more concerned with adjustments for each game, specific plyometrics, or the most useful drills, I have 3 solid beliefs on fundamentals of warm-ups:
Try to do the same thing for each game. No matter what you may include in your warm-ups, teams and individuals respond well to a routine. This way players don’t have to focus too much on the timing or progression of warm-ups and can instead focus on their skills, body and/or uncontrollables around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Will Change Every Season</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-032/it-will-change-every-season/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to realize about your team’s culture is that it will change every season.
Yes, I was concerned when I first joined Riot that I might never fit into the intense, upfront grind of the kickass East Coast transplant women, but the team has changed a great deal in the past 7 years. Riot has become a weird, unique, open-nearly-to-a-fault bunch of weenies (young and old) who’d rather drink Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loud &#43; Positive = Good</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</guid>
      <description>I think that sideline contributions are underrated in their worth by most teams and particularly by most great players. People who are great at team sports are not necessarily motivated to play well for themselves – especially in our sport, they are motivated to play well by their love of team, teammates and something bigger than themselves.
In this way, I will stand by something I accidentally said in a huddle last year: &amp;ldquo;Loud information is good information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fury Knows How To Win</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/fury-knows-how-to-win/</guid>
      <description>Fury, more than any other Women&amp;rsquo;s team in the nation (perhaps ever, though there will be those who argue for Godiva or Maineiacs), knows what to do in Sarasota.
Each player seems to have a very good grasp of her specific role from the top of the roster to the bottom. Everyone plays that role perfectly when push comes to shove. They don&amp;rsquo;t mess around against teams they know they will beat, and they bring it hard to teams that might have entertained thoughts of having a chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retain That!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/retain-that-/</guid>
      <description>To catch a 50/50 disc, you need to somehow make the chances better than 50/50 for yourself. The first thing you can do is be tall—and yes, I know you can&amp;rsquo;t teach height, but this also includes putting your hand up outstretched and trying to catch the disc at your &amp;ldquo;tallest point&amp;rdquo; including your jump. This is related to the second thing which is timing your jump. I know lots of players (particularly new women) who think just putting their hand up will work—well, it won&amp;rsquo;t work against good competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countering &amp; Changing Defenses</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/countering-changing-defenses/</guid>
      <description>While I have not been personally very successful in this situation, other teams have been successful at times against my teams so I can tell you what it seems like they did. You must call tight lines—having players in the games that can create Ds and capitalize on them is imperative. Now is not the time to give players a chance to show their stuff for the first time—use people that are tried and true on D and O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/footwork/</guid>
      <description>The skill I&amp;rsquo;ve used most and tried to teach my players more than any other part of getting a layout block (aside from the obvious WANTING IT BAD part) is the footwork required to get a layout block. The obvious problem about getting a layout D is that you are trying to get to something that is being blocked by your offense&amp;rsquo;s body. I think getting a layout D without getting called for a foul/hurting anyone is huge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Practice For Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/effective-practice-for-zone/</guid>
      <description>Zone offense is very difficult to simulate in practice. The skills necessary for zone are often quite different than for man (offense and defense). For zone O, you need to practice vision, patience and confidence which are quite difficult to simulate. For the most part, we usually teach zone O by drawing it up on a white board, going over it on the field and then doing LOTS of 5/10-pulls sometimes stopping the point to reposition people, especially in the early parts of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Best Part Of Each Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</guid>
      <description>The best example of a role player on Riot is Michelle Bowlen. Michelle is very tall (5&#39;11&amp;quot;), well-trained in fundamentals and particularly smart (Fulbright Scholar!). She doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best break-mark throws in the game and can&amp;rsquo;t guard every quick little handler. However, she is the scariest mark I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in a 1-3-3. Luckily, we play in bad weather conditions at Sectionals, Regionals and Nationals (usually) so we can run a lot of zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shimmy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/the-shimmy/</guid>
      <description>My favorite move, that is very popular and can be used by any player, is the shimmy flick. This is a move that I was taught at Carleton but is based on principles that I learned in my first sport, basketball. In basketball as a defender, you are always taught to look at the offense&amp;rsquo;s belly-button because that is the hardest part of the body to fake with. You can get faked out if you look at the ball, the player&amp;rsquo;s head, feet or hands, but the belly button&amp;rsquo;s not going anywhere unless the whole player is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication &amp; Vision</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</guid>
      <description>I think there are two skills that can take a player from a good defender to a great defender and they both have to do with the transition from an individually good defender to a good team defender.
1. Communication. Silent defenders will never be great defenders. This includes &amp;ldquo;up,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;switch&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;last back&amp;rdquo; calls. This is particularly important in zone defense for wings and deeps. To practice this, I sometimes require players to be saying something continuously during a defensive drill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Move</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-012/my-favorite-move/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m usually thinking, &amp;ldquo;Get open on the open side.&amp;rdquo;
When fatigue sets in, throws and finesse are the first thing to go and open side throws are generally easier. Cutters can push through fatigue with desire and brute strength. So, to get open on the open side, I usually start facing the thrower, juke hard toward the defender (they are on their heels), take a few steps really hard to the break side (this usually lures the off-balance defender to commit to the break side), then explode past them to the open side (this may require some stepping past/running through limbs of your defender).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Backhands</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</guid>
      <description>I am going to focus on a long backhand because that is my best long throw, but I think that a lot of the principles hold for long forehands and pulls as well.
I&amp;rsquo;m all about maximizing torque when throwing—using rotation to generate power flowing into your throw. On a long backhand the first point is to step out so that when you twist your body you&amp;rsquo;re not killing your defender with a giant elbow to the face (this is easier for tall players—shorter players should focus on a quick stepout).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sub-Calling Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/my-sub-calling-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>1. If you pick the right personnel, there will always be a time when you can play each player. Think about when these times are for each player on your team and allow them to excel in these situations.
2. Be clear to your teammates about the team&amp;rsquo;s sub-calling philosophy. If it changes for a tournament, don&amp;rsquo;t make it a hush hush operation—let everyone know so nothing is a surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting An Extra Foot Of Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/getting-an-extra-foot-of-space/</guid>
      <description>I think that for me, the main catching technique that can be practiced (and that I have learned from coaches and taught to players) is attacking the discs with two hands, thumbs down claw-style. When I was in high school, my coach Michael Baccarini used to always say that any catch you can clap, you can catch at least a foot further in front of you if you reach out with your pinchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-four-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>For most of my teams (coaching and playing) we have been most comfortable in a 4-person cup recently. The goal with this zone is to prevent throws through the cup or around it with yardage gainers—we want to force the throws backward and we want to force a lot of them. I was taught to see this as a math problem—even the simplest throw will only be completed 99% of the time (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>The player that has excellent footwork in my mind has a football and track background. He has great body positioning while cutting that I think leads to his strong footwork. His cuts are strong as a result of pushing his weight into the ground and exploding after getting low and chopping his feet. This helps his play because I believe he is able to get open on players that are bigger and stronger and faster than him by using good technical footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/three-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>When this happens I need to assess what about our reset isn&amp;rsquo;t working before I change anything. Generally, there are a few problems that are typical of this sort of situation.
The dump is not working hard enough. This is actually not the most likely explanation, but it does happen. This typically results from lack of readiness—the dump fails to get to position in a timely matter, or relies on the thrower to thread the needle rather than actually getting open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play The Player First, Then The Disc</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/play-the-player-first-then-the-disc/</guid>
      <description>When I hear the up-call, my first instinct is to get between my player and where I think the disc is going to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t look for the disc yet because the disc is secondary to my player when I&amp;rsquo;m on defense. If I can get my body into the proper position, I will get the disc every time.
Typically in this situation, I will try to make some kind of body contact (not with arms or legs)—jockeying for position using my butt or shoulders to maintain my position between my player and the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Lose A Game Without</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/never-lose-a-game-without/</guid>
      <description>As a wise woman once said (props to those who get the joke), never lose a game without playing zone. I think this thought answers the question but taken to a broader sense: never get beat over and over again without changing something.
So your scouting report was wrong or the team has adjusted to all their opponents having the same scouting report on their strong player. This happens very often with great, specialized players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Work Stands Out</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/hard-work-stands-out/</guid>
      <description>At tryouts, I am looking for someone who will fit into the TOP HALF of our roster if they are a new player. I prefer having all-team tryouts so that each member, even if they have played on the team previously, brings great intensity to tryouts — this is the best way to start a season (and the most fair way to choose a team).
In terms of skills, this means you need to have all the basics without flaw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vouching For the Vert Stack</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/vouching-for-the-vert-stack/</guid>
      <description>I guess I&amp;rsquo;m pretty old school on this one. One of the main advantages of the horizontal offense is the deep space it affords throwers, particularly once cutters get the disc in their hands. In a crosswind or upwind situation, deep looks for any thrower become less of an option so I would prefer to run the vertical stack. This usually gives the thrower multiple in looks and I find the dump-swing to be much easier out of a vertical set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
