<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Van Heuvelen on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ben-van-heuvelen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ben Van Heuvelen on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ben-van-heuvelen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</guid>
      <description>In the moment of competition, I like my brain to be functioning on approximately the level of a caveman chasing a woolly mammoth. The biggest motivation to help from the sideline is that the louder I yell, the more primordial I feel, and the better I play. It’s the best way for me to get in and stay in &amp;ldquo;the zone.&amp;rdquo;
Here is a great description of the zone, which I recently read in a novel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut &amp; Clear</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</guid>
      <description>When we&amp;rsquo;re facing a &amp;ldquo;rotated&amp;rdquo; mark paired with good up-line dump defense, we have to do a few things to win.
First, we have to cut and clear decisively. The defensive tactic succeeds if it forces the handlers to &amp;ldquo;dance,&amp;rdquo; clogging the reset lane and creating uncertainty for the thrower. Even if the handlers have nowhere to run but towards the defense, they must run. Often times, the defense isn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as it looks and the handler can swim past the up-line defender, or the thrower can shimmy to open up the around-break throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond The Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the fundamentals of marking—getting low with the hips, staying balanced, keeping arms wide—here are a few &amp;ldquo;advanced fundamental&amp;rdquo; techniques.
1. Chin up, eyes on the chest. My hand is much more likely to find its way in front of the disc when I&amp;rsquo;m only &amp;ldquo;looking&amp;rdquo; with my peripheral vision. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this works so well. In part, I think it&amp;rsquo;s because good throwers use disc fakes to get you out of position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Goes Through Your Head</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/what-goes-through-your-head/</guid>
      <description>Last year at Northeast Regionals my team (PoNY) was playing Bodhi to go to Nationals. Game tied at 12s, time cap approaching, PoNY is on defense. Bodhi goes on a fast break with a quick succession of give-go throws—&amp;ldquo;Pick!&amp;rdquo; someone yells—and the last throw, a huck, falls incomplete. The two teams start to argue. Was the pick two throws ago, or one? Does the disc go back to Bodhi, or is it a turnover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Fundamentals Of Zone O</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/personal-fundamentals-of-zone-o/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll write here about the fundamentals of good zone O. These will, I hope, reveal some underlying principles that any team can apply to its specific strategy/terminology, and to specific situations (e.g., how to deal with a sideline trip). I&amp;rsquo;ll rely on my co-contributors to address those specifics in detail, and read with interest!
So, getting down to basics&amp;hellip;
To figure out how our zone offense should work, we should think about what makes good zone defense successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depends On The Offensive System</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/depends-on-the-offensive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/depends-on-the-offensive-system/</guid>
      <description>The value of the sideline space depends on the offense. In a horizontal offense, the sideline limits your options. In a vertical offense, it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to be—until it isn&amp;rsquo;t.
Horizontal
From a downfield cutter&amp;rsquo;s perspective, one unique benefit of the horizontal offense is that it lets you make cuts across the mark. With so much uncrowded horizontal space between the cutters and the thrower, you can threaten an open-side cut, then change direction to receive a breakmark pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Your Weakness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/addressing-your-weakness/</guid>
      <description>A good offense should be able to reset against even a very good defense. If we&amp;rsquo;re having trouble resetting, chances are that we&amp;rsquo;re suffering from a problem of our own making: either A. The design of our reset protocol is flawed; or B. We&amp;rsquo;re executing it poorly. †
A. There are many effective ways to reset a disc, but any effective way will probably have these elements:
The reset cutters give the thrower at least two options, simultaneously or in close succession, such that the marker must leave at least one throw open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train For The Launch Pad</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/train-for-the-launch-pad/</guid>
      <description>More than any other skill in ultimate—besides, maybe, getting layout blocks—dominating in the air has largely to do with raw athleticism, aggressiveness, and instinct. There&amp;rsquo;s really no substitute for being a physical beast. If you&amp;rsquo;re tall and fast, and you have springs for legs, you&amp;rsquo;re going to posterize some poor souls, and in the process you&amp;rsquo;ll develop confidence and intuition that you&amp;rsquo;ll bring into every future matchup.
So: train. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not a premium genetic specimen, effective training can bring out the inner beast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defensive Goals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/defensive-goals/</guid>
      <description>On defense, your goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to shut down all options , because that&amp;rsquo;s impossible against a good offense. Rather, your goal is to dictate to the offense those options it can take. So, the first thing to realize here is: if Big Thrower hasn&amp;rsquo;t been able to make big throws, you&amp;rsquo;ve done something successful.
The question to ask yourself now: Is Big Thrower hurting us more now as a deep receiver than he/she usually does as a thrower?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts From Team USA Tryouts</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/thoughts-from-team-usa-tryouts/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on this topic are at the front of my mind today!
Advice to tryouts:
1. Distinguish yourself on defense, even if you consider yourself an offensive player. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the offensive system of the new team, you can always make an impression on D. In particular, focus on marks and shut-down defense.
Be the defender who uses intelligence, positioning, and quickness to prevent his guy from getting open for uncontested passes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
