<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jim Parinella on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jim-parinella/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jim Parinella on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jim-parinella/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make It Useful</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</guid>
      <description>Basic principles of sideline talk are fairly simple: make it targeted (say the player’s name first), make it specific (not just &amp;ldquo;c’mon, go, go&amp;rdquo;), and give information (not instruction). You may not know what the player already knows and is planning, so this lets him decide what to do and how to handle the info. (Sometimes, if the level of trust is high, off-field players can give instructions rather than information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn To Think So You Don&#39;t Have To Think</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/learn-to-think-so-you-don-t-have-to-think/</guid>
      <description>How do we make decisions? In many real-life examples we create a list of choices and features, maybe take some data, rate how each option stacks up in each feature, and coolly select the optimum choice. In ultimate you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to go through this whole process. You have to rely on your trained inner self to figure out what to do based on internalized guidelines.
Since I like lists of rules here are some for making sense of what is happening on the field and figuring out what to do about it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain: The New DoG</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-028/chain-the-new-dog/</guid>
      <description>During DoG&amp;rsquo;s heyday 15 years ago, our main offensive strength was that we would take what they&amp;rsquo;d give us. Our offense was efficient, not just in terms of scoring percentage, but in using energy wisely. Players created space by knowing when to get out of the way or to simply stay put and remain out of the way. We liked the long game, but were equally comfortable in taking a series of passes up the line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
