<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build From Versatile, Athletic Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</guid>
      <description>Not everyone can be great at everything and some become very good at a few things. There are times where we have a few players who are very, very good at a particular position - whether defensive or offensive. For example, I have been on teams where we have a few players who sole purpose in life is to give the handlers on the other team h***. That is their job, and is why they are on the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Hope For The Specialist?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</guid>
      <description>I started playing for Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Sockeye in the Spring of 2007. Among the great athletes and throwers and minds one thing stood out the most—an almost singular obsession on beating their main rival, Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s Furious George. Throwers needed to have five options because at nationals, against Furious, you could be sure four would not be open. Three-step separations were not enough, because Oscar and Alex could make it one. Running trap zone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needs Of The Team And The Individual</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/needs-of-the-team-and-the-individual/</guid>
      <description>Role players are valuable to any successful team. More than valuable, they may be essential. This is typically because they have the ability to throw their whole effort into a part of the game that the stars don&amp;rsquo;t have the effort for. An obvious example of this is a marker in the zone. Marking takes a lot of effort, and is very tiring both because of chasing the disc around, but also because working hard on the mark takes a lot of energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles Can Be Difficult To Observe</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-can-be-difficult-to-observe/</guid>
      <description>Apart from specific match-ups on defense that require certain roles (being tall and fast, or short and quick), there are lots of roles in zone defenses and in some offensive sets. The best example I can think of is the marker on a trap-side zone defense. This is the position that anchors the zone when it is within 5 yards of the sideline, and can make or break the scheme. This person has the opportunity to take away more options that any other defensive player on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles From Necessity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/roles-from-necessity/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting topic as the need for specialized roles has been born more out of necessity than out of desire in Vancouver.
Historically, the top players on Furious have been the players who excel at multiple aspects of the game. These players have been able to fulfill multiple roles, and truly have a very strong all-around game. Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s fast pace of play combined with multiple turnovers and unforeseen situations, calls for players on the field to be able to adapt and excel regardless of the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use All Of Your Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/use-all-of-your-players/</guid>
      <description>I believe that what makes a team successful is its ability to use all of its players. Most good teams have a few superstars- those players that are game- changers and whose absence can really hurt the team&amp;rsquo;s chances. However, the difference between good teams and great teams, I believe, lies in how the team utilizes its role players. Ultimate is truly a team sport, and if the top players on a team aren&amp;rsquo;t supported by a solid and confident group of role players, the team will have many exploitable weaknesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Best Part Of Each Player</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/using-the-best-part-of-each-player/</guid>
      <description>The best example of a role player on Riot is Michelle Bowlen. Michelle is very tall (5&#39;11&amp;quot;), well-trained in fundamentals and particularly smart (Fulbright Scholar!). She doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best break-mark throws in the game and can&amp;rsquo;t guard every quick little handler. However, she is the scariest mark I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in a 1-3-3. Luckily, we play in bad weather conditions at Sectionals, Regionals and Nationals (usually) so we can run a lot of zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is A Role Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/what-is-a-role-player-/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen certain players take over games, throwing hucks, getting lay out Ds, or getting open against good defenders. These players are revered. What is a role player? Everyone else.
I avoid using the term &amp;ldquo;role player&amp;rdquo; because it implies a value judgment on those players who don&amp;rsquo;t get the glory. The player who throws hucks isn&amp;rsquo;t a role player. The player who uses his mark to stop the hucks is a role player.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
