<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lindsey Hack on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/lindsey-hack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lindsey Hack on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/lindsey-hack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Left &amp; Right Options</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-027/left-right-options/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I would be very intrigued to hear the Open authors&amp;rsquo; answers on this question because, for the most part, Women&amp;rsquo;s pulls do not involve a ridiculous amount of rocket science to field (or maybe I have been missing out on something for years).
Typically, we will call a pull play where one person on the left side of the field fields the pull if it goes left and one person on the right side of the field fields the pull if it goes right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even If No One Is Watching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/even-if-no-one-is-watching/</guid>
      <description>Really, honestly, how can anyone possibly not believe that this is a worthy philosophy to embrace? The only thing that kills me is the the name: &amp;ldquo;Spirit of the Game.&amp;rdquo; The word spirit is not synomynous with common words and expressions I associate with sports: Grit - Battle - Fair - Integrity - Determination - Motivation - Guts - Glory - Respect. &amp;ldquo;Spirit&amp;rdquo; is a word that I would associate with yoga class, folklore, or a Bible Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Priorities</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-023/catching-priorities/</guid>
      <description>In order to catch a 50/50 disc a player needs to be able to do a number of things correctly to win the battle.
1. Reading
The player must be able to read the disc and understand how the wind and the way the disc was thrown is going to affect its flight path.
2. Positioning
Once that player has a good grasp of where that disc is going to float down to earth, that player must establish that position firmly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity, Creatvity</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/simplicity-creatvity/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play great is simplicity and creativity. It should be designed to have a main cut, but also a bail out. It should be taught on paper, on a whiteboard, with walk-throughs and at full speed. In the past, we have relied more on designing our own plays. My women&amp;rsquo;s club team has minimal to no plays, but the college team I coach has a playbook that they rely on probably 20% of the time off a dead disc situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short, Aggresive Risks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/short-aggresive-risks/</guid>
      <description>As a coach, I feel it is necessary to take some risks defensively and call a few different defensive looks that may create enough confusion and lead to a quick turnover by the offense. If you have been playing man the entire game, try a little zone. If you have been forcing one way the entire time, try some middle or straight up. At that point, you must try something different to get the other team out of their comfort zone because clearly, they are comfortable right now in the driver&amp;rsquo;s seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepping For A 4-Person Cup</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/prepping-for-a-4-person-cup/</guid>
      <description>A zone defense is usually designed to only give the offense options that do not play to their strengths (i.e. working it laterally, taking away speed, or breaking the mark into the wind). I have been on women&amp;rsquo;s teams before that have had a very difficult time with the four person cup in a moderately windy (cross wind) situation. Typically, the defense would trap the downwind sideline making it difficult for the thrower to break the cup not only because there are four big defensive players near them, but also because there is a wind in their face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Rotate Or Not To Rotate?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/to-rotate-or-not-to-rotate-/</guid>
      <description>To rotate or not to rotate? That is the question. Well, that depends on what type of game we are talking about. If we are talking about semis at Nationals, and I have a great downfield defender and the other team has a great downfield offensive player, then my defender is going to be on that offensive player for as long as they are effective. If this is pool play at Nationals, than I feel like it is somewhat necessary to share the load for fear that you may wear out your best defensive player during Day One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Room For Error</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/no-room-for-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/no-room-for-error/</guid>
      <description>Typically, our offense thinks of the sideline as a trap if we are being forced to that sideline. Given the right thrower, it could be a land of opportunity as it is much easier to destroy a defense with one break throw from the trap sideline. But, given that there are few throwers that skilled on a team, as a whole, the sideline is viewed as a trap.
The sideline is a trap because it gives throwers who do not consistently break the mark a very small window to work with when throwing to an in-cutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build From Versatile, Athletic Players</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/build-from-versatile-athletic-players/</guid>
      <description>Not everyone can be great at everything and some become very good at a few things. There are times where we have a few players who are very, very good at a particular position - whether defensive or offensive. For example, I have been on teams where we have a few players who sole purpose in life is to give the handlers on the other team h***. That is their job, and is why they are on the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allowing Mistakes, Deceiving Marks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-014/allowing-mistakes-deceiving-marks/</guid>
      <description>What is your favorite &amp;lsquo;move&amp;rsquo; for breaking the mark? How do you do it, and in what situations do you find it most useful?
To break the mark, I typically like to convince, or deceive, the mark that I am going to throw a different throw than what I want.
For example, if I am being forced flick and I want to throw the around backhand break, I will get into a very threatening inside out forehand flick position.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
