<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seth Wiggins on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/seth-wiggins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seth Wiggins on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/seth-wiggins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits Of Theft</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/the-benefits-of-theft/</guid>
      <description>Steal, steal, steal. If you are the smartest play to have ever played the game, you may have reason to rely on your own originality. If not, find out who is—be it player, team, or just a better division—and how they position themselves to be successful. Any stoppage of play, between points, after timeouts, after violations, will allow you to see what they want to do, given the context on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defense From The Handler Spot</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-021/defense-from-the-handler-spot/</guid>
      <description>A great defensive handler first and foremost plays defense. The defensive unit will only get a handful of opportunities to try to score; most of their time spent on the field will be defending. To be valuable to their team, a defensive handler will need to produce more than they give up, and the offense has a big advantage to start with. Effective defending from a variety of positions is well covered in other issues of The Huddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretically Helpful Exercise</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/a-theoretically-helpful-exercise/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t really answer these questions. The right answers depend on too many factors, many of which can only be judged during your game. Variables such as individual&amp;rsquo;s athleticism, defensive abilities, your opponent&amp;rsquo;s strengths, current conditions, number of defenders available, ect, are all part of the equation.
Having an answer to these questions is hard, but judging the quality of your answer is even harder. At best it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly difficult to evaluate results based on your coaching input alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Hope For The Specialist?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-015/is-there-any-hope-for-the-specialist-/</guid>
      <description>I started playing for Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Sockeye in the Spring of 2007. Among the great athletes and throwers and minds one thing stood out the most—an almost singular obsession on beating their main rival, Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s Furious George. Throwers needed to have five options because at nationals, against Furious, you could be sure four would not be open. Three-step separations were not enough, because Oscar and Alex could make it one. Running trap zone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downfield 1-On-1 Defense</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-011/downfield-1-on-1-defense/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re downfield, the disc has stopped, and you&amp;rsquo;re defending a cutter in the middle of a flat stack. You&amp;rsquo;ll need all the speed, agility, and strength you have—long before the point begins you can better your odds by improving your physical ability. Chances are if you are reading this you know how.
Although Ultimate is a team game, the flat stack does a good job at isolating one-on-one matchups. While switching and poaching can work against weaker offensive teams, intelligent ones will be able to change the position of both the disc and their cutters quicker than you can react, and will beat your defense without much effort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
