<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advice For Improvement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/advice-for-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I am writing in about this topic not because I am a great distance thrower. In fact I am quite the opposite. Throwing the disc was something that I did with much trepidation for many years. In fact I was ridiculed constantly by my teammates for not being able to throw a simple backhand (which is why my scoober is a decent throw for me now).
However, over the years I have improved in this area and I do have some advice to pass along to others who struggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Every Huck</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/complete-every-huck/</guid>
      <description>I think a lot of people focus too much on how to throw the disc far rather than on how to complete their hucks. A lot of time, players will spend hours practicing throwing the disc really far, but then they don&amp;rsquo;t make disciplined decisions during a game about when to use those hucks. There are three questions to ask yourself before unleashing any bomb if you want to increase the chances of completing that huck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face A Mark</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/face-a-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/face-a-mark/</guid>
      <description>The most important part of throwing for distance is learning to do so while facing a mark. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for many players to throw 40+ yards unmarked, but when someone&amp;rsquo;s standing in front of you, it becomes much more difficult.
Begin your backhand motion with your hips and follow through with your shoulder and arm. I&amp;rsquo;m a proponent of bringing the disc straight from the wind- up point to the release point, as opposed to a more arced path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Chris Page</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/find-your-chris-page/</guid>
      <description>You need Chris Page. Chris who? Remember back when Sockeye was good the first time? Back in the 90s and you watched those epic battles on NBC? Dreaming of how it was gonna be you? Sockeye-Double Happiness? Sockeye-Rhino? All those heart-breakers against DoG? Remember that shaggy headed blonde kid ripping it forehand, backhand, marked, didn&amp;rsquo;t matter? That was Chris Page.
When I hit the big time in 96, I had some power, but no control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Backhands</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/long-backhands/</guid>
      <description>I am going to focus on a long backhand because that is my best long throw, but I think that a lot of the principles hold for long forehands and pulls as well.
I&amp;rsquo;m all about maximizing torque when throwing—using rotation to generate power flowing into your throw. On a long backhand the first point is to step out so that when you twist your body you&amp;rsquo;re not killing your defender with a giant elbow to the face (this is easier for tall players—shorter players should focus on a quick stepout).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2¢ On Hucking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-2-on-hucking/</guid>
      <description>When I think about throwing long, it helps me to visualize a spring in action. I try to activate four parts of my body that act as springs: legs, hips, shoulders, elbow, and wrist. As I wind up for the throw, I think about compressing these springs in turn and as I throw, I think about releasing each of the springs. The legs are an important part of the step; I step out as far as I can to still feel completely balanced throughout the throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secrets For Throwing Farther</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-secrets-for-throwing-farther/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/my-secrets-for-throwing-farther/</guid>
      <description>How to throw farther.
A good question. To start I will say this. Some people do not have the physical ability to throw as far as others. Strength, body type, and other factors are the reason behind this. However, there are ways to throw further no matter how far you can throw it now.
TECHNIQUES
The best throwers in the game and their ability to throw the disc further than others is based on a few techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Body Mechanics Early</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/strong-body-mechanics-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-010/strong-body-mechanics-early/</guid>
      <description>Hailing from Paideia I probably started throwing a frisbee earlier than most. In 4th grade I was learning push passes, thumbers, and scoobers from Coach Baccarini in addition to the more conventional flicks, backhands, and hammers. As soon as I picked up a disc I wanted to know how I could throw farther, faster, and better. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until my senior year in high school that I was able to figure out how to throw deep with consistency from both the backhand and forehand side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
