<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jaime Arambula on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jaime-arambula/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jaime Arambula on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/jaime-arambula/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Space For Real Time Results</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</guid>
      <description>At the college level, the dividing line between teams that can generate a break or two, and the teams that consistently go on a run of breaks can be attributed to the concept of team defense.
My experience in trying to introduce this concept to new, or inexperienced, players is to break things down to the absolute basics. Initially, during our first chalktalk regarding the defense I like to introduce the name of the D (something catchy, without lending too much information to opponents who might hear it on the sideline), and the main objectives of the defense (forcing lots of short passes, forcing inside out strikes, forcing long, low percentage throws).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wham!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-007/the-wham-/</guid>
      <description>2001 in Sarasota was crazy. Hurricane Michelle was causing major havoc for most of the Mixed division&amp;rsquo;s offenses. The wind started mild on Thursday and picked up through the week. One of my teammates on Trigger Hippy, Scott &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; Runkel (who played for Boston back when they were Big Brother, and, as far as I know, was the original &amp;ldquo;the Kid&amp;rdquo; of the three that I know), along with Mike &amp;ldquo;the Wizard&amp;rdquo; Faris, came up with a zone to man to zone to man, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
