<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Angles</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/angles/</guid>
      <description>There are a few key tricks that I have found make an effective mark. Some are commonly talked about and pretty well agreed. I do think that not all of these are universally agreed. This is mostly a list of key points, rather than in depth on each one.
The first is mental. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to relax when you get to a mark. It&amp;rsquo;s important to remind yourself that you are responsible for more of the field than any other single defender on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond The Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/beyond-the-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the fundamentals of marking—getting low with the hips, staying balanced, keeping arms wide—here are a few &amp;ldquo;advanced fundamental&amp;rdquo; techniques.
1. Chin up, eyes on the chest. My hand is much more likely to find its way in front of the disc when I&amp;rsquo;m only &amp;ldquo;looking&amp;rdquo; with my peripheral vision. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this works so well. In part, I think it&amp;rsquo;s because good throwers use disc fakes to get you out of position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending The Area Around The Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/defending-the-area-around-the-thrower/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy marking—particularly in the zone of a 1-3-3. Marking is a very important part of the game that often goes unnoticed or is an afterthought in defensive play. Teams usually pay some lip service to marking strategy (forcing flick or middle or straight-up), but that tends to be about it. Unfortunately, common practice is that the marker will rest on the mark. They use the mark as a chance to get their breath and prepare for another defensive run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventative vs. Deceptive</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/preventative-vs-deceptive/</guid>
      <description>The most common mark you see on the frisbee field is what I would define as a preventative mark. The mark has each arm extended out fully, explicitly placed to take away a specific throw. This is a useful mark as it does prevent the intended throws and it is seen at every level of frisbee (see photo 1). However, though it is useful, it has certain disadvantages. It allows the thrower to know which throws you are trying to take away before they even attempt to throw or fake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Marking</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/team-marking/</guid>
      <description>When marking, face to face, one-on-one with your opponent, you are more closed off from the game around you than at any other moment in Ultimate. This leads some markers to try for too much, going for every block. Others miss opportunities to help their teammates by adhering too closely to the force. Effective marking requires a balance between these extremes. One trick to achieving this balance (and knowing when to take a risk on the mark) is glancing over your shoulder at the oncoming cuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidbits</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tidbits/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of marking tidbits I&amp;rsquo;ve heard and dispensed over the years. I find myself repeatedly coming back to four in particular. Two of these pieces of wisdom have come from amazing coaches, one is from a legendary point-block machine, and one is from observations of what makes the biggest difference in my own marking.
From Jennifer &amp;ldquo;JD&amp;rdquo; Donnelly (while coaching Stanford Superfly): Your mark should take into account body mechanics and reaction time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips &amp; Insights</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tips-insights/</guid>
      <description>When the disc is dead, always check behind your back to see where the first threats are and position yourself to take those away most effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s the one chance you have to see what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen behind you before you set up your mark—use it!
I try to think of my arms and legs separately as a &amp;rsquo;two-pronged&amp;rsquo; defense. Think of your arms as being on a separate vertical plane from your legs, so that the thrower has to get through 2 vertical planes of extremities rather than just one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks Of The Trade</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tricks-of-the-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/tricks-of-the-trade/</guid>
      <description>As a player who is in all honesty not the most gifted and speedy athlete in the game, getting defensive turnovers with monster layouts and big skies is not always the best strategy for me. I learned early on however that I can still have a huge effect on the defensive side of the game by simply focusing on putting on a solid mark on the player I&amp;rsquo;m covering (or trying to cover) once they have the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice, No More</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/twice-no-more/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve mastered the basics (like the two-spot mark) and the not-so-basic- but-standard (like denying the dump on stalling 8), it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to learning individual players.
Of course you know all the moves of your nemesis; you play him five times a season and cover him every point you&amp;rsquo;re in. Of course you adjust your game to meet the challenge. Your match-ups become games within games within games where the slightest mistake yields victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-025/two-simple-steps/</guid>
      <description>Marking consists of two simple steps: knowing the threats, and denying the threats. While the specifics will depend on how your team decides to play defense, the ideas below will apply in nearly all situations.
Step 1: Know the threats.
The best way to adjust your mark is to anticipate what the offense wants to do. If you can read the offense, you can take away the throws that would help them the most.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
