<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Whitaker on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/mike-whitaker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mike Whitaker on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/mike-whitaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Pod System</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/the-pod-system/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling is one of the most difficult parts of being a team leader, be it as a coach or a player. As coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have employed several different strategies throughout the years depending on the team. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give young players some insight into one coach&amp;rsquo;s perspective of sub-calling.
My sub-calling strategy begins in the organization of my sub sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminate The Unforced Turnover</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-008/eliminate-the-unforced-turnover/</guid>
      <description>Catching technique and practice are often overlooked components of player development. Catching instructions generally begin and end with a demonstration of the pancake catch and calls to &amp;ldquo;use two hands,&amp;rdquo; with players left to their own devices to improve their catching through repetitions. As a coach of Kali (the University of Colorado Women&amp;rsquo;s team), I have developed a more proactive approach to teaching catching.
The reason for this is that drops are unforced turnovers that are preventable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containing A Big Thrower</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/containing-a-big-thrower/</guid>
      <description>The best strategy for containing good deep throwers depends in part on the type of handler position they are playing. If the thrower is frequently in a dump reset position, the number one priority must be that he does not get the disc moving up field. A good thrower with momentum and a trailing mark is deadly. You will often find a defender guard this player well for the first two or three resets and then the defender will get impatient.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
