<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Little Theory &amp; A Lot Of Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-little-theory-a-lot-of-practice/</guid>
      <description>It can be easy to make excuses for not playing team defense in Mixed Ultimate, especially in man-to-man set-ups. About half the people on the field you would never choose to mark up on/cover prior to the pull, the people you want to set up switches with may not be the closest people to you, and the person in the best position to help you might not be the obvious choice given the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Example: Defending The Dump</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/a-quick-example-defending-the-dump/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had some success teaching team D in the past, and I like to think that young players, especially bright ones, will often surprise you with their ability to learn complex concepts and make them work against very good offensive players and teams.
One example of our team-D philosophy is in how we taught dump D at U of Oregon. This would usually happen at some point during February or March, after the basics of defense and offense but before the real tournament schedule got up to speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication &amp; Vision</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/communication-vision/</guid>
      <description>I think there are two skills that can take a player from a good defender to a great defender and they both have to do with the transition from an individually good defender to a good team defender.
1. Communication. Silent defenders will never be great defenders. This includes &amp;ldquo;up,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;switch&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;last back&amp;rdquo; calls. This is particularly important in zone defense for wings and deeps. To practice this, I sometimes require players to be saying something continuously during a defensive drill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Screw The Team</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/don-t-screw-the-team/</guid>
      <description>Team defense begins with an understanding and analysis of the strengths and weaknesses of your team&amp;rsquo;s defensive talents, followed by the development of defensive philosophies that are executed by specific team-oriented strategy. Too often, &amp;ldquo;team defense&amp;rdquo; is taught in terms of situational defensive sets such as zone, clam, poaching, and whatnot with an over-reliance on individual athleticism to play man-D. While high-flying layout blocks are at times warranted and necessary, it appears the spectacular has come to define a team&amp;rsquo;s defensive prowess along with foot-races and gravity-defying leaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Specific Calls To Your D</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/give-specific-calls-to-your-d/</guid>
      <description>Rich &amp;ldquo;Farmer&amp;rdquo; Hollingsworth once said that when a team is on offense, seven people is too many (a crowd), but when a team is on defense, seven isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Communication is the extra player, and it&amp;rsquo;s the key to successful team defense. For team defense, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there is a more important skill or a more simple one. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to develop and I have always found it to be really difficult to teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limit Handler Play, &amp; The Caterpillar Drill</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/limit-handler-play-the-caterpillar-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/limit-handler-play-the-caterpillar-drill/</guid>
      <description>Team defense starts when you can make solid assumptions about what your teammates will and will not allow. A good team defense limits the offense&amp;rsquo;s options to looks that the D is prepared for, and then pounces when the O predictably does what you set them up for. Basically, you can&amp;rsquo;t play team defense if you are purely reactive to the offense—you have to have a general goal for how you are going to manufacture turnovers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Space For Real Time Results</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/real-time-space-for-real-time-results/</guid>
      <description>At the college level, the dividing line between teams that can generate a break or two, and the teams that consistently go on a run of breaks can be attributed to the concept of team defense.
My experience in trying to introduce this concept to new, or inexperienced, players is to break things down to the absolute basics. Initially, during our first chalktalk regarding the defense I like to introduce the name of the D (something catchy, without lending too much information to opponents who might hear it on the sideline), and the main objectives of the defense (forcing lots of short passes, forcing inside out strikes, forcing long, low percentage throws).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-By-Step Approach At Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-013/step-by-step-approach-at-practice/</guid>
      <description>Understanding that each player is an integral part in the defensive machine precludes all other aspects of defense. Getting everyone on the same page is of utmost importance as 6 players playing together and fulfilling their responsibilities does not equate to a block. So, this is the initial step in teaching team defense.
From here, it is a matter of understanding the defense we are running (zone, man, clam, junk, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
