<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Balance &amp; Explosiveness</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/balance-explosiveness/</guid>
      <description>I still remember being at Worlds in 1999 in Scotland and it was sort of the debut of Fortunat Mueller with Boston. He was a young workhorse at that time and DoG knew how to use him, as he was probably catching half their goals. I remember watching a pool play game of theirs and a more experienced player pointing out his footwork, how he was always on balance. While we had begun some very basic footwork drills, it was the first time I remember noticing someone&amp;rsquo;s footwork in a game situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/cutting-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>The player that has excellent footwork in my mind has a football and track background. He has great body positioning while cutting that I think leads to his strong footwork. His cuts are strong as a result of pushing his weight into the ground and exploding after getting low and chopping his feet. This helps his play because I believe he is able to get open on players that are bigger and stronger and faster than him by using good technical footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get On The Ladder!</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/get-on-the-ladder-/</guid>
      <description>A big part of footwork is quickness, and the best tool I know of to improve quickness is a speed ladder. I would highly recommend getting one—the longer the better. The various drills and exercises are pretty easy to find and learn, and they&amp;rsquo;re pretty fun to do.
You can just Google &amp;ldquo;speed ladder drills&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ll get plenty of sites that do a far better job of explaining the drills than I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</guid>
      <description>Improving footwork is just one of many ways to improve quickness and efficiency on offense and defense. Other ways to improve quickness and efficiency include weight training, plyos to train muscles often overlooked/underused, learning to lower your center of gravity, core strengthening, and balance. As a team, Truck Stop has chosen to focuses on some of these other factors to improve quickness and efficiency.
However, there are two instances where I think a focus on footwork, more so than the other factors, can vastly improve performance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From Other Sports</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/notes-from-other-sports/</guid>
      <description>Ring of Fire&amp;rsquo;s Dave Snoke has tremendous footwork. Of course, Dave was a star soccer player for the NC State Wolfpack before switching over to Ultimate so it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise this skill is to his advantage. On offense, he constantly seems to accomplish more with less, taking the least amount of steps to get a big gain or get the O out of a tight situation, time and again. On the D side of things it&amp;rsquo;s not a matter of beating the receiver to the spot, but he excels at the cat and mouse game prior to the cut due to the economy of his footwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay On Your Toes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/stay-on-your-toes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/stay-on-your-toes/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of simple rules that can be followed that have far reaching implications for improving your individual game. Staying on your toes, or more appropriately, keeping your weight on the balls of your feet, is one of the best, and can be the foundation for all improvement in footwork that increase your basic skills set. My mentor in the game, Steve Joye, one of the best players of the 80&amp;rsquo;s and early 90&amp;rsquo;s was a big (almost manic) proponent on this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Players of Note</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/two-players-of-note/</guid>
      <description>Two players that come to mind when I think of good footwork are Idris Nolan offensively and Hensley Sejour defensively. Idris is quite a good basketball player, which requires a significant amount of body control as well as footwork. Hensley, coming from a football background as a defensive back (I believe) has worked on his footwork extensively.
Whether offensively or defensively, Idris and Hensley have the same traits in common:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Coach Arambula Is Preaching</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/what-coach-arambula-is-preaching/</guid>
      <description>Is footwork important? Only if winning games is important. Ultimate, maybe more than any sport, has layers of pretty arm and upper-body movement that disguise a game primarily decided by feet. Basketball is right up there.
As a handler, I get lots of different body-types defending me during big games. I&amp;rsquo;m just as likely to look across the line and see Jit (Revolver&amp;rsquo;s tiny handler-defender extraordinaire) as I am to see some massive athlete that I have no hope of running with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
