<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Unpredictable</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/be-unpredictable/</guid>
      <description>1. Face the mark. This classic piece of throwing technology dates back to the dawn of modern Ultimate when Windy City and NYNY ruled. The uneducated thrower looks upfield at the stack and they position their body to reflect this. When they want to throw a dump they have to turn 270 degrees, which is incredibly slow. (Or turn their back to the field, which is incredibly dumb.) By facing the mark, you shorten the turn to 180 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut &amp; Clear</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/cut-clear/</guid>
      <description>When we&amp;rsquo;re facing a &amp;ldquo;rotated&amp;rdquo; mark paired with good up-line dump defense, we have to do a few things to win.
First, we have to cut and clear decisively. The defensive tactic succeeds if it forces the handlers to &amp;ldquo;dance,&amp;rdquo; clogging the reset lane and creating uncertainty for the thrower. Even if the handlers have nowhere to run but towards the defense, they must run. Often times, the defense isn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as it looks and the handler can swim past the up-line defender, or the thrower can shimmy to open up the around-break throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move As Early As Possible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/move-as-early-as-possible/</guid>
      <description>In framing this discussion, I think it is important to note that some teams have a static approach to shifting the mark, while others are more dynamic. In the static case, the mark starts off taking away more of the reset look only on the sideline, while giving up more of an angle downfield. In the dynamic case, the marker starts off with a conventional angle, but rotates with the marker when they turn to hit the dump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Without The Frisbee</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/moving-without-the-frisbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/moving-without-the-frisbee/</guid>
      <description>Rotating the mark is a very effective strategy in forcing teams into difficult situations. This strategy works especially well in windy conditions or against teams that primarily run a vertical stack. I am sure that other authors will talk about the mechanics of the thrower in this situation but the one thing that I want to emphasize in this situation is the role of the cutter (normally a handler) who is in the dump position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotate 90°</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/rotate-90-/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark can effectively make the backfield dump a very difficult throw. Here are a few ways to prevent this defense from making your life as a thrower difficult.
First of all, the D is most effective on a high stall count when you are running out of time and options (and many teams will only shift their marks to take away the dump once the stall count gets high).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Advantage Of The Given Space</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/take-advantage-of-the-given-space/</guid>
      <description>Rotating the mark can be a very effective strategy against teams that effectively use the reset to work the disc upfield when the initial cut isn&amp;rsquo;t open. This defense works best when it has the element of surprise behind it. However, like many defenses, if offenses recognize that this strategy is being used they can develop a plan to counter it.
The easiest thing to think about is what the defense gives up when they implement this strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Looks</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/three-looks/</guid>
      <description>Nothing earth-shattering here, but first and most important: the easiest way to get out of this situation is to avoid it. A good offense recognizes what the D is playing early (see the zone, see the clam, see everything). An anti- reset mark can be set up by the defense several throws ahead. A person sits in the lane, leaving the handler on the sideline open. It&amp;rsquo;s an obvious throw. The first way to avoid this is to have that receiver (the person who would be trapped) move towards the thrower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition From The Grabled Mess</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-026/transition-from-the-grabled-mess/</guid>
      <description>The anti-reset mark is very effective at putting throwers in an uncomfortable position. You&amp;rsquo;ve been working it up the line effectively, dumping when needed, but generally marching up the field. Now, the defense has shifted, and you either have to make a tough break backwards or hope that your resets can break free up the line. The sideline, as the 8th defender, limits your options. Typically in these situations there is a flood of players close to you, as cutters come in for the bail or defenders sag a bit into the lane.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
