<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Morgan on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ryan-morgan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ryan Morgan on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ryan-morgan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yeah Iverson, We&#39;ve Talkin&#39; About Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/yeah-iverson-we-ve-talkin-about-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have a rather painful childhood memory from back in middle school. I was playing basketball and went to set a low screen for another player. In a moment of miscommunication both my defender and the player who I set a pick on rushed to guard my teammate. I was left open for just a few seconds, but before I realized it, the basketball hit me in the face. The point guard recognized that I was about to be open and passed the ball early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Rules</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/our-rules/</guid>
      <description>No one gets four strikes in baseball simply because they think its wrong that the rules allow only three. You don&amp;rsquo;t pick and choose which rules to follow. You play by the rules of the game. Whether or not you agree with it, the Spirit of the Game concept is a fixture in the official rules of Ultimate so we, as players, have an obligation to adhere to it. But in the middle of a game, especially one with much at stake, what does it mean to adhere to a concept that is so vaguely defined?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wings &amp; Poppers</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/wings-poppers/</guid>
      <description>My college team always seemed to be able to only field 5 good zone offense players. The last two players on the line were usually assigned to play the wing position—that is, the popper responsible for making cuts to the sideline when the handlers swung the disc around. As a result, I never really appreciated how important the wing position is to an effective zone offense until I started playing club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Your Team, Not Your Teammates</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-009/for-your-team-not-your-teammates/</guid>
      <description>Sub-calling, especially for one who one who plays at the same time, is one of the most difficult things to do. Personally, I hate doing it because I feel like it distracts me from my ability to remain focused while playing. But like everyone, I always have my own feelings about who should be playing at a particular time. Fortunately, as captain of my team, my opinion about who plays carries a bit of weight with the sub-caller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Footwork</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-006/improving-footwork/</guid>
      <description>Improving footwork is just one of many ways to improve quickness and efficiency on offense and defense. Other ways to improve quickness and efficiency include weight training, plyos to train muscles often overlooked/underused, learning to lower your center of gravity, core strengthening, and balance. As a team, Truck Stop has chosen to focuses on some of these other factors to improve quickness and efficiency.
However, there are two instances where I think a focus on footwork, more so than the other factors, can vastly improve performance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic &amp; Potential Energy</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-005/kinetic-potential-energy/</guid>
      <description>I believe that good chemistry between handlers can affect the game more than at any other position. Having two or three experienced handlers that really know each other is such an advantage because they likely have withstood defensive pressure like this before and they likely have talked about it and figured out, between them, how to deal with it. Because they can predict what the other is going to do, they don&amp;rsquo;t panic when the stall count gets higher and they can reset the disc accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Position Relative To Your Opponent</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-004/get-position-relative-to-your-opponent/</guid>
      <description>Being a receiver, this scenario is one of my favorite moments in ultimate. The adrenaline kicks in and it dawns on you that it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to make the play you have been training all season. My training regimen is focused on maximizing acceleration and jumping ability, both of which are essential to getting the block in this scenario. But before putting those skills to use, you have to look up quickly and find the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Any Adjustment...Just Make It Now</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-003/make-any-adjustment-just-make-it-now/</guid>
      <description>This is a very interesting scenario because there are so many adjustments that could be made to respond to this player. You could assign a speedy defender to outrun him on the deep cuts, you could assign a tall defender to pull down floaty passes, you could assign a physical defender to disrupt the flow of his cuts, you could keep playing the same defense on him but put a straight-up mark on everyone else, you could go zone, you could play last back, or you could even throw your scouting report out the window and let him hang around the disc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus On What You Can Control</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-002/focus-on-what-you-can-control/</guid>
      <description>Trying out for a club team is like interviewing for any job. There are some things that are in your control and some things that aren’t. It’s important to focus on the things you can control and understand that the other things aren’t worth worrying about. Even if you are a great thrower, if the team already has great throwers then the 6’9&amp;quot; guy that can’t throw may get selected over you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Type of Offense Fits Your Team?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-001/which-type-of-offense-fits-your-team-/</guid>
      <description>There are numerous factors to consider when deciding whether to run a horizontal stack (HO) or vertical stack (Vert) offense such as: recent success rate with a particular offense against your opponent, probable individual match-ups with your opponent, and how critical the particular point is. In this scenario we are asked to discuss how another factor, wind, affects that decision. Before that discussion, however, it is necessary to look generally at the relative costs and benefits of the Vert versus the HO offense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
