<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Constant Stream Of Specific Information</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-constant-stream-of-specific-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-constant-stream-of-specific-information/</guid>
      <description>When I played in college especially, my team made a concerted effort to maintain an active sideline and to communicate efficiently from the sideline rather than simply being loud. That carried over in Club, where I played with many of those same players.
When I am on the sideline helping teammates on the field, I like to select one player to communicate with and focus on two things: 1) conveying information and 2) being specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Strong Sideline Voice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/a-strong-sideline-voice/</guid>
      <description>Most offenders will tell you that yelling instructions to them on the sideline when they&amp;rsquo;re on offense is annoying, if not worse. When you&amp;rsquo;re on offense, sideline chatter is best saved for positive encouragement and celebrating a goal scored.
However, on D, the sideline is an incredibly powerful tool, able to create momentum on your side, stop momentum for the other team, and create blocks that otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Now, a good sideline voice has a few characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assisting The Visually Impaired</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/assisting-the-visually-impaired/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/assisting-the-visually-impaired/</guid>
      <description>The impact of the sideline is most important when the team is on defense. In ultimate, as in most possession style games, the offense has a distinct advantage. The offense is in control of where the future will take place on the field and therefore offensive players are ABLE to be a step ahead of the defense at all times. It is the job of the defenders to constantly anticipate where the thrower would like to throw and when those spaces will be available, while at the same time making decisions to force blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Takes Practice</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/it-takes-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/it-takes-practice/</guid>
      <description>Like any team, Death or Glory had its own mythology. As a green twenty-year old, very few tales of the past loomed as large for me as Paul Greff’s block against the Condors in 1998. It seemed told and told again: as the deep in the zone at a critical point, Paul hears someone on the sideline telling him to drop and he does, without looking, just in time to get a game saving block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep It Calm</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/keep-it-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/keep-it-calm/</guid>
      <description>Assuming there are other essays that discuss the importance of having one sideline voice using simple language, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a slightly contrarian approach to the topic: there&amp;rsquo;s not much you can really accomplish from the sideline during a game. Put more accurately, the best you can hope for from your sideline is to help remind the players on the field of what they already know. Defensive blocks are created by players executing the strategy they decided on before the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loud &#43; Positive = Good</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/loud-positive-good/</guid>
      <description>I think that sideline contributions are underrated in their worth by most teams and particularly by most great players. People who are great at team sports are not necessarily motivated to play well for themselves – especially in our sport, they are motivated to play well by their love of team, teammates and something bigger than themselves.
In this way, I will stand by something I accidentally said in a huddle last year: &amp;ldquo;Loud information is good information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Useful</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/make-it-useful/</guid>
      <description>Basic principles of sideline talk are fairly simple: make it targeted (say the player’s name first), make it specific (not just &amp;ldquo;c’mon, go, go&amp;rdquo;), and give information (not instruction). You may not know what the player already knows and is planning, so this lets him decide what to do and how to handle the info. (Sometimes, if the level of trust is high, off-field players can give instructions rather than information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide New Information and Reinforcement</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/provide-new-information-and-reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>Sideline talk should make the players on the field more effective in two ways: it should help them make different decisions than they might make otherwise, and it should help them (re)act more quickly to game situations. In other words, the primary functions of sideline talk are to provide new information, and to provide reinforcement that cuts down processing time.
&amp;lsquo;Provide new information&amp;rsquo;: tell the player on the field anything they can&amp;rsquo;t see that might- or should- change the way they play for the next few seconds or passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing The Work</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/sharing-the-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/sharing-the-work/</guid>
      <description>Standing on the sidelines is, for many players, the hardest or most frustrating part of being on a team. Ultimate is special in the larger world of sports in that the sideline is a great place to help your team out. Where in other sports the sideline is not allowed to actively participate by communicating with their fellow players on the field, in Ultimate the sideline can work as an eighth player, one with position and focus dedicated to improving the outcome of strategies and plays being made my fielded players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing A Team Way Of Communicating</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/standardizing-a-team-way-of-communicating/</guid>
      <description>Different teams have a very different approach to the role of individuals when they’re on the sideline. Some teams like to give the players on the sideline a chance to rest and have them sit in the shade to recover for their next time in the game. Others, especially in the college ranks, can have countless players making tons of useless noise from the sidelines. I think the best teams find a way to keep players involved in the success of the team when they are not one of the seven guys on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangible vs. Intangible</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/tangible-vs-intangible/</guid>
      <description>As cliché as it may be, it is true that the sideline can equate to the eighth man (woman) for a team. However, I would say the sideline can mean much more than just an eighth man. The sideline can be a symbolic representation of the morale and demeanor of the game.
Most speak of the sideline and the tangible benefits of using your voices to motivate and push your teammates in the heat of battle on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zone</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/the-zone/</guid>
      <description>In the moment of competition, I like my brain to be functioning on approximately the level of a caveman chasing a woolly mammoth. The biggest motivation to help from the sideline is that the louder I yell, the more primordial I feel, and the better I play. It’s the best way for me to get in and stay in &amp;ldquo;the zone.&amp;rdquo;
Here is a great description of the zone, which I recently read in a novel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Things Durings A Point</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-030/two-things-durings-a-point/</guid>
      <description>When you find yourself on the sideline, there are two obvious things to do during a point. You should serve as an extra brain and pair of eyes to help them execute the team’s strategy, and you need to encourage them to keep putting in effort. I’ll skip over these two aspects of sideline help (which I hope others will cover in more detail), and focus on one aspect which takes place after a point is over, and one aspect which is believed to be helpful, but is frequently not, and should be discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
