<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ted Munter on The Huddle</title>
    <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ted-munter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ted Munter on The Huddle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/author/ted-munter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Play A Different Position</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-029/play-a-different-position/</guid>
      <description>I would argue that field vision, like speed or height, is pretty hard to teach and learn. The best athletes don&amp;rsquo;t see what&amp;rsquo;s happening so much as take a picture of the field and respond. A few brains can do that kind of thing, but most can&amp;rsquo;t. Bill Rodriguez would counsel deeps in a zone to move up if they saw seven opposing players in front of them. Super, if, like Bill, you can see them all at once and count them at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codifying Spirit</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-024/codifying-spirit/</guid>
      <description>This topic is not useless, but I find that my thoughts on it are fairly disconnected.
A phrase that reminds us to respect each other and the game makes sense even if it is not as effective as some would like preventing players from cheating or acting like jerks. We are really just codifying the idea that Ultimate players should practice good sportsmanship, That has value, I hope.
A lot of people discover Ultimate after some bad experience with another sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Play(er)s</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-022/great-play-er-s/</guid>
      <description>What makes a great play is if it works on the field with the players you have. No matter the nomenclature, strategic genius, or underlying theory: what happens on paper matters little.
In general, I would say most team&amp;rsquo;s playbooks (and plays) are too complicated. Go simple. And a few simple rules are:
1. Does the play work? (Not, &amp;ldquo;it would have worked if&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;)
2. What is option B if the first pass doesn&amp;rsquo;t go as designed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute Your Changes</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-020/execute-your-changes/</guid>
      <description>If you are behind because the team has something you can&amp;rsquo;t handle (a few players or a defense) you are not behind, you are getting beaten. Change it up. Play a different D, run the counter play, even if you have to invent it. Maybe the risk means you go down 13-7 and later people whisper about how you got blown out. But if you can&amp;rsquo;t get the score to 11-9 or 12-10 so what?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Glory</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-019/team-glory/</guid>
      <description>Ah the layout block, the play that got you started, the one you still dream about, the slam dunk of our game. Or maybe the three-pointer.
On a bad throw everyone can get what looks like a good block. That&amp;rsquo;s why you play summer league. But when teams are executing well, coming up with a piece is tough. Don&amp;rsquo;t over-commit to laying out or you will end up getting burned on jukes and lying on the ground as the person you are supposed to cover has a free throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Points</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-018/three-points/</guid>
      <description>Three points about zone offense that are usually true:
Your poppers have to identify the zone they are playing against and adjust their positioning/movement accordingly. Handlers must do the same and adjust their throws.
Keep moving. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for deeps and wings to start standing and watching. Even if your zone offense calls for you as the deep O threat to go to the back of the endzone, move around there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Should Guard Their Best Player?</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-017/who-should-guard-their-best-player-/</guid>
      <description>Let me answer this question with a question. When was the last time your best cutter defender spent a scrimmage covering your best handler? How about the other way around? Sure, your best on the ball defender talks all the time about hounding the region&amp;rsquo;s best handler, and your best athlete wants to stop the receiver all others fear, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a game hoping (or just hoping) your top players match up well against their top players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraphrasing Parinella &amp; Zaslow</title>
      <link>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/paraphrasing-parinella-zaslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-huddle.indiaultimate.org/issue-016/paraphrasing-parinella-zaslow/</guid>
      <description>Moving the disc does one of three things:
Gains ground (i.e. attacks) Moves you to a better place from which to attack Maintains possession Because there is less room, the sideline can often be a harder place from which to do 2 and 3. But if you can make space for your teammates, it can also be an ideal place from which to attack.
As always, personnel and approach determines much of what you do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
